<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Development on Haiku Project</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/development/</link><description>Recent content in Development on Haiku Project</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>2001-2021 Haiku Inc.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2009 06:38:22 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.haiku-os.org/development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Application Patterns</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/development/apps-patterns/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2018 22:37:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/development/apps-patterns/</guid><description>There are several common patterns or approaches that you will use when developing Haiku native applications. These are listed below:
These tutorials were created by DarkWyrm unless otherwise stated.
Using the Layout API [PDF] - by waddlesplash Using attributes in your application [PDF] Using attributes in Queries[PDF] Monitoring the File System with the StorageKit [PDF] Registering a new file type [PDF] Using fonts [PDF] Creating a new UI Control [PDF] Using application scripting [PDF] Adding scripting to your applications [PDF] Enabling Drag &amp;amp; Drop [PDF] Exposing re-usable parts of your application with Replicants [PDF] Tutorial Project: Create a text editor [PDF]</description></item><item><title>Prepare for Publishing</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/development/apps-prepare/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2018 22:31:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/development/apps-prepare/</guid><description>The are many tasks you should look in to before publishing your new or latest application.
Translating your application using catkeys files Create an icon for your application</description></item><item><title>To Create or Contribute?</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/development/apps-tocreate/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2018 22:21:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/development/apps-tocreate/</guid><description>When you spot a need for an application it is tempting to create a new one from scratch. The HaikuArchives contains many projects that were started as an idea, and then fell out of use.
To minimise code waste and maximise re-use, you should consider finding a project that aligns with your goals, and adding your own new feature enhancements to it, rather than default to create Yet Another Application.</description></item><item><title>Setting up a Development Environment</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/development/contribute-dev-env/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2018 22:06:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/development/contribute-dev-env/</guid><description>The first thing you'll need to do before writing code in Haiku is to set up a development environment. How you do this will depend on whether you are developing for Haiku within Haiku itself, or from another operating system.
In future we hope to provide step by step guides for each platform. For now though, whichever of the below routes you take, see the summary: Building pre-requisities page for details.</description></item><item><title>Programming With Haiku</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/development/programming_with_haiku/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2015 13:21:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/development/programming_with_haiku/</guid><description>Lessons by DarkWyrm Since I started publishing my Learning to Program with Haiku lesson series back in January, I have, on many occasions, seen comments asking for lessons aimed at current codemonkeys who want to break into development for Haiku. Here begins a new series of programming lessons aimed at people who already have a basic grasp on C++: Programming with Haiku. While I have a basic outline for the series, it's very general and I'm not exactly sure how long the series will run.</description></item><item><title>Learning to Program with Haiku</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/development/learning_to_program_with_haiku/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2010 00:59:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/development/learning_to_program_with_haiku/</guid><description>Lessons by DarkWyrm ISBN: 978-0-557-53969-7 (lulu.com) In January of 2010, I started publishing lessons on learning to program for Haiku, aimed at people who want to be able to write simple programs to get stuff done, but never had anyone around teach them. Years ago, I started teaching myself and am an active developer. It's my turn to give back. All of these lessons are distributed under a Creative Commons license which allows free distribution for noncommercial purposes.</description></item><item><title>Icon Guidelines</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/development/icon-guidelines/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2009 07:02:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/development/icon-guidelines/</guid><description>This document explains the artistic subtleties of Haiku icons. If it leaves something unclear to you, that is, what rules to follow when designing an icon for the Haiku operating system, please bring the issue to our attention. Existing icons should give you a pretty good idea what directions to follow. This document is meant to define the distinctive look in further detail and to be a useful resource in case of doubt.</description></item><item><title>Coding Guidelines</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/development/coding-guidelines/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2009 06:48:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/development/coding-guidelines/</guid><description>div.content { tab-size: 4; -moz-tab-size: 4; } The document below outlines our code style guidelines. If you have suggestions for things that should be clarified better, etc. please let us know. Please don&amp;rsquo;t send us suggestions of the kind &amp;ldquo;I like this indenting style better, could we switch?&amp;quot;.
The information in the document below is extremely important. If you will be contributing code or patches to Haiku, you will need to strictly follow the code style guidelines.</description></item><item><title>Getting Started</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/development/getting-started/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2009 06:42:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/development/getting-started/</guid><description>Developers are the driving force behind Haiku, and without them, we would not be where we are today. It’s hard to put into words the pleasure of seeing something you’ve built help many other people. Newcomers will need to know or be willing to learn C++, as well as the BeOS/Haiku API.
Getting Involved The best way to get into developing on the Haiku project is to get to know the environment and make yourself familiar with the system.</description></item><item><title>Development FAQ</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/development/faq/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2009 06:40:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/development/faq/</guid><description>I am a programmer and would like to help. Where can I get started? Do you have any easy introductory tasks for me? Do you have coding guidelines? How do I create and submit patches? What development tools do you use? Do you have a mailing list for developers? Do you have an IRC channel? How much space is needed to build Haiku? Why can't I create a ticket in Trac?</description></item></channel></rss>