<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>gsoc2021 on Haiku Project</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/tags/gsoc2021/</link><description>Recent content in gsoc2021 on Haiku Project</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>2001-2021 Haiku Inc.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 17:55:41 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.haiku-os.org/tags/gsoc2021/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>GSoC 2021 Progress Update 3: Coding style checker bot for Gerrit</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/blog/ritz/2021-07-21_gsoc_2021_progress_update_3_coding_style_checker_bot_for_gerrit/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 17:55:41 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/blog/ritz/2021-07-21_gsoc_2021_progress_update_3_coding_style_checker_bot_for_gerrit/</guid><description>Tl;dr I have completed the bot with basic functionality for my local gerrit instance
Link to Introductory blog
Link to Progress 1
Link to Progress 2
As I have said before I divided my project in the following parts
For every event (change, patch etc.), trigger the Concourse CI pipeline. Implement pipeline in concourse CI for fetching the Git repo and running the haiku-format tool on the relevant files and creating appropriate reports out of the tool.</description></item><item><title>GSoC 2021 Progress Update 2: Modernizing Cardie (Caya)</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/blog/jadedctrl/2021-07-09_gsoc_2021_progress_update_2_modernizing_cardie_caya/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 11:58:06 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/blog/jadedctrl/2021-07-09_gsoc_2021_progress_update_2_modernizing_cardie_caya/</guid><description>Looks like it&amp;rsquo;s time for me to clutter the blog again!
To start: Since the last update, Caya has been hard-forked and renamed to &amp;ldquo;Cardie&amp;rdquo; (short for &amp;ldquo;cardinal&amp;rdquo;), which at least fits the &amp;ldquo;bird theme&amp;rdquo; of libpurple clients.
… And the name&amp;rsquo;s fitting, since it&amp;rsquo;s now a fairly functional libpurple client. :-)
libpurple support There are a few features not implemented yet, which keeps it behind the XMPP add-on in terms of functionality, but the core is there: Configuring and managing accounts for any protocol, joining/creating/leaving rooms, chatting, sending/receiving your own status, room invitations, managing roster, purple-side chat commands, etc.</description></item><item><title>GSoC 2021 Progress Update 2: Coding style checker bot for Gerrit</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/blog/ritz/2021-06-27_gsoc_2021_progress_update_2_coding_style_checker_bot_for_gerrit/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Jun 2021 14:50:01 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/blog/ritz/2021-06-27_gsoc_2021_progress_update_2_coding_style_checker_bot_for_gerrit/</guid><description>Link to Introductory blog
Link to Progress 1
On my quest to finding a way to trigger my jobs anytime a commit happens in gerrit I was looking into this repo and trying to make it work. I tried using it as a resource but it turns out either it&amp;rsquo;s not public anymore or it was deleted. Then I went through the list of forks in that repo and found this.</description></item><item><title>GSoC 2021 Progress Update 1: Modernizing Caya</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/blog/jadedctrl/2021-06-07_gsoc_2021_progress_update_1_modernizing_caya/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 09:19:49 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/blog/jadedctrl/2021-06-07_gsoc_2021_progress_update_1_modernizing_caya/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s the end of the first GSoC period, so it&amp;rsquo;s about time I clutter the blog again!
A good few changes have been made to Caya― most obviously support for multi-user rooms and some UI changes. Multi-protocol add-ons are now supported, the program is oriented around &amp;ldquo;Conversations&amp;rdquo; rather than &amp;ldquo;Contacts,&amp;rdquo; basic moderation (kicking, banning, muting) works, etc.
The protocol API&amp;lsquo;s expanded because of these general changes, and I don&amp;rsquo;t think it could be called &amp;ldquo;stable&amp;rdquo; for another couple weeks at least― I still need to document it, and some of the new additions might still be consolidated into others.</description></item><item><title>GSoC 2021 Progress Update 1: Coding style checker bot for Gerrit</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/blog/ritz/2021-06-05_gsoc_2021_project_update_coding_style_checker_bot_for_gerrit/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2021 19:46:42 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/blog/ritz/2021-06-05_gsoc_2021_project_update_coding_style_checker_bot_for_gerrit/</guid><description>Hey everyone! I am Hrithik (ritz), You can find about my project in my introductory blog. Here&amp;rsquo;s what I have done so far.
I started by reading Concourse CI documentation in order to get myself familiarise with ci pipeline and various schema involved in it. I also looked at other resources provided by my mentors i.e. Suhel Mehta @suhel_mehta and Alexander von Gluck @kallisti5 . Below are some links if anyone wants to check out.</description></item><item><title>GSoC 2021: Coding style checker bot for Gerrit</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/blog/ritz/2021-05-22_gsoc_2021_coding_style_checker_bot_for_gerrit/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 May 2021 20:31:22 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/blog/ritz/2021-05-22_gsoc_2021_coding_style_checker_bot_for_gerrit/</guid><description>Introduction Hey everyone! I am Hrithik Kumar, a sophomore at National Institute of Technology Agartala, India majoring in Computer Science and Engineering (CSE). I am happy to say that I will be working on creating a Coding style checker bot for Gerrit as part of the GSoC 2021 project. My mentors are Alexander von Gluck and Suhel Mehta.
IRC nick: ritz Matrix: ritz (@ritzkr:matrix.org) Project Haiku has its own coding guidelines which describe how the code should be formatted.</description></item><item><title>GSoC 2021 Project: Modernizing Caya</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/blog/jadedctrl/2021-05-18_gsoc_2021_project_modernizing_caya/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 09:46:10 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/blog/jadedctrl/2021-05-18_gsoc_2021_project_modernizing_caya/</guid><description>Introduction Hi! I&amp;rsquo;m Jaidyn Levesque (jadedctrl on IRC and elsewhere), a 2nd year Computer Science student. I&amp;rsquo;ve been using *nixes for several years now, and just moved over to Haiku as my main OS a little over a year ago. I&amp;rsquo;m lucky enough to be a mentee this summer, and I&amp;rsquo;m excited to get started!
Project My GSoC project is to modernize Caya, a multi-protocol chat program. &amp;ldquo;Modernize&amp;rdquo; here means a couple different things: General updates, multi-user chats, and libpurple support.</description></item><item><title>Haiku to mentor 4 students in Google Summer of Code 2021</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2021-05-17_haiku_mentors_4_students_in_gsoc/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 May 2021 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2021-05-17_haiku_mentors_4_students_in_gsoc/</guid><description>The list of accepted students for Google Summer of Code 2021 has just been announced. Over the summer, four students will work on improving Haiku and related applications, with help from our mentor team. Google gives the students a stipend, which allows them to work full-time on the project without the need to find another job.
The goal of the program is to introduce students to the way open source projects work, and encourage them to become long term contributors.</description></item></channel></rss>