<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>News on Haiku Project</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/</link><description>Recent content in News on Haiku Project</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>2001-2021 Haiku Inc.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2021 12:59:08 +1000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.haiku-os.org/news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Media Release: The Haiku Project Celebrates the Release of Beta 3</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2021-07-26_media_release_the_haiku_project_celebrates_the_release_of_beta_3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2021 12:59:08 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2021-07-26_media_release_the_haiku_project_celebrates_the_release_of_beta_3/</guid><description>FOR IMMEDIATE RELEASE
July 25, 2021
THE HAIKU PROJECT CELEBRATES THE RELEASE OF BETA 3 Poetry is in motion. The Haiku Project, its developers and team members announced the Haiku operating system released its third beta release, version R1/Beta3, July 25th, 2021. Version R1B3 continues the trend of more frequent releases to provide users and developers with an up to date and stable platform to work on.
This release combines the best of Haiku’s history as a spiritual successor of BeOS and the hard work of a passionate community.</description></item><item><title>Haiku R1/Beta3 Timeline Update</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2021-07-13_haiku_r1beta3_timeline_update/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 10:14:26 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2021-07-13_haiku_r1beta3_timeline_update/</guid><description>The Haiku Project&amp;rsquo;s release coordinator for the R1/Beta3 release, kallisti5, has made the decision to bump back the release of R1/Beta3 by one week.
The updated timeline is here.
The Beta3 release introduces an important update to Haiku WebKit, which subsequently produces some rendering regressions.
While several of the bugs have already been fixed in Haiku WebKit this week, one final bug remains, which involves an issue with disappearing text.</description></item><item><title>Haiku, Inc. sponsoring hardware purchases for RISC-V port</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2021-07-01_haiku_inc_sponsoring_hardware_purchases_for_risc_v_port/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 08:50:00 +0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2021-07-01_haiku_inc_sponsoring_hardware_purchases_for_risc_v_port/</guid><description>RISC-V is an interesting, relatively new and open source hardware platform. The inventors of RISC-V created a company called HiFive and that company recently released a desktop-class System on a Chip (SoC) board called HiFive Unmatched. Long before this release Haiku developer Alexander von Gluck (kallisti5) had pre-ordered this board and had begun work on the Haiku port to RISC-V, making some progress on the boot loader, u-boot support and memory mapping.</description></item><item><title>Important Change Required for Haiku Nightly and R1/Beta2 Users</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2021-06-22_important_change_required_for_haiku_nightly_and_r1beta2_users/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2021 09:55:21 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2021-06-22_important_change_required_for_haiku_nightly_and_r1beta2_users/</guid><description>HaikuPorts functionality restored Due to the important change to repository identifiers announced earlier, the HaikuPorts repository was presenting users with an error reading unarchiving the repo. This issue has now been fixed and users may need to re-add the HaikuPorts repository again. Nightly and Beta2 users will need to “re-add” their release repositories to update to newer versions of Haiku and beyond. This change is part of a long-term improvement of our Haiku/HaikuPorts repository identifiers.</description></item><item><title>Haiku R1/Beta3 Timeline Approved</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2021-06-14_haiku_r1beta3_timeline_approved/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2021 16:45:15 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2021-06-14_haiku_r1beta3_timeline_approved/</guid><description>The release timeline for Haiku R1/Beta 3 has been approved after a 7 day RFC (Request for Comment) period on the mailing list.
Access the release timeline on the Trac wiki. Note that minor changes to the dates may occur. If all goes to plan, Beta 3 will be released sometime after the 24th of July. Note that the release will only happen when everything is ready, so there are no final dates and the timeline may change to account for delays.</description></item><item><title>Haiku's IRC channels are moving to OFTC!</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2021-05-19_haiku_is_moving_to_oftc/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 May 2021 07:12:00 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2021-05-19_haiku_is_moving_to_oftc/</guid><description>After being present for more than 20 years on the Freenode network, we are moving our IRC channels to the OFTC IRC network!
To those not familiar what&amp;rsquo;s happening, Freenode recently went through a major internal reorganization, which resulted in the overwhelming majority of well-established staff members either being forcefully removed or resigning from their roles as administrators of the network.
The OFTC (Open and Free Technology Community) has been around since 2001 and is associated with the 501(c)(3)-registered non-profit organization &amp;ldquo;Software in the Public Interest, Inc.</description></item><item><title>Haiku to mentor 4 students in Google Summer of Code 2021</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2021-05-17_haiku_mentors_4_students_in_gsoc/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 May 2021 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2021-05-17_haiku_mentors_4_students_in_gsoc/</guid><description>The list of accepted students for Google Summer of Code 2021 has just been announced. Over the summer, four students will work on improving Haiku and related applications, with help from our mentor team. Google gives the students a stipend, which allows them to work full-time on the project without the need to find another job.
The goal of the program is to introduce students to the way open source projects work, and encourage them to become long term contributors.</description></item><item><title>System Sounds Contest Wrap-up</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2020-12-07-contest-results/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2020 12:00:00 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2020-12-07-contest-results/</guid><description>Contest for Haiku System Sounds is finally over; and ladies and gentlemen, we have a winner!
Before going into details, lots of thanks to all participants and voters are in order. Thanks to you, Haiku now has a cohesive high-quality sound set, that will hopefully make using Haiku even more pleasant and accessible.
Without further ado, the winner is Garrett Kabler, with the sound theme &amp;ldquo;grubs-sparkly-tones&amp;rdquo; (previously named as &amp;ldquo;burgs-sparkly-tones&amp;rdquo;, name changed by the author due to a possible identity mixup)!</description></item><item><title>Call for Wallpapers</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2020-10-04-wallpaper-contest/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2020 13:00:00 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2020-10-04-wallpaper-contest/</guid><description>One of the most common feedback that we receive is that Haiku needs some nice colourful wallpapers shipping with its releases. We definitely want to improve the current situation. And we need your help.
Haiku currently ships with only one (1) wallpaper, and it&amp;rsquo;s not a complete wallpaper per se, it&amp;rsquo;s just the Haiku logo positioned at fixed coordinates on the screen. To be fair, there is a reason we only use the Haiku logo as the default wallpaper; we want Haiku to be usable on systems that have memory as low as 256 MB, therefore each byte that we can spare counts.</description></item><item><title>Contest for System Sounds</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2020-09-11-system-sound-contest/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2020 13:00:00 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2020-09-11-system-sound-contest/</guid><description>UPDATE (2020/12/08): The contest has concluded. See this blog post for the results.
It wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be wrong to say that, Haiku is a unique operating system. It takes its roots from BeOS, the OS everyone envied back in the day. Haiku continues to follow its footsteps, trying to deliver that same experience. What could be better than complementing this unique operating system with a set of unique system sounds?
As R1 steadily approaches, we are looking for contestants (amateur, professional, enthusiast) to produce system sound effects for Haiku.</description></item><item><title>Haiku R1/beta2 has been released!</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2020-06-09_haiku_r1_beta2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2020-06-09_haiku_r1_beta2/</guid><description>After almost 2 years since R1/beta1, Haiku R1/beta2 has been released. See &amp;ldquo;Release Notes&amp;rdquo; for the release notes, &amp;ldquo;Press contact&amp;quot;, for press inquiries &amp;hellip; and &amp;ldquo;Get Haiku!&amp;rdquo; to skip all that and just download the release (or upgrade to it from an existing install!)</description></item><item><title>Google Code-in 2019 finished</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2020-02-13_google_code-in_2019_finished/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2020 08:14:36 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2020-02-13_google_code-in_2019_finished/</guid><description>This 2019/2020 Google Code-in (GCI) was the 10th iteration in as many years and according to Google&amp;rsquo;s stats it was the most successful yet: In 7 weeks 3,566 students from 76 countries finished 20,840 tasks for 29 open source organizations!
Haiku was one of those organizations - the only open source project, by the way, that participated in all 10 editions of GCI - and we had our share of dedicated students that completed numerous tasks, big and small.</description></item><item><title>It's almost time for the 2019 Google Code-In and Haiku is ready!</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2019-11-7_its_almost_time_for_the_2019_google_code-in_and_haiku_is_ready/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2019 12:40:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2019-11-7_its_almost_time_for_the_2019_google_code-in_and_haiku_is_ready/</guid><description>Another year, another Google Code-In! The Haiku project is proud to announce that it will be participating in the 2019 Google Code-In!
Together with 28 other open source projects, we&amp;rsquo;ll mentor students between 13 and 17 years of age through a variety of large and small tasks. The aim is to introduce them to the work and community of open source projects, while benefitting ourselves from their work and energy, and maybe even by gaining future contributors.</description></item><item><title>GCI 2018 - Wrap-up report</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2019-03-10_gci2018oct-dec-wrap-up-report/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2019 16:42:01 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2019-03-10_gci2018oct-dec-wrap-up-report/</guid><description>Better late than never&amp;hellip; Here&amp;rsquo;s a quick report on GCI 2018.
Google Code-in is the annual contest for students between 13 and 17. It brings together teenagers and open source organizations with the idea of giving &amp;ldquo;pre-university students&amp;rdquo; an experience of real world coding which might inspire them to consider Computer Science in their future educational and career plans.
At the end of the contest, each organization chooses five finalists. These finalists each receive limited edition Google Code-in hoodies.</description></item><item><title>Haiku to mentor interns in Google Summer of Code and Outreachy</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2019-02-26_haiku_gets_into_gsoc_and_outreachy/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 17:47:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2019-02-26_haiku_gets_into_gsoc_and_outreachy/</guid><description>Haiku is proud to once again be part of the Google Summer of Code. Over the summer, students will work on improving Haiku and related applications, with help from our mentor team. Google gives the students a stipend, which allows them to work full-time on the project without the need to find another job.
The goal of the program is to introduce students to the way open source projects work, and encourage them to become long term contributors.</description></item><item><title>Haiku R1/beta1 has been released</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2018_09_28_haiku_r1_beta1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2018 20:26:33 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2018_09_28_haiku_r1_beta1/</guid><description>After nearly 6 years since R1/alpha4, Haiku R1/beta1 has been released. See &amp;ldquo;Release Notes&amp;rdquo; for the (lengthy) release notes, &amp;ldquo;Press contact&amp;quot;, for press inquiries &amp;hellip; and &amp;ldquo;Get Haiku!&amp;rdquo; to skip all that and just download the release.</description></item><item><title>Back into Google Summer of Code</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2018-02-14_back_into_google_summer_of_code/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2018 17:47:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2018-02-14_back_into_google_summer_of_code/</guid><description>Haiku is proud to once again be part of the Google Summer of Code. Over the summer, students will work on improving Haiku and related applications, with help from our mentor team. Google gives the students a stipend, which allows them to work full-time on the project without the need to find another job.
The goal of the program is to introduce students to the way open source projects work, and encourage them to become long term contributors.</description></item><item><title>GCI 2017 Wrap Up Report</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2018-02-02_gci_2017_wrap_up_report/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2018 00:13:41 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2018-02-02_gci_2017_wrap_up_report/</guid><description>Like all good things Google Code-In 2017 comes to an end, this year the program attracted over 3555 students in total for Google Code-In and out of those about ⅓ of the students claimed at least one task for Haiku, with 255 students completing at least one Haiku task. Haiku is also proud of its history of getting selected each year in Google’s Code-In. Just like the other 24 organizations, Haiku picked winners out of the 10 students who completed the most tasks for Haiku, finalists and grand prize winners were picked collectively by the diligent team of Haiku’s 20+ mentors.</description></item><item><title>Back into Google Summer of Code</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2017-02-27_back_into_google_summer_of_code/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2017 17:47:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2017-02-27_back_into_google_summer_of_code/</guid><description>After a two year break, the Haiku project is proud to be part of Google Summer of Code again. Over the summer, students will work on improving Haiku and related applications, with help from our mentor team. Google gives the students a stipend, which allows them to work full-time on the project without the need to find another job.
The goal of the program is to introduce students to the way open source projects work, and encourage them to become long term contributors.</description></item><item><title>GCI 2016 Wrap Up Report</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2017-02-05_gci_2016_wrap_up_report/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 12:44:02 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2017-02-05_gci_2016_wrap_up_report/</guid><description>What happens when you combine 337 students, 20+ mentors, and an endless volley of tasks? During the time from November 2016 to January 2017, 368 Haiku tasks were successfully completed. The seventh year of Google’s Code-In, and the seventh for Haiku as a mentoring organization was a grand success.
Students from all around the world aged 13-17 worked with the project mentors on improving Haiku during the 7 weeks of the contest.</description></item><item><title>Haiku mentors once more in Google's Code-In</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2016-11-08_haiku_mentors_once_more_in_googles_code-in/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2016 17:47:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2016-11-08_haiku_mentors_once_more_in_googles_code-in/</guid><description>The Haiku project is proud to be once again part of Google&amp;rsquo;s Code-In. Together with 16 other open source projects we&amp;rsquo;ll mentor students between 13 and 17 years of age through various large and small tasks. The aim is to introduce them to the work and community of open source projects, while benefitting ourselves from their work and energy, and maybe even by gaining future contributers.
If you know people in the right age bracket that might be interested, point them to Google&amp;rsquo;s Code-In site that has all the information.</description></item><item><title>Media Kit Contract Underway</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2016-03-09_media_kit_contract_underway/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2016 15:53:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2016-03-09_media_kit_contract_underway/</guid><description>Last week, Haiku, Inc. accepted a 120 hour contract for Dario Casalinuovo.
Over the course of a month, Dario will be working on streaming support, improving the media_server, and improving/integrating the BMediaClient.
You can read more about his contract proposal here. Keep an eye on his blog for updates on his progress.
To further support Dario&amp;rsquo;s contract, Dane of TuneTracker Systems has donated $500 USD.
Dario has expressed his willingness to work on other areas of Haiku in the future once he has improved the media_kit, which is the area he is currently most comfortable working with.</description></item><item><title>WLAN Master Thesis Published</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2016-02-26_wlan_master_thesis_published/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2016 18:05:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2016-02-26_wlan_master_thesis_published/</guid><description>In 2010 Colin Günter finished his master thesis on Haiku&amp;rsquo;s WLAN stack. His work was supported by Haiku users with donations to Haikuware&amp;rsquo;s bounty program. After his move to New Zealand he didn&amp;rsquo;t find the time to prep the documents for publication. But now it&amp;rsquo;s finally done and available at a GitHub repo [Dead link as of December 2017].
Two documents (both mirrored at the Haiku website) should be interesting to developers curious about Haiku&amp;rsquo;s WLAN stack: The thesis Masterarbeit.</description></item><item><title>Haiku's GCI 2015 winners</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2016-02-13_haikus_gci_2015_winners/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2016 08:13:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2016-02-13_haikus_gci_2015_winners/</guid><description>&lt;p>In February the roughly two months long Google Code-In (GCI) period came to an end. See the results of all participating organizations at the &lt;a href="https://codein.withgoogle.com/winners/">GCI site&lt;/a>. As always, it&amp;rsquo;s been a strenuous time for students and mentors alike. Of course, it was a very productive one, too.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Google Code-In 2015 now in progress</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2015-12-07_google_code-in_2015_now_in_progress/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2015 16:15:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2015-12-07_google_code-in_2015_now_in_progress/</guid><description>For the sixth time Google&amp;rsquo;s Code-In program attracts students of the ages 13 to 17 from all over the world to work with open source projects. Haiku is once again proud to take part and is one of 14 mentor organizations that will supply tasks and guidance. The tasks range from coding and documentation to quality assurance and research. Each task is relatively small and should be accomplished in 3 to 6 hours.</description></item><item><title>Haiku, Inc. board of director elections complete</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2015-07-01_haiku_inc_board_director_elections_complete/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2015 20:13:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2015-07-01_haiku_inc_board_director_elections_complete/</guid><description>The Haiku, Inc. board of directors has the pleasure of announcing several new members to help support the project.
What is Haiku, Inc.?Haiku, Inc. is a 501(c)(3) non-profit organization dedicated to supporting the Haiku Project and the development of Haiku® (the "Software"). Haiku, Inc. does not have any technical decision making power within the Haiku project at large. The current board of directors: Axel Dörfler (axeld) Rene Gollent (DeadYak) Ryan Leavengood (leavengood) Urias McCullough (umccullough) Alexander von Gluck IV (kallisti5) Sadly, Bruno Albuquerque (BGA, Vice President) and Matthew Madia (mmadia, Secretary) have decided to step down from their positions on the board.</description></item><item><title>Analysis of Haiku Operating System (BeOS Family) by PVS-Studio</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2015-04-22_analysis_haiku_operating_system_beos_family_pvsstudio/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2015 07:30:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2015-04-22_analysis_haiku_operating_system_beos_family_pvsstudio/</guid><description>Development team of proprietary PVS-Studio C/C++ static analyzer presents their report on the source code of Haiku project in the article, which contains the review of the most suspicious code fragments they discovered.
While the Haiku developers are already using Coverity to identify some problems (mostly security related), PVS-Studio also detects code written in unusual ways or with possibly unexpected behavior. This means it can detect some functional issues, rather than just security problems.</description></item><item><title>Haiku at VALS' second Semester of Code</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2015-03-15_haiku_vals_second_semester_code/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2015 15:46:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2015-03-15_haiku_vals_second_semester_code/</guid><description>The Haiku project is participating again in this year's "Semester of Code" (SoC) of the European VALS project. The SoC is similar to Google's GSoC, but without the financial incentive and more emphasis on the educational side.
This is the second installment of "SoC", the objective is still the same:
Its goal is to connect higher education students with open source projects to introduce them to the cooperative nature of working within a group on a bigger project.</description></item><item><title>Google Code-In 2014 Wrap Up Report</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2015-02-13_google_codein_2014_wrap_report/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2015 08:53:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2015-02-13_google_codein_2014_wrap_report/</guid><description>&lt;p>Google has now announced the 24 winners for Google Code-In 2014, with Josef Gajdusek and Puck Meerburg being the two winners from Haiku. This is Puck&amp;rsquo;s second time winning for Haiku. This year we got to pick our top 5 out of the top 10 students who completed that most tasks for Haiku. Augustin Cavalier was selected as our backup winner, and Markus Himmel and Chirayu Desai were selected as finalist. Chirayu was a GCI 2013 winner with RTEMS, and made the jump to Haiku when RTEMS took this year off from GCI.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This was the fifth year of Google&amp;rsquo;s Code-In, and the fifth for Haiku. This year we had 6 students who completed 20 or more tasks, one more than in 2013. We had 36 students who completed three or more tasks and qualified for a Google Code-In T-Shirt, and 53 students who completed two or more tasks. This was the first year of having beginner tasks, aimed at lowering the bar to get more new students introduced into open source. Haiku had 149 total students complete at least one task, many of those were for the beginner tasks. We had 164 beginner tasks completed, which was mostly just to introduce students to booting and using Haiku. Other beginner tasks were to compile Haiku or to install and use Haikuporter to build a package from a recipe file. In total students completed a staggering 435 tasks this time for Haiku.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Google's Code-In in progress</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2014-12-01_googles_codein_progress/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 07:15:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2014-12-01_googles_codein_progress/</guid><description>The Haiku project was once again chosen as a mentor organization for this year&amp;rsquo;s Google Code-In. The little brother of the Summer of Code is targeting younger students - 13 to 17 years old - and consists of many small tasks that are suitable for that age group. Under the lead of Scott McCreary, over a dozen Haiku mentors have entered roughly 400 tasks into Haiku&amp;rsquo;s GCI page, mostly about creating or fixing haikuporter recipes to package applications and small C++ coding tasks.</description></item><item><title>Haiku at VALS' Semester of Code</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2014-10-10_haiku_vals_semester_code/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 17:01:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2014-10-10_haiku_vals_semester_code/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Haiku project is participating in this year&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Semester of Code&amp;rdquo; (SoC) of the European &lt;a href="http://virtualalliances.eu/what-is-vals/">VALS&lt;/a> project. The SoC is similar to Google&amp;rsquo;s GSoC, but without the financial incentive and more emphasis on the educational side.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Its goal is to connect higher education students with open source projects to introduce them to the cooperative nature of working within a group on a bigger project. For Haiku, besides potentially extending its feature set, it&amp;rsquo;s another opportunity to spark the interest of new, eager developers with a chance to gain future regular contributors.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Haiku nightlies site moved!</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2014-07-15_haiku_nightlies_site_moved/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2014 19:57:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2014-07-15_haiku_nightlies_site_moved/</guid><description>
Effective immediately, the Haiku Nightlies page has moved from &lt;a href="http://haiku-files.org/">http://haiku-files.org/&lt;/a> to &lt;a href="https://download.haiku-os.org/">https://download.haiku-os.org/&lt;/a>.</description></item><item><title>An extensive interview with Haiku developer - Paweł Dziepak.</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2014-05-10_extensive_interview_haiku_developer_pawe%C5%82_dziepak/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 May 2014 08:08:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2014-05-10_extensive_interview_haiku_developer_pawe%C5%82_dziepak/</guid><description>&lt;p align="justify">&lt;em>I have interviewed &lt;strong>Paweł Dziepak&lt;/strong> during my private conversation with him, on polish Haiku IRC channel (&lt;strong>#haiku-pl, Freenode&lt;/strong>). We talked for two nights, on 28 and 29 of April 2014. &lt;strong>Paweł&lt;/strong> is known to the community as &lt;strong>pdziepak&lt;/strong>, I am &lt;strong>Premislaus&lt;/strong>. There are many great people involved with &lt;strong>Haiku Project&lt;/strong>, everyone is worth interviewing - I will try to do that in the future (&lt;strong>Ingo&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Axel&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>Stephan&lt;/strong>, beware!). Why &lt;strong>pdziepak&lt;/strong> this time? The big role in the decision played ease of communication, since we are the same nationality, we talk pretty often with each other on IRC channel. Besides, he is an excellent programmer, engineer with vision! Despite his young age, he doesn't do mobile apps, his field of interest are kernel architectures. Unfortunately, he didn't have current photo and he said no when I proposed him to take a stylish one, either selfie or in an elevator.&lt;/em>&lt;/a>
&lt;p align="justify">&lt;em>We had deep and sincere conversation about &lt;strong>Haiku Project and Community&lt;/strong> condition. I also asked him about Open Source movement in general. The part of that I present to you below:&lt;/em>&lt;/a></description></item><item><title>The Heartbleed Aftermath... Some Things You Should Know</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2014-04-11_heartbleed_aftermath_some_things_you_should_know/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2014 17:28:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2014-04-11_heartbleed_aftermath_some_things_you_should_know/</guid><description>&lt;p>As most of our visitors have probably already heard in the last few days - one of the largest security disasters I can recall in modern internet history was discovered, and dubbed &amp;ldquo;Heartbleed&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Miracles do happen; Development contract for April!</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2014-03-31_miracles_do_happen_development_contract_april/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2014 20:40:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2014-03-31_miracles_do_happen_development_contract_april/</guid><description>Wow. Thanks to our donors' generousity, Adrien is able to continue for a seventh month of improving WebPositive, WebKit and its related techologies. $2145 has been raised this past month! This is spot on with the number mentioned in last month's contract announcement article. If you did not hear, Adrien has started working on HTML5 Audio/Video support, specifically the audio portion. As usual, he is publishing weekly progress reports on his blog.</description></item><item><title>Funded development continues into March!</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2014-02-28_funded_development_continues_march/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 04:20:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2014-02-28_funded_development_continues_march/</guid><description>&lt;p>Within these past 4 weeks, over $1,200 USD and &amp;EUR;900 EUR have been raised! Thanks directly to this fundraising, Adrien is now able to be funded through the month of March. With the addition of the newest monthly subscribers, we reached a milestone and now raise over $1,000 per month through recurring monthly donations!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Contract extension and 2013 financial review.</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2014-02-06_contract_extension_and_2013_financial_review/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2014 03:01:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2014-02-06_contract_extension_and_2013_financial_review/</guid><description>&lt;p>
Pawel's contract has concluded with his work being merged into Haiku's master repository. Hopefully within the next few days, he will be able to post another blog post to summarize the improvements.
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
Now the even better news -- the recent donations from everyone has made it possible for Adrien to continue for another month! If another $1200 USD is raised by the end of this month, then there will definitely be enough funds to keep him coding through March (At the moment, our reserves would drop to below $800 USD, which is something we try to avoid.)
&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Google Code-In 2013 wrap up report</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2014-01-20_google_codein_2013_wrap_report/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2014 05:48:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2014-01-20_google_codein_2013_wrap_report/</guid><description>Google has now announced the 20 winners for Google Code-In 2013, with Freeman Lou and Puck Meerburg being the two winners from Haiku.
This was the fourth year of Google's Code-In, and the fourth for Haiku. This contest came at a good point this year for Haiku as the package management merge happened just a few weeks prior to the start of the contest and thus gave us plenty of ideas for tasks.</description></item><item><title>Happy Contract Extensions!</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2014-01-01_happy_contract_extensions/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 19:17:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2014-01-01_happy_contract_extensions/</guid><description>
&lt;p>
This may be the final chapter of contract extensions, as the available funds will be plummeting to less than $1500 USD.
&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>An excellent donation from Google, extended contracts, and Google Code-In update</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2013-11-30_excellent_donation_google_extended_contracts_and_google_codein_update/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2013 12:26:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2013-11-30_excellent_donation_google_extended_contracts_and_google_codein_update/</guid><description>
&lt;p>
This is excellent news.
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
As mentioned in the last contract announcement article, the available funding of Haiku, Inc. was starting to dry up.
It had gotten so low, that Adrien and Paweł were told not to expect a third month of contractual development.
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
However ... &lt;strong>Google has contacted the project and informed us of a $5,000 USD donation!&lt;/strong>
The donation is being processed and should be deposited in the next few weeks.
To simply say "Thank you." is not enough to express the depth of our gratitude.
Instead, many agree that actions speak louder than words.
This donation will immediately be used to finance Adrien and Paweł's contracts for an additional month.
There are few, if any, better uses for this money than to provide two previous Google Summer of Code students the opportunity to flip bits, not burgers.
... and by the way, Thank you Google! :-D
&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Good news everybody -- contracts and more!</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2013-10-20_good_news_everybody_contracts_and_more/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2013 21:32:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2013-10-20_good_news_everybody_contracts_and_more/</guid><description>
&lt;p>
If there was ever an example of the saying "Money talks and ...", this is it.
Since publishing the "HAIKU needs you!" article in late August, over $5,000 has been raised!
This is from 110 individuals who made a combined 75 recurring monthly donations and 72 one-time donations.
The yearly total is soaring over $20,000 with the help of 322 donors making 354 recurring and 322 one-time donations.
&lt;strong>Because of their efforts and generosity, we are able to finance another month of contractual development for both Adrien and Pawel!&lt;/strong>
Thank you and congratulations to everyone who helped!
&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>HAIKU needs you!</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2013-08-29_haiku_needs_you/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2013 00:42:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2013-08-29_haiku_needs_you/</guid><description>&lt;p>We have heard you. Other areas of Haiku need some loving. Though, we need your contribution to make this awesome.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First and foremost, the package management contracts are going well and are starting to wind down. Ingo is expected to finish his last month within the next week. Oliver will have another 160 hours (spread over two months). As for actual progress, as seen in Ingo&amp;rsquo;s recent blog post, it has been amazing. Hybrids are working (even ground work is done for future possible x86_64 + x86-gcc4 + x86-gcc2 combinations!). Building and updating Haiku for new platforms (e.g., various ARM platforms) is easier for developers. The tool for building ported software, haikuporter, is much more versatile, functional and reduces complexities for porters. They have requested wide spread testing of the &lt;a href="http://www.haiku-files.org/unsupported-builds/package-management-preview">HaikuPM images&lt;/a>, in anticipation of merging the changes back into master branch.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On to current news &amp;ndash; two developers, Adrien &amp;ldquo;PulkoMandy&amp;rdquo; Destugues and Pawel &amp;ldquo;pdziepak&amp;rdquo; Dziepak wish to have the opportunity to dedicate full-time hours improving different aspects of Haiku. Adrien plans to work on our port of WebKit and our native browser, Webpositive. His first task will be to bring the Services Kit to maturation, which was a former Google Summer of Code project. Pawel desires to enhance CPU scheduler, with respect to utilizing caches better, performance on HyperThread enabled processors and power-savvy (as in wattage consumption) features. As of now, there are only enough funds to provide each developer with a single month of contractual development!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>BIG contracts and a call to support HAIKU!</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2013-05-27_big_contracts_and_call_support_haiku/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2013 15:42:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2013-05-27_big_contracts_and_call_support_haiku/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="../files/todo-donate.png" border="8" align="right" />
&lt;p>
We are excited to finally share this news about development contracts!
We are going to be funding a minimum 800 hours of HAIKU development and with your help, many more hours!
And to help you preview the progress, there is a set of &lt;a href="http://www.haiku-files.org/unsupported-builds/package-management-preview">pre-built package management images&lt;/a> available!
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
As you know, Ingo and Oliver have been working these past months on Haiku's package management for extremely low rates -- to the tune of &amp;euro;12.50 per hour.
It is a commendable and fortunate event to have developers who are able to devote large blocks of time in their schedules for such a meager pay scale.
This time, we are going to try new models for each of them, in order to secure even more dedicated development time.
&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Google Summer of Code 2013 - Update</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2013-04-09_google_summer_code_2013_update/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2013 15:22:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2013-04-09_google_summer_code_2013_update/</guid><description>Bummer!
We did not make it into Google Summer of Code this year. We were fortunate to be selected so often in the past, but apparently it&amp;rsquo;s now time to let other projects benefit from this summer event; 177 out of 417 projects were chosen this year. GSoC 2012 went especially well for us though, which certainly makes this announcement that much more difficult to swallow. Congratulations and best wishes to the organizations that were accepted, and hopefully we&amp;rsquo;ll have better luck next year.</description></item><item><title>Google donates $5,000 USD. "Thank you" is not enough.</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2013-01-27_google_donates_5000_usd_thank_you_not_enough/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Jan 2013 16:16:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2013-01-27_google_donates_5000_usd_thank_you_not_enough/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="../files/star-thank-you.png" border="8" align="right" />
&lt;p>
What an upbeat way to start the new year!
&lt;strong>Google, Inc. has donated Five-Thousand Dollars to Haiku, Inc.&lt;/strong>
Earlier in December, a Google employee contacted the project to coordinate
their donation. The transaction was received this month and shows as part
of 2013's fundraising progress. This donation will greatly assist in securing
additional development time specifically for HAIKU!
Thank you Google, Inc!
&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Haiku is looking for Web Developers</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2012-12-22_haiku_is_looking_for_web_developers/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Dec 2012 21:28:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2012-12-22_haiku_is_looking_for_web_developers/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Haiku project is supported by various websites and web services, such as the &lt;a href="../>main website&lt;/a>, the &lt;a href="https://dev.haiku-os.org/">development tracker&lt;/a> and the &lt;a href="http://i18n.haiku-os.org/pootle">translation tools&lt;/a>. For all these services we have various short and long term goals and objectives, and we are looking for help to realize our plans.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Helping out means that you are contributing to the continued development of Haiku! We are looking for people with Drupal/PHP skills and people with Python experience.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Haiku Amongst 10 Open-source Organizations To Participate in Google Code-In 2012</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2012-11-25_haiku_amongst_10_opensource_organizations_participate_google_codein_2012/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Nov 2012 21:16:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2012-11-25_haiku_amongst_10_opensource_organizations_participate_google_codein_2012/</guid><description>What is Google Code-in ? GCI is a contest for pre-university students (from 13 to 17 years old) with the goal to encourage young students to participate into open-source development. To achieve that goal, open-source organizations sets up various tasks and students are invited to claim them. Various prizes are awarded and, this year, each organizations are going to award two (2) grand prize winners amongst participating students.
When does the contest start ?</description></item><item><title>Haiku Release 1 Alpha 4.1</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2012-11-14_haiku_release_1_alpha_41/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Nov 2012 15:45:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2012-11-14_haiku_release_1_alpha_41/</guid><description>Due to the immediate testing efforts of HAIKU Release 1 Alpha 4, several critical bugs were detected by testers and reported on our bug tracker. On several hardware configurations, those issues prevented Haiku from booting properly. Since then, those bugs have been squashed and are resolved in this bugfix update, R1 Alpha 4.1. There are two general issues fixed by this point release:
Deskbar can freeze at boot-up on read-only media.</description></item><item><title>Haiku Release 1 Alpha 4</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2012-11-12_haiku_release_1_alpha_4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2012 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2012-11-12_haiku_release_1_alpha_4/</guid><description>
&lt;a href="http://www.haiku-inc.org/order-disc.html" title="Haiku R1 Alpha 4 CD"
>&lt;img src="../files/r1a4-cd-graphic.png" alt="Haiku R1 Alpha 4 CD" style="float: right;margin: 0 10px 0 30px;" />&lt;/a>
&lt;p>
The Haiku Project is excited to announce the availability of our
fourth official alpha release. A year and four months have passed
since the Alpha 3 and the Haiku Project has been busy. The main
purpose of this release is to provide interested third party
developers with a stable version for testing and development.
To aid with that, Haiku includes a rich set of development tools.
&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>BeGeistert 026 - "Marathon"</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2012-10-07_begeistert_026_marathon/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Oct 2012 15:28:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2012-10-07_begeistert_026_marathon/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;span class="inline right">&lt;img src="../files/screenshots/begeistert-logo.png" alt="BeGeistert Logo" title="BeGeistert Logo" class="image image-_original " width="272" height="60" />&lt;/span>
Hello everyone!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The &lt;a href="http://www.haiku-support-association.org/index-eng.html">Haiku Support Association (HSA)&lt;/a> would like to invite everyone to the 26th BeGeistert on 3rd &amp;amp; 4th of November 2012. The location will be once again the youth hostel in Düsseldorf, Germany.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For years now, BeGeistert has been the regular get-together of users and developers of Haiku (and BeOS before that); a nice opportunity to present the latest projects and get a direct reaction from the participants.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Two contractors, each for two months!</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2012-08-20_two_contractors_each_two_months/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2012 21:26:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2012-08-20_two_contractors_each_two_months/</guid><description>That's right -- Oliver Tappe and Ingo Weinhold have been accepted for individual contracts![1, 2] Each of them will be working for two 160 hour periods. That adds up to an additional 640 hours of dedicated HAIKU development time for a total cost of €8,000 EUR. The area of focus will be Haiku's package management. (See A brief summary of HAIKU's package management. for an explanation of how package management will work.</description></item><item><title>He's back, back in the Haiku groove!</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2012-06-30_hes_back_back_haiku_groove/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jun 2012 16:49:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2012-06-30_hes_back_back_haiku_groove/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="../files/lighter.png" border="8" align="left" />&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ok it hasn&amp;rsquo;t been years since Michael was here, on IRC passin&amp;rsquo; his time away.
To the left and to the right, commits towering to the sky.
It&amp;rsquo;s outta sight in the dead of night
Here he is, again in this project, with a fistful of keystrokes
And baby, you better believe.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>He&amp;rsquo;s back, back in the Haiku groove!
He&amp;rsquo;s back, back in the Haiku groove!
(Ok, enough ripping off &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=L-4vMQOOiUY">KISS lyrics&lt;/a>)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Michael Lotz has been casually making commits in his &lt;a href="https://github.com/mmlr/haiku/commits/key_store">KeyStore feature branch&lt;/a>! First as a reminder to everyone, as Michael &lt;a href="../blog/mmlr/2011-11-28_bugs_back_wireless_and_friends">explained&lt;/a> the KeyStore API will be able to &amp;ldquo;securely manage keys, passwords, certificates, etc. in a central place and generic way (so that it can be used by other applications as well)&amp;quot;. More details on its design and functionality are mentioned in &lt;a href="../blog/mmlr/2011-12-23_api_design_hard_finding_bugs_can_be_made_easy">Michael&amp;rsquo;s blog&lt;/a>. As you can imagine the KeyStore API will add much appreciated functionality to Haiku, specifically in the area of managing wifi connections.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Magazine Article About Haiku Published in the May 2012 Issue of IEEE Spectrum</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2012-05-30_magazine_article_about_haiku_published_may_2012_issue_ieee_spectrum/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2012 17:29:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2012-05-30_magazine_article_about_haiku_published_may_2012_issue_ieee_spectrum/</guid><description>Long time Haiku contributor and Haiku, Inc. board of directors member Ryan Leavengood recently wrote an article about Haiku, which was just published in the May 2012 issue of IEEE Spectrum. For those Haiku community members who are IEEE members you can read the article in your print magazine, and all others can read the whole article online.
The Haiku project is always appreciative of any positive media coverage, and we want to thank Ryan for writing the article and the staff of IEEE Spectrum for publishing it.</description></item><item><title>A new development contractor!</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2012-05-20_new_development_contractor/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 May 2012 16:03:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2012-05-20_new_development_contractor/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="../files/WebPositive.png" border="8" align="right" />
&lt;p>
Announcing development contracts is one of the best feelings.
It is a time when a volunteer developer is given the opportunity
to dedicate a large block of time for their hobby -- developing HAIKU!
This is made possible through the countless donations from people like you,
who love Haiku and are willing to give what is right for them, to make Haiku a better
operating system. Thank you to all of
&lt;a href="http://www.haiku-inc.org/public-sponsors.html">our supporters, both public and anonymous&lt;/a>!
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
This time, we are pleased to announce that &lt;strong>Alexandre Deckner will be working
on the WebKit port and, if time allows, WebPositive&lt;/strong>. You may remember "aldeck"
primarily from his work on Tracker -- squashing bugs, rewriting sections for better
performance and updating it to &lt;a href="https://github.com/aldeck/haiku/tree/tracker_layout">utilize the Layout API&lt;/a>.
As Alexandre states, &lt;i>
"Good web support is something crucial for any operating system these days,
it is for some users the main software they will use on a computer and one
of the first things a new user will try on Haiku. To summarize, Haiku has
to provide the best web experience possible and i believe i can help to go
in that direction."&lt;/i>
&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>RealLife(TM)</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2012-04-22_reallifetm/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Apr 2012 22:09:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2012-04-22_reallifetm/</guid><description>
&lt;p>
To be honest, this article is something I have been dreading.
It's one of those situations, where you hope and pray that it gets better before you take action, but it hasn't.
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
Michael has landed onto some tough times.
The injury from some weeks ago has healed well enough.
However, RealLife&amp;trade; has prevented him from focusing on Haiku.
It involves his personal life outside of Haiku. That's all we know and that's all we need to know.
With everything that has happened and will continue to play out over the next weeks, Michael has decided to cease the contract.
In the future, he does plan to contribute to Haiku.
For now though, he needs to take a step back.
&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>First Bugfix Weekend</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2012-03-28_first_bugfix_weekend/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2012 18:30:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2012-03-28_first_bugfix_weekend/</guid><description>We'd like to invite every developer to our first Bugfix Weekend this weekend March 31st to April 1st. It's an idea recently brought up on the developer mailinglist that developers should regularly meet up virtually to solve bugs or enhancement tickets from our bugtracker together.
While it's a bit short notice, it fits nicely with the 25th BeGeistert meeting that is held on that same date in Düsseldorf. That way everyone can participate in the two day hackfest even if they can't make it there in person.</description></item><item><title>BeGeistert 025 "Silver" registration now open!</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2012-03-20_begeistert_025_silver_registration_now_open/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2012 14:47:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2012-03-20_begeistert_025_silver_registration_now_open/</guid><description>Late as always the registration for the 25th BeGeistert event is now open at last. Head over to www.begeistert.org if you want to take part in it.
The jubilee event is taking place at the youth hostel Düsseldorf as usual. Many of Haiku's core developers will attend, and discuss the future of Haiku among other things. It's a social event where Haiku developers and users come together to share their ideas, and experiences, even though there will also be workshops, and presentations for those interested.</description></item><item><title>ReactOS gets USB Stack, with Help from Us</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2012-02-20_reactos_gets_usb_stack_help_us/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2012 23:22:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2012-02-20_reactos_gets_usb_stack_help_us/</guid><description>&lt;p>The &lt;a href="http://www.reactos.org/">ReactOS&lt;/a> and Haiku projects have had a friendly working relationship for several years now, with each group helping the other whenever possible. These range from &lt;a href="../news/2008-07-14/haiku_to_exhibit_at_linuxworld_2008">helping&lt;/a> &lt;a href="../blog/mmu_man/2009-02-09/fosdem_2009_report">each other&lt;/a> with conference attendance at &lt;a href="http://www.socallinuxexpo.org/">SCALE&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="http://fosdem.org/">FOSDEM&lt;/a> to development related matters. Haiku was especially helpful during ReactOS’ successful application to &lt;a href="http://code.google.com/soc/">Google Summer of Code&lt;/a> 2011, providing advice and feedback on ReactOS’ application efforts, and the ReactOS project remains grateful for the assistance.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The current ReactOS USB stack was started by Michael Martin, with Johannes Anderwald quickly joining in the development effort. Recently Johannes made &lt;a href="http://www.reactos.org/en/newsletter_90.html#sec1">significant progress&lt;/a> in completing its USB stack, thanks to the reference Haiku&amp;rsquo;s USB stack provided.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>SOPA / PIPA information</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2012-01-18_sopa_pipa_information/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2012 15:39:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2012-01-18_sopa_pipa_information/</guid><description>Today the internet is taking a moment to protest the current US internet censorship bills.
SOPA and its brother PIPA are universally seen as limiting free speech on the internet. Many organizations including Google, Wikipedia, Reddit, and thousands of others are using today to better inform the public in a non-partisan way that these bills are bad for freedom on the internet at large.
You can find more information on SOPA, PIPA, and who you can contact to voice your opinion to at sopablackout.</description></item><item><title>2011: From the desk of Haiku, Inc.</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2012-01-03_2011_desk_haiku_inc/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2012 03:42:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2012-01-03_2011_desk_haiku_inc/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="../files/haiku-inc.png" border="8" align="left" />
&lt;p>
2011 has been an amazing year for Haiku in many ways. It is easy to
see the improvements in Haiku (the operating system) by looking at
the nightly builds or the bug tracker. In quite such a tangible way.
&lt;a href="http://www.haiku-inc.org">Haiku, Inc.&lt;/a> serves as the business arm of the project, if you will,
collecting donations, handling paperwork, dealing with web hosting,
etc. It is a little harder to see some of the improvements in
Haiku, Inc. sometimes - they are a little more "behind the scenes",
so we wanted to take this time to talk about all of the good stuff
that has happened!
&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>University of Auckland: Scholarship awarded! Call for Students/Visitors!</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2011-11-19_university_auckland_scholarship_awarded_call_studentsvisitors/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Nov 2011 17:08:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2011-11-19_university_auckland_scholarship_awarded_call_studentsvisitors/</guid><description>&lt;p>Exciting times these are. Haiku, Inc. steadily marches towards being capable of funding a core developer for 12 months of contractual development. &lt;i>Thank you donors!&lt;/i> BeGeistert 024 has spurred a flurry of commits, even continuing past the coding sprint. Google has accepted Haiku as a mentoring organization in its &lt;a href="http://www.google-melange.com/gci/homepage/google/gci2011">Google Code-in 2011&lt;/a> program. The version control system has been &lt;a href="https://www.freelists.org/post/haiku-development/Weve-switched-to-Git,2">migrated from subversion to git&lt;/a>. &lt;i>Thank you sys-admins!&lt;/i> And on top of all this, the &lt;http://www.cs.auckland.ac.nz/~lutteroth/">University of Auckland&lt;/a> has awarded Alex "yourpalal" Wilson with a 2011/12 International Summer Scholarship for a research project in Haiku! And the university has placed an open call for additional students and visitors!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2011 Google Code-In Contest, Haiku Selected as One of Eighteen Participating Organzations</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2011-11-10_2011_google_codein_contest_haiku_selected_one_eighteen_participating_organzations/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2011 04:18:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2011-11-10_2011_google_codein_contest_haiku_selected_one_eighteen_participating_organzations/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Haiku has been selected as one of eighteen organizations to participate in the Google Code-In 2011!&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Once again Haiku has been selected to participate in Google Code-In. To read the announcement and to see what other organizations were selected see [1] below. Here&amp;rsquo;s some basic information on the contest:&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="alert alert-info">
&lt;span class="inline inline-right">
&lt;img src="http://code.google.com/opensource/gci/2011-12/gci_logo.jpg" alt="Google Code-In 2011 logo" />&lt;/span>
Google's contest to introduce pre-university students to the many kinds of contributions that make open source software development possible, is starting on November 21, 2011. We are inviting students worldwide to produce a variety of open source code, documentation, training materials and user experience research for the organizations participating this year. These tasks include:
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Code: Tasks related to writing or refactoring code&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Documentation: Tasks related to creating/editing documents&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Outreach: Tasks related to community management and outreach/marketing&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Quality Assurance: Tasks related to testing and ensuring code is of high quality&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Research: Tasks related to studying a problem and recommending solutions&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Training: Tasks related to helping others learn more&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Translation: Tasks related to localization&lt;/li>
&lt;li>User Interface: Tasks related to user experience research or user interface design and interaction&lt;/div>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Official Google Code-In website and to review the updated rules for 2011. [2]&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Over the next couple of weeks we will be busy getting our task list in order and putting together a good group of Haiku mentors for this. Many of the tasks will be for translations, so we may still need a few more mentors to cover some of those tasks. If you are interested in mentoring please let us know on the mailing list. For a preview of some of the possible Haiku tasks, you can check the wiki page we used for gathering ideas. [3]&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Invitation to BeGeistert 024</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2011-10-11_invitation_begeistert_024/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2011 16:24:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2011-10-11_invitation_begeistert_024/</guid><description>
&lt;span class="inline right">&lt;img src="../files/screenshots/begeistert-logo.png" alt="BeGeistert Logo" title="BeGeistert Logo" class="image image-_original " width="272" height="60" />&lt;/span>&lt;p>Dear Haiku developers and users!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We'd like to invite everyone to &lt;a href="http://www.haiku-support-association.org/index-eng.html">HSA's&lt;/a> 24th BeGeistert, the largest Haiku conference around. On the weekend of October 29th/30th developers and users meet again in &lt;a href="http://www.jugendherberge.de/jh/rheinland/duesseldorf/index.shtml.en?m">Düsseldorf's Youth Hostel&lt;/a> to code and talk and see what's new in the Haiku world. A perfect opportunity to learn of others' projects or present your own.&lt;br />
Currently we plan to have these talks and workshops on the agenda:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Google Summer of Code 2011 Results!</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2011-09-03_google_summer_code_2011_results/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2011 18:44:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2011-09-03_google_summer_code_2011_results/</guid><description>
&lt;p>
&lt;em>Hot summer of code&lt;br />
Students learned a lot, had fun&lt;br />
Everyone wins!&lt;br />&lt;/em>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;b>Friday August 26th 2011&lt;/b> marked the end of Google Summer of Code&amp;trade; 2011 and, once again, Haiku did great with 4 out of the 8 initial students passing the final evaluation (7 were actually evaluated, 1 having unfortunately failed at midterm). The raw numbers might be a little bit deceiving, given that the fundamental goal of the program is ultimately to attract new contributors to the project; and early indications are pointing toward a success in that perspective.
&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Survey results in</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2011-08-20_survey_results/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2011 15:53:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2011-08-20_survey_results/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Last year Dr. Miroslav Stimac asked the Haiku community to participate in a survey to gauge interest in Haiku, usage pattern and wishes for the future, and obtain some general demographic data. This was part of his master thesis "&lt;i>The desktop operating system Haiku&lt;/i>" that can now be &lt;a href="http://www.cuvillier.de/flycms/de/html/30/-UickI3zKPS77f08=/Buchdetails.html">ordered as PDF or printed book&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Miroslav is so kind to provide chapter 6 with the survey and his analysis as a &lt;a href="../files/Survey-Results-OS-Haiku.pdf">free download&lt;/a>. While naturally being quite technical at times, it offers some interesting numbers that may also become useful when considering strategies in the future. At last we now have some hard empirical data instead of vague feelings concerning size or interests of our community at this point of Haiku's evolution.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Decade of Haiku</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2011-08-18_decade_haiku/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2011 18:12:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2011-08-18_decade_haiku/</guid><description>Ten years ago today, the first post appeared on the mailing list of our project - then still called "OpenBeOS" - officially marking the start of our endeavor. Back then, with the imminent demise of Be Inc., there was an excitement and creative motivation in the air, that lead many to think a first release was only a matter of a few years. As it turns out, this estimation was a bit too optimistic.</description></item><item><title>(R) II: Return to the USPTO</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2011-07-14_r_ii_return_uspto/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2011 01:53:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2011-07-14_r_ii_return_uspto/</guid><description>On July 12th, 2011, Haiku&amp;reg; received its registration with the United States Patent and Trademark Office (USPTO). This registration is for "Haiku" the name (as opposed to the HAIKU logo&amp;reg;, which became a registered trademark in March). More precisely, this new registration is known as a "standard character claim" and affords much more protection than the "stylized mark" registration of the logo. Now for a quick crash course in trademarks.</description></item><item><title>Haikuware Donates $10,000 to Haiku!!!</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2011-07-07_haikuware_donates_10000_haiku/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2011 20:30:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2011-07-07_haikuware_donates_10000_haiku/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="../files/diamond_200.png" border="8" align="right" />
&lt;p>
That's right, you read that right. And no, today is not April 1st.
&lt;a href="http://www.haikuware.com">Haikuware&lt;/a>
has donated Ten-Thousand Dollars to Haiku, Inc.
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
Haiku, Inc. gratefully values each and every dollar that is is donated.
A contribution of this magnitude, well, it simply is astounding.
&lt;b>In other words, thank you once again, Haikuware!&lt;/b>
&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The time is now: Michael Lotz on a long term contract.</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2011-06-29_time_now_michael_lotz_long_term_contract/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2011 23:35:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2011-06-29_time_now_michael_lotz_long_term_contract/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="../files/target.png" border="8" align="right" />
&lt;p>
Haiku, Inc. is ecstatic to announce
&lt;b>Michael Lotz (AKA "mmlr") on a 6 month contract&lt;/b> developing Haiku!!
There is the intention to renew this contract for another 6 months,
making Michael to be the first person to be paid to work on Haiku for an
entire year and you can make that a reality!
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
The goal of his contract would be to work on anything and everything
to bring Haiku closer to its first production quality release, better known
as "R1". The scope, variety and quality of code that Michael has produced
over the past six years and even more recently, gives Haiku, Inc. the fullest
confidence in his ability to succeed in every task that he works on.
&lt;b>Simply put, Michael gets the job done and done right.&lt;/b>
&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Haiku Release 1 Alpha 3</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2011-06-20_haiku_release_1_alpha_3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2011-06-20_haiku_release_1_alpha_3/</guid><description>
&lt;a href="http://www.haiku-inc.org/order-disc.html" title="Haiku R1 Alpha 3 CD"
>&lt;img src="../files/r1a3-disc.png" alt="Haiku R1 Alpha 3 CD" style="float: right;margin: 0 10px 0 30px;" />&lt;/a>
&lt;p>
The Haiku Project is excited to announce the availability
of our third official alpha release. A year and a month have passed since
the Alpha 2 and the Haiku Project has been busy. The main purpose of this
release is to provide interested third party developers with a stable version
for testing and development. To aid with that, Haiku includes a rich set of
development tools.
&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Haiku, Inc. accepts a second development contract in 2011!</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2011-06-12_haiku_inc_accepts_second_development_contract_2011/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2011 16:44:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2011-06-12_haiku_inc_accepts_second_development_contract_2011/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="../files/code-o-matic.png" border="8" align="right" />
&lt;p>On the Haiku, Inc. mailing list, &lt;strong>Ingo Weinhold proposed a development contract.&lt;/strong>
You may know Ingo better by his commit id "bonefish", as he recently merged his POSIX signals development branch back into trunk as &lt;a href="https://dev.haiku-os.org/changeset/42116">r42116&lt;/a>.
His proposal is for &lt;strong>160 hours relating to furthering package management with a €2,000 EUR payout.&lt;/strong>
That is roughly a meager $18 USD per hour!
&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>FreeLists issues</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2011-05-26_freelists_issues/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2011 22:07:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2011-05-26_freelists_issues/</guid><description>As many have likely noticed, our trusty mailing lists hosted on freelists.org are currently down.
It seems freelists.org is having some kind of critical DNS issue which hasn&amp;rsquo;t yet been resolved. We have been unable to find out much info beyond that. If anyone has more details, please feel free to mention it in the comments.
However, since Haiku has a lot of mailing lists on freelists.org, this does drastically impact development and community discussion, we may have to relocate our mailing lists to another service if the problem doesn&amp;rsquo;t get resolved soon.</description></item><item><title>Haikuware donates $2,000 to Haiku, Inc.</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2011-04-30_haikuware_donates_2000_haiku_inc/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2011 16:28:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2011-04-30_haikuware_donates_2000_haiku_inc/</guid><description>A big and heartfelt thank-you goes out to Haikuware and its supporters. Over this weekend, a $2,002.09 donation has been made to Haiku, Inc. on behalf of Haikuware&amp;rsquo;s financial contributors. The current funds available to Haiku, Inc. are now over $13,000 dollars!
This donation will be earmarked for contractual work on any of the R1 requirements. Additionally, there are intentions to use other finances to supply developers with the necessary hardware to resolve issues and improve support for them.</description></item><item><title>Switch to XEmacs and fish</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2011-04-01_switch_xemacs_and_fish/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2011 00:11:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2011-04-01_switch_xemacs_and_fish/</guid><description>&lt;p>On this first of April, the main Haiku developers wish to announce an important change that will likely increase user friendliness of the overall Haiku experience. We are a bit late to report the news due to the excitement and the required planification work, but we hope everyone will enjoy the move.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Haiku Trademark Registration - Achievement Unlocked!</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2011-04-01_haiku_trademark_registration_achievement_unlocked/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2011-04-01_haiku_trademark_registration_achievement_unlocked/</guid><description>We are happy to announce that the trademark registration process of the HAIKU logo&amp;reg; has finally been completed (pdf) by Haiku, Inc. Over the last year or two, Haiku, Inc. has been seeking to cleanup the Haiku trademark usage. The official registration of the logo was a major part of that process.There are several benefits of having Federal trademark registration, which include fortifying the protection of the mark and entitling additional methods of resolving trademark infringers.</description></item><item><title>Haiku, Inc. accepts contract relating to package management</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2010-12-27_haiku_inc_accepts_contract_relating_package_management/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Dec 2010 23:50:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2010-12-27_haiku_inc_accepts_contract_relating_package_management/</guid><description>&lt;p>As seen with the poll for the &lt;a href="https://dev.haiku-os.org/wiki/FutureHaikuFeatures">must-have features for R1&lt;/a>, &lt;strong>the lack of proper package management is clearly one of the items that are delaying the release of R1&lt;/strong>. More importantly though, as package management is an actual lacking feature (as opposed to a bug in an existing implementation), even the beta cycle is being blocked as a result. In order to progress, Haiku needs package management.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2010 Google Code-In Contest, Haiku Selected as a Participating Organization</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2010-11-18_2010_google_codein_contest_haiku_selected_participating_organization/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Nov 2010 20:17:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2010-11-18_2010_google_codein_contest_haiku_selected_participating_organization/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Haiku has been selected as one of twenty organizations to participate in the 2010 Google Code-In!&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>From the Google announcement[1]:&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="alert alert-info">
&lt;span class="inline inline-right">
&lt;img src="http://code.google.com/opensource/gci/2010-11/images/gcilogo.jpg" alt="Google Code-In logo" />&lt;/span>
Google's contest to introduce pre-university students to the many kinds of contributions that make open source software development possible, is starting on November 22, 2010. We are inviting students worldwide to produce a variety of open source code, documentation, training materials and user experience research for the organizations participating this year. These tasks include:
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Code: Tasks related to writing or refactoring code&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Documentation: Tasks related to creating/editing documents&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Outreach: Tasks related to community management and outreach/marketing&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Quality Assurance: Tasks related to testing and ensuring code is of high quality&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Research: Tasks related to studying a problem and recommending solutions&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Training: Tasks related to helping others learn more&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Translation: Tasks related to localization&lt;/li>
&lt;li>User Interface: Tasks related to user experience research or user interface design and interaction&lt;/div>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Since we were picked on November 5th, we have been busy getting our task list in order and putting together a good group of Haiku mentors for this. Many of the tasks are for translations, so we may still need a few more mentors to cover some of those tasks. If you are interested in mentoring please let us know on the mailing list. For a preview of some of the possible Haiku tasks, you can check the wiki page we used for gathering ideas[2].&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Google Summer of Code 2010: Wrap up report</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2010-09-12_google_summer_code_2010_wrap_report/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Sep 2010 15:36:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2010-09-12_google_summer_code_2010_wrap_report/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="../files/gsoc2010logo-big.jpg" alt="Google Summer of Code 2010 Logo jpeg" border="8" align="right" />
&lt;p>
In the past four years, the Haiku Project has had both the honor and privilege
of being a Mentoring Organization in &lt;a href="http://socghop.appspot.com/"
>Google Summer of Code&amp;trade;&lt;/a>. This is a wonderful opportunity for the Project,
as it exposes Haiku to many potential youthful and energetic minds that are interested in developing Open Source Software. Even more exciting, it provides a unique opportunity of generating income for the Project while growing a handful of carefully selected students into knowledgeable and potential long-term contributors.
&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Haiku turns 9 today!</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2010-08-18_haiku_turns_9_today/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2010 14:44:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2010-08-18_haiku_turns_9_today/</guid><description>DaaT over at IsComputerOn reminds us that today is Haiku&amp;rsquo;s 9th birthday!
I guess we were so busy, we forgot to post something&amp;hellip; shame on us!</description></item><item><title>Stephan back at the wheel &amp; a website for Haiku, Inc.</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2010-08-12_stephan_back_wheel_website_haiku_inc/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2010 00:24:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2010-08-12_stephan_back_wheel_website_haiku_inc/</guid><description>Axel has now completed his contract, and intends to pursue the Haikuware bounty for implementing the missing bits of WiFi support over the next weeks. Your generous donations are allowing us to continue contracting Haiku developers for money. Thank-You-All for supporting these efforts! Stephan has submitted (edit: and has been accepted for) a development contract -- 160 hours at $2000 USD. Originally he proposed for additional features relating to WebPositive.</description></item><item><title>Opportunity to Pay Axel to Code Haiku!</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2010-07-14_opportunity_pay_axel_code_haiku/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2010 15:10:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2010-07-14_opportunity_pay_axel_code_haiku/</guid><description>
&lt;p>
We are excited to tell you about another proposal for contract development!
This time, it is from &lt;strong>Axel Dörfler. He is proposing to work 120 hours at $14
per hour, for a total of $1,680.&lt;/strong> To remind you of the sheer awesomeness of this,
Axel has been with the Project since nearly the beginning -- he joined a few
months after it was started in 2001. Axel was also
&lt;a href="../blog/axeld/2005-10-13/haikus_first_employee">Haiku's first employee back&lt;/a>
in 2005! This is a chance to get him back in the saddle -- or, according to some jokes,
back in the basement -- coding Haiku full time for a few weeks.
&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="alert alert-info">
&lt;strong>Astonishing Update:&lt;/strong> In a mere &lt;strike>24 hours, over $800&lt;/strike> &lt;strike>36 hours, over $1,100&lt;/strike> &lt;strong>42hours, over $3,000&lt;/strong> has been donated! Your response has been overwhelmingly amazing. Thank you for all of your support!
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Haiku @ oscon kyoto 2010</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2010-07-12_haiku_oscon_kyoto_2010/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2010 11:55:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2010-07-12_haiku_oscon_kyoto_2010/</guid><description>A few words about our effort at kansai open source conference in Kyoto 9-10.7.2010
I had no idea what to expect from an open source event here in kansai (osaka,kyoto,kobe,nara area of japan). Everything software in japan is very much focused to Tokyo so I was keen to see whats going on here at the boons so to speak.
After a few weeks of exchanging emails with jorge and eguchi-san, both which i&amp;rsquo;ve never met, we had trouble getting together to think about how we will present haiku and just decided to play by ear once we got to the event.</description></item><item><title>Survey about Haiku and BeOS</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2010-07-08_survey_about_haiku_and_beos/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2010 14:33:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2010-07-08_survey_about_haiku_and_beos/</guid><description>Miroslav Stimac, a part time student at the FernUniversitaet in Hagen, is writing a master thesis about Haiku and asks you to answer his survey at www.haiku-survey.com. The survey is relatively short, and should be answered in about two minutes.
The aggregated results of the survey are expected to be published in early 2011, so don&amp;rsquo;t hold your breath.</description></item><item><title>Haiku Featured in FLOSS Weekly</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2010-05-14_haiku_featured_floss_weekly/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 May 2010 11:27:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2010-05-14_haiku_featured_floss_weekly/</guid><description>The FLOSS Weekly (Free Libre Open Source Software) podcast is featuring Haiku in episode 120. Hosts Randal Schwartz and Aaron Seigo talk with Haiku developer Ryan Leavengood and contributor Niels Sascha Reedijk about the origins of Haiku, its purpose, the current status of the project and the potential for the future. Of course, alpha 2 is shamelessly being plugged!
Listen to the podcast now, or download it for later!</description></item><item><title>Haiku Project Announces Availability of Haiku R1/Alpha 2</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2010-05-10_haiku_project_announces_availability_haiku_r1alpha_2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 May 2010 22:14:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2010-05-10_haiku_project_announces_availability_haiku_r1alpha_2/</guid><description>
&lt;img src="../files/images/alpha-2-stamp.png" alt="Haiku R1 Alpha 2 stamp" style="float: right;margin: 0 0px 0 0px;" />
&lt;p>The Haiku Project is proud to announce the availability of Haiku R1A2, its second official alpha release. Haiku is an open source operating system that specifically targets personal computing intended for desktop use. Alpha 2 is a stable development release and a milestone on the way to the upcoming Release 1.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Seven students to be mentored by Haiku in Google Summer of Code 2010!</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2010-04-22_seven_students_be_mentored_haiku_google_summer_code_2010/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2010 19:14:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2010-04-22_seven_students_be_mentored_haiku_google_summer_code_2010/</guid><description>
&lt;p>
For this year's Google Summer of Code&amp;trade; program, we at Haiku have been allocated seven students!
Initially, we were allocated six students, but through a combination of good fortune and due diligence of our administrator Matthew Madia, an extra slot was allocated in the final days! In 2010, 367 mentoring orgs applied and there were 5539 proposals submitted by students.
Of those, Haiku is one of &lt;a href="http://socghop.appspot.com/gsoc/program/accepted_orgs/google/gsoc2010">152 accepted organizations&lt;/a>
and had 26 submitted proposals.
&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Launch sequence initialized! R1 Alpha 2 countdown in T minus ...</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2010-04-21_launch_sequence_initialized_r1_alpha_2_countdown_t_minus/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2010 16:04:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2010-04-21_launch_sequence_initialized_r1_alpha_2_countdown_t_minus/</guid><description>&lt;p>Over the weekend, an &lt;a href="https://www.freelists.org/post/haiku-development/Wrapping-up-R1-alpha-2">official commitment to enter the release cycle mode&lt;/a> has been made for a &lt;strong>tentative release date of May 10th&lt;/strong>! In the seven months since the release of R1 Alpha 1, there has been &lt;a href="https://dev.haiku-os.org/wiki/R1/ImprovementsSinceAlpha1">numerous improvements&lt;/a> to Haiku, with over 300 &lt;a href="https://dev.haiku-os.org/wiki/R1/Alpha1ReportedIssues">reported issues with R1 Alpha 1&lt;/a> fixed.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Haiku Inc.: Contractors (yes more!), Donation Analysis, and Google Checkout</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2010-04-07_haiku_inc_contractors_yes_more_donation_analysis_and_google_checkout/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2010 22:22:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2010-04-07_haiku_inc_contractors_yes_more_donation_analysis_and_google_checkout/</guid><description>
&lt;p>
In this installment, we are proud to announce Ingo Weinhold's contract,
a brief summary of our donation history, and a new method for accepting donations.
&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>TuneTracker Systems Donates Serial Driver</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2010-04-02_tunetracker_systems_donates_serial_driver/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Apr 2010 00:22:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2010-04-02_tunetracker_systems_donates_serial_driver/</guid><description>&lt;p>A newly-developed hardware driver will allow Haiku to access multiple serial ports via a PCI serial card. The new &amp;ldquo;pc_serial&amp;rdquo; driver was commissioned by &lt;a href="http://www.tunetrackersystems.com" title="TuneTracker Systems website">TuneTracker Systems&lt;/a> and is being donated to the Haiku user community.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Haiku Inc.: Contractors, Haiku Code Drive, and Available Funds.</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2010-03-22_haiku_inc_contractors_haiku_code_drive_and_available_funds/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2010 20:28:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2010-03-22_haiku_inc_contractors_haiku_code_drive_and_available_funds/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Several hot topics are covered in this update; new development contracts,
changes to our Haiku Code Drive program, and some notes about our immediate
finances.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Donation rally successful</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2010-03-05_donation_rally_successful/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2010 12:38:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2010-03-05_donation_rally_successful/</guid><description>&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s not just Stippi&amp;rsquo;s project that&amp;rsquo;s a huge success (see the WebKit/Web+ progress documented in his &lt;a href="../blog/stippi"> blog posts&lt;/a>). Our call for donations for this kind of contractual work is also doing very well!
In the two weeks since our announcement to hire developers for specific projects, donations have picked up significantly. Since then we received over $1,600USD and a few more people opting for small but recurrent monthly funding.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Our thanks go out to all contributors! This shows that our Haiku community is strong and effective when called upon!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Haiku Inc. is hiring - funds needed</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2010-02-21_haiku_inc_hiring_funds_needed/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2010 16:03:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2010-02-21_haiku_inc_hiring_funds_needed/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Haiku project rests on the shoulders of volunteer individuals who spend their free time developing, bughunting and in general advancing the system. Unfortunately everyone's time is limited and working for a living takes a major cut into what could be dedicated to Haiku work. It would be great if a developer could take off work for a few weeks to fully concentrate on Haiku development.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And this is exactly what we would like to make possible! Starting now:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>R1/Alpha 1 Commemorative CD Now Available</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2009-10-28_r1alpha_1_commemorative_cd_now_available/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2009 19:10:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2009-10-28_r1alpha_1_commemorative_cd_now_available/</guid><description>To all the Haiku fans out there who have been eagerly looking forward to getting their hands on the first official Haiku CD, the wait is finally over: Haiku R1/Alpha 1 CDs are now available on the Haiku Store! Since a lot of sweat and tears have gone into this first Haiku release, we wanted the availability of our first official CD to also be an opportunity for the community to give something back to the project.</description></item><item><title>Wrap-up Reports 2009 : Google Summer of Code, Haiku Code Drive</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2009-09-20_wrapup_reports_2009_google_summer_code_haiku_code_drive/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2009 03:18:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2009-09-20_wrapup_reports_2009_google_summer_code_haiku_code_drive/</guid><description>&lt;p>This year eight students were funded to work with Haiku during the summer months, six from Google in their &lt;a href="http://code.google.com/soc/">Google Summer of Code&lt;/a> program and two from Haiku Inc. for Haiku Code Drive. It is both my pleasure and honor to announce that overall this year has been more successful than last. Five of the six Google Summer of Code students passed, as well as one of two Haiku Code Drive students. On top of this achievement, Adrien Destugues and Bryce Groff were granted commit access for Haiku. Maxime Simon was approved by WebKit to receive commit access as well!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Before getting into the actual results for each student, it is worth re-visiting how we got here. This is the third year in which Haiku was selected to participate in Google Summer of Code. Each year we, as an organization, strive to improve our process for both the participating students and our community. Perhaps the most significant modification was the introduction of requiring students to resolve one or more tickets in our bug tracker. The intention was to ensure each applicant had a minimal level of exposure to our project. This includes navigating and building Haiku&amp;rsquo;s source code, as well as communicating through our mailing lists and other collaboration tools. Having the requirement fairly open ended allowed the applicants to provide our mentors with initial insight to their motivation, skill, and communicative abilities. The results speak for themselves: an increased number of passing students puts the proverbial stamp of approval on this new addition to our selection process. And now for the summaries for each student&amp;hellip;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Wi-Fi Stack With Atheros Driver Ready For Testing</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2009-09-15_wifi_stack_atheros_driver_ready_testing/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2009 08:24:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2009-09-15_wifi_stack_atheros_driver_ready_testing/</guid><description>After the exciting news of the Alpha 1 release, another bit of good news poured in. Colin Günther has been working on creating a Haiku WIFI stack for the WIFI bounty over at Haikuware. The stack, which he is creating as a part of his MSc Thesis, is currently a port of the FreeBSD 8.0 WLAN Stack. His further plans are described in his blog, where he writes about his progress.</description></item><item><title>Haiku Project Announces Availability of Haiku R1/Alpha 1</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2009-09-13_haiku_project_announces_availability_haiku_r1alpha_1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2009-09-13_haiku_project_announces_availability_haiku_r1alpha_1/</guid><description>
&lt;a href="../files/images/news/2009-09-14_r1a1-cd-mockup.png" title="Haiku R1 Alpha 1 CD" rel="lightbox" >&lt;img src="../files/images/news/2009-09-14_r1a1-cd-mockup.thumb.png" alt="Haiku R1 Alpha 1 CD" style="float: right;margin: 0 10px 0 30px;" />&lt;/a>
&lt;p>The Haiku Project is proud to announce the availability of Haiku R1/Alpha 1, the first official development release of Haiku, an open source operating system that specifically targets personal computing. The purpose of this release is to make a stable development snapshot of Haiku available to a wider audience for more extensive testing and debugging. This will help the Haiku development team identify and address bugs, and thus improve the quality of the system as development keeps advancing towards the subsequent development milestones. Bugs found in Alpha 1 should be reported to the Haiku bug tracking system at https://dev.haiku-os.org.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Website in Read-Only Mode Due to Upgrade in Preparation For Alpha 1 Release</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2009-09-09_website_readonly_mode_due_upgrade_preparation_alpha_1_release/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2009 16:37:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2009-09-09_website_readonly_mode_due_upgrade_preparation_alpha_1_release/</guid><description>The redesigned Haiku websiteIn preparation for the upcoming Haiku R1 Alpha 1 release, we are working on a Drupal upgrade and a redesign of the Haiku website. As a result, haiku-os.org is scheduled to operate in read-only mode from approximately September 9th at 17:00 through the 14th at 00:00AM (UTC). During this time, no major outages are expected and the website will be online for the most part, but the following operations will be disabled:</description></item><item><title>Summer of Code: Progress within the first month</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2009-06-26_summer_code_progress_within_first_month/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2009 18:29:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2009-06-26_summer_code_progress_within_first_month/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="field field-type-text field-field-body">
&lt;div class="field-items">
&lt;div class="field-item odd">
&lt;p>There have been some exciting developments from our Google Summer of Code and Haiku Code Drive students, even though it is only the first of three month. Here's a brief summary from most of the students. Be sure to visit their blogs for additional information and the occasional screenshot.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4>Adrien Destugues&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Lately, his work has been focusing on the catalogs for translating applications. These provide the mappings from one language to another. The initial mechanism is functional with Haiku's API and allows any application to be translated. This functionality is better explained in his &lt;a href="../blog/pulkomandy/2009-06-19/locale_kit_somewhat_weekly_report">blog post&lt;/a>. The &lt;a href="http://icu-project.org/">International Components for Unicode&lt;/a> or simply known as "ICU" and a preflet for selecting the desired locale are other major aspects to be implemented. Amongst other features, ICU will provide the formatting conversions for date, time, monetary, and locale specific characters. Further down the road (and beyond GSoC) is an API wrapper for the gettext library, which can interface with posix applications.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>An Important Update on Haiku Code Drive 2009</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2009-05-26_important_update_haiku_code_drive_2009/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2009 17:29:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2009-05-26_important_update_haiku_code_drive_2009/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="field field-type-text field-field-body">
&lt;div class="field-items">
&lt;div class="field-item odd">
&lt;p>In the past few days, there has been two important developments regarding our participating students.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tom Fairfield has resigned from this year's Haiku Code Drive. Recently, he was accepted for a Research Experience for Undergraduate (REU) program. This is a significant and important opportunity for him, especially since Tom is pursuing a continuing education in graduate school. However, the REU conflicts with the Haiku Code Drive timeline. As such, he decided to formally withdraw from HCD. To quote him: "I still plan on contributing code to Haiku - it's an awesome project but I must put it on hold for now. Thanks again for the opportunity though." We at Haiku wish you all the luck with your Research Experience for Undergraduate program and we are confident that you will succeed!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>It's Official! Haiku Code Drive 2009!</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2009-05-15_its_official_haiku_code_drive_2009/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2009 16:49:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2009-05-15_its_official_haiku_code_drive_2009/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="field field-type-text field-field-body">
&lt;div class="field-items">
&lt;div class="field-item odd">
&lt;p>This year for Haiku Code Drive, the student selection process has been completely overhauled. Unlike last year, where a public vote was held to select the students, our mentors have determined the combinations of &amp;lt;student&amp;gt;-&amp;lt;project&amp;gt;-&amp;lt;mentor&amp;gt;. Since our requirements for &lt;i>Google Summer of Code&lt;/i> were greatly improved upon from last year, our mentors were able to confidently decide which of those combinations have the highest chance of succeeding. &lt;/p>
&lt;h3 class="icon-ide-project-medium">Full-text indexing and search tool for Haiku&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li class="icon-person">Student: Ankur Sethi&lt;/li>
&lt;li class="icon-person">Mentor: Rene Gollent&lt;/li>
&lt;li class="icon-document">Project Abstract
&lt;/p>A plugin-based, full-text file indexing tool for Haiku, similar in functionality to OSX's Spotlight, GNOME's Tracker and SkyOS's Index Feeder. The main goal of the project is to make important documents and applications easily accessible and to reduce mouse usage.
&lt;/p>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 class="icon-ide-project-medium">Services Kit&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li class="icon-person">Student: Tom Fairfield&lt;/li>
&lt;li class="icon-person">Mentor: Pier Luigi Fiorini&lt;/li>
&lt;li class="icon-document">Project Abstract
&lt;p>The Services Kit will be a set of APIs that applications can use to communicate with various web services such as Facebook, Twitter, and Last.fm
&lt;/p>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Interviews : Google Summer of Code Applicants</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2009-05-04_interviews_google_summer_code_applicants/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2009 14:27:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2009-05-04_interviews_google_summer_code_applicants/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="field field-type-text field-field-body">
&lt;div class="field-items">
&lt;div class="field-item odd">
&lt;p>
In celebration and recognition of the hard work put in by all of this year's &lt;i>Google Summer of Code&lt;/i> applicants, several of Haiku's news sites have coordinated with each other to provide those students with an opportunity to be interviewed. These interviews will be covered by &lt;a href="http://www.beosnews.com/">BeOSNews&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="http://begroovy.com/">BeGroovy&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="http://www.haiku-gazette.de/">Haiku Gazette&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="http://www.haikuware.com/">Haikuware&lt;/a>, and &lt;a href="http://joomla.iscomputeron.com/">IsComputerOn&lt;/a>, and will be spread out over the following two weeks.
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Update: All of the received interviews have now been posted! I would like to congratulate and thank all of the participating newsites on this extensive collaboration effort. If any additional translations become available, feel free to &lt;a href="../user/331/contact">Contact Me&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Update: IsComputerOn has conducted another interview with Alexey Burshtein&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Google Allocates Six Students for Haiku in Summer of Code 2009!</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2009-04-17_google_allocates_six_students_haiku_summer_code_2009/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Apr 2009 00:26:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2009-04-17_google_allocates_six_students_haiku_summer_code_2009/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="field field-type-text field-field-body">
&lt;div class="field-items">
&lt;div class="field-item odd">
&lt;p>We are pleased to announce that Google has allotted us with six students for this year's Summer of Code program! This is quite an achievement, seeing as how Google accepted only 1000 students, which is about 10% less than in 2008. As with the year before, the quality of the proposals submitted by students has increased significantly. This year, students who applied to Haiku were suggested to fix an issue in our &lt;a href="http://dev.haiku-os.org">bug tracker&lt;/a>. This provided our mentors with a glimpse into the students' programming ability, as well as their ambition. Those contributions, several of which have already been committed to our SVN repository, proved to be a valuable resource when ranking the students. This allowed our mentors to strike a balance between projects that fill a need in Haiku and projects by students who have also shown themselves to be a worthy &lt;i>Google Summer of Code&lt;/i> student. These students went above and beyond our requirements and expectations. They gave us hope that come October, November, and beyond, they will still be making contributions to our community. Since retaining students as community developers is one of the goals of Summer of Code, it weighed heavily in our decision. Without further ado, here is the list of students who will be sponsored by Google to contribute to Haiku in &lt;i>Google's Summer of Code 2009&lt;/i>:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Haiku makes it into Google Summer of Code for third year in a row</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2009-03-18_haiku_makes_it_google_summer_code_third_year_row/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2009 23:59:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2009-03-18_haiku_makes_it_google_summer_code_third_year_row/</guid><description>Haiku GSoC 2009 flier (pdf &amp; hi res PNG) Haiku's application for Google Summer of Code 2009&amp;trade; has been accepted!
This year, the role of Haiku's Google Summer of Code primary administrator has been taken up by Matt Madia, with Stephan Aßmus acting as the backup administrator. Over the past few days, Google program administrators evaluated a total of 395 Mentoring organization applications and published their list of those accepted on Wednesday, March 18th 19:00 UTC.</description></item><item><title>Haiku presence at Chemnitzer Linux-Tage</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2009-03-07_haiku_presence_chemnitzer_linuxtage/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Mar 2009 08:43:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2009-03-07_haiku_presence_chemnitzer_linuxtage/</guid><description>If you happen to be visiting the Chemnitzer Linux-Tage conference on March 14-15, 2009, make sure to stop by the Haiku booth and say "Hi!". Attending this year on behalf of Haiku will be Stephan Aßmus, Axel Dörfler, Denise Wein and Daniel Wünsch.
The Haiku booth is next to the one of the Fedora Linux project, together with many other open source operating systems like FreeBSD, Ubuntu, openSUSE, NetBSD, OpenBSD, etc.</description></item><item><title>Website Upgraded to Drupal 5</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2009-02-25_website_upgraded_drupal_5/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2009 19:49:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2009-02-25_website_upgraded_drupal_5/</guid><description>This Saturday, the 28th of February, the software that powers the website, Drupal and 47 (!) modules, have been upgraded to the Drupal 5 platform. This upgrade creates the foundation to continue to improve the functionality and information on our website, as the demands change, also in the face of the upcoming Alpha 1 release.
While the upgrade team has concluded that most of the data migrated smoothly, there are some rough edges.</description></item><item><title>Haiku Finally Gets a Native GCC4 - full story inside!</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2009-01-31_haiku_finally_gets_a_native_gcc4_full_story_inside/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2009 04:25:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2009-01-31_haiku_finally_gets_a_native_gcc4_full_story_inside/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="field field-type-text field-field-body">
&lt;div class="field-items">
&lt;div class="field-item odd">
&lt;span class="inline right">&lt;a href="../files/screenshots/stressing_it.png" rel="lightbox">&lt;img src="http://www.haiku-os.org/files/screenshots/stressing_it.thumbnail.png" alt="Michael's Quad-core compiling GCC4.3.3" title="Michael's Quad-core compiling GCC4.3.3" class="image thumbnail" width="200" height="160">&lt;/a>&lt;span class="caption" style="width: 198px;">&lt;strong>Michael's Quad-core compiling GCC4.3.3&lt;/strong>&lt;/span>&lt;/span>
&lt;p>As many Haiku community members know, one major hurdle that has been making it difficult to port new software to Haiku has been the lack of an up-to-date GCC4 compiler. While a GCC 4.1.2 cross-compiler has been available now for some time, cross-compiling software for a GCC4-built Haiku can be painful and frustrating. What Haiku really needed was a native GCC4 toolchain to run on a GCC4-built Haiku install.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>That time is now! A native Haiku GCC4.3.3 is now a reality.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Michael Lotz set out to tackle this task and the fruits of his labor have finally been committed to the Haiku repository for all to benefit from.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Happy Holidays from Haiku!</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2008-12-25_happy_holidays_from_haiku/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2008 21:18:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2008-12-25_happy_holidays_from_haiku/</guid><description>On behalf of Haiku, we'd like to wish everyone Happy Holidays!
While the news may seem a little slow lately (people are likely busy during the holiday season), there has indeed been a few things happening of note.
One exciting announcement was from Christof Lutteroth letting us know that some final-year projects from the University of Auckland were prototyped using Haiku. While these prototypes and the code behind them are not yet publicly available, they have generously offered to donate this code to Haiku in the future.</description></item><item><title>Mailing list change</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2008-10-22_mailing_list_change/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2008 14:42:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2008-10-22_mailing_list_change/</guid><description>At the end of the month, the main user mailing list &amp;#111;&amp;#112;&amp;#101;&amp;#110;&amp;#98;&amp;#101;&amp;#111;&amp;#115;&amp;#64;&amp;#102;&amp;#114;&amp;#101;&amp;#101;&amp;#108;&amp;#105;&amp;#115;&amp;#116;&amp;#115;&amp;#46;&amp;#111;&amp;#114;&amp;#103; will finally be renamed to &amp;#104;&amp;#97;&amp;#105;&amp;#107;&amp;#117;&amp;#64;&amp;#102;&amp;#114;&amp;#101;&amp;#101;&amp;#108;&amp;#105;&amp;#115;&amp;#116;&amp;#115;&amp;#46;&amp;#111;&amp;#114;&amp;#103;, removing the most apparent reference to our previous name, OpenBeOS, that our project had until summer of 2004. The old archive will remain accessible, and all subscribers will be moved to the new list automatically. We'll even send you a reminder when it's done, so that you'll remember to send future mails to &amp;#104;&amp;#97;&amp;#105;&amp;#107;&amp;#117;&amp;#64;&amp;#102;&amp;#114;&amp;#101;&amp;#101;&amp;#108;&amp;#105;&amp;#115;&amp;#116;&amp;#115;&amp;#46;&amp;#111;&amp;#114;&amp;#103; instead.</description></item><item><title>Impression from BeGeistert 019</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2008-10-17_impression_begeistert_019/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2008 08:36:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2008-10-17_impression_begeistert_019/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Stephan Aßmus asked me if I'd like to translate my article on BeGeistert 019
&lt;a href="https://haiku-gazette.blogspot.com/2008/10/das-war-begeistert-019.html">https://haiku-gazette.blogspot.com/2008/10/das-war-begeistert-019.html&lt;/a> to English. How could I refuse? :) Here it is:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BeGeistert 019 was held last weekend in Düsseldorf and was, as far as I can tell, a great success. I've been to BeGeistert twice in the past (I think 2002 and 2003) and in my opinion the spirit of BeGeistert hasn't changed since then. Maybe there used to be some more non-coders among the guests and the focus was more on applications; that was of course because Haiku was still in its OpenBeOS nappies at that time...&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Google Summer of Code 2008 and Haiku Code Drive harvest</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2008-10-07_google_summer_of_code_2008_and_haiku_code_drive_harvest/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2008 09:18:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2008-10-07_google_summer_of_code_2008_and_haiku_code_drive_harvest/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="field field-type-text field-field-body">
&lt;div class="field-items">
&lt;div class="field-item odd">
&lt;p>We're very glad that Haiku has been part of Google's Summer of Code this year again. We were granted five student projects to improve Haiku. But since we had so many good and worthwhile project proposals, we set out to start our very own Haiku Code Drive. We asked for your help in the form of donations, and we were absolutely overwhelmed by the response we got from you, our community: we were able to sponsor 4 more student projects to work on Haiku.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yes, of course, you know all of that already. The reason for this review is that, since both coding events are officially over by now, I wanted to give you an overview of what has happened, and how the students fared. Not all projects have been success stories, but we were lucky to have found some very talented students this year. We're glad we had you!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>BeGeistert 019 - Alphaville registration open</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2008-09-14_begeistert_019_alphaville_registration_open/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2008 12:43:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2008-09-14_begeistert_019_alphaville_registration_open/</guid><description>After the date has been known for some time, Charlie Clark in the name of BeFAN and the BeGeistert orga team is now officially inviting to BeGeistert 019 from October 11. - 12. 2008 in the youth hostel Düsseldorf. Reservations are now open and should be made as soon as possible. To learn more about BeGeistert, see the BeGeistert website. It includes more info on directions, car pooling and costs.</description></item><item><title>Haiku Grows Swap Support</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2008-08-29_haiku_grows_swap_support/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2008 15:34:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2008-08-29_haiku_grows_swap_support/</guid><description>Thanks to Google Summer of Code student Zhao Shuai successfully finishing his project Haiku does now feature support for swapping. As of revision 27233 it is enabled by default, using a swap file twice the size of the accessible RAM. The swap file size can be changed (or swap support disabled) via the VirtualMemory preferences.
Swap support finally allows building Haiku in Haiku on a box with less than about 800 MB RAM, as long as as the swap file is large enough.</description></item><item><title>Haiku to Exhibit at LinuxWorld 2008 in San Francisco</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2008-07-14_haiku_to_exhibit_at_linuxworld_2008/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2008 00:20:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2008-07-14_haiku_to_exhibit_at_linuxworld_2008/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="field field-type-text field-field-body">
&lt;div class="field-items">
&lt;div class="field-item odd">
&lt;p>&lt;span class="inline right">&lt;a href="../files/downloads/2008-07-17_haiku_lw08-free-pass.pdf">&lt;img src="http://www.haiku-os.org/files/screenshots/2008-07-17_lw08-free-pass.thumbnail.png" alt="LinuxWorld Expo 2008 Free Pass (PDF)" title="LinuxWorld Expo 2008 Free Pass (850KB PDF)" class="image thumbnail" width="156" height="200">&lt;/a>&lt;span class="caption" style="width: 154px;">&lt;strong>LinuxWorld Expo 2008 Free Pass (850KB PDF)&lt;/strong>&lt;/span>&lt;/span>In February of 2007 Haiku exhibited at SCaLE 05, making its first appearance ever at an open source conference. Since then, Haiku has made appearances in &lt;a href="../conference/">many open source events worldwide&lt;/a>. One big event that we have been targeting since last year was the LinuxWorld Expo; unfortunately, both this and last year we were unable to get a spot in the .Org pavilion. Fortunately, that's about to change. After some perseverance, creative thinking and thanks the good will of &lt;a href="http://www.idgworldexpo.com/live/wec/">IDG World Expo&lt;/a> (the organizers of LinuxWorld) and the &lt;a href="http://www.reactos.org">ReactOS&lt;/a> project (with whom we will be sharing the booth), we are excited to announce that we were able to obtain an exhibit spot at the &lt;a href="http://www.linuxworldexpo.com/live/12/">LinuxWorld Expo 2008&lt;/a> to be held next month in the &lt;a href="http://www.moscone.com">San Francisco Moscone Center&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We have secured a full-sized 10x10 spot (booth #1617), where we plan to showcase Haiku for the full duration of the expo, that is, August 5, 6 and 7. Our plan is to demo Haiku on two or more PCs, one of them hooked up to a projector which will display its image on a screen hanging from the booth backwall (&lt;a href="http://picasaweb.google.com/haiku.inc/SCaLE6x/photo#5166963800208274690">like here&lt;/a>). We will also hand out fliers and possibly a CD with a VMWare image, and sell Haiku t-shirts (if allowed) to raise funds for the project.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Notice: Scheduled Maintenance for dev.haiku-os.org</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2008-06-11_notice_scheduled_maintenance_for_dev_haiku_os_org/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2008 19:00:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2008-06-11_notice_scheduled_maintenance_for_dev_haiku_os_org/</guid><description>On Monday the 16th of June, from 09:00 GMT onwards, dev.haiku-os.org will be down for a server move and software upgrade. The website team has chosen to combine these two operations in order to minimize downtime. The operation is expected to take about three hours. Live progress updates will be offered on the#haiku channel on freenode. The service will be moved to hosting that has been offered by Scott Palmer from Unixheads.</description></item><item><title>Notice: user account changes on dev.haiku-os.org</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2008-06-02_notice/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2008 13:23:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2008-06-02_notice/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="field field-type-text field-field-body">
&lt;div class="field-items">
&lt;div class="field-item odd">
&lt;p>&lt;em>Update:&lt;/em> as of now this change is in effect. If you are encountering any problems, read on to learn how to get help.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The &lt;a href="http://www.haiku-os.org/about/teams/website">website team&lt;/a> is constantly trying to improve the user experience of the various websites we maintain. In order to improve our existing infrastructure, we are currently preparing a move to a new server infrastructure, which is offered by the &lt;a href="http://www.isc.org/">Internet Systems Consortium&lt;/a>. ISC is a non-profit that, amongst many &lt;a href="http://www.isc.org/index.pl?/profsvcs/">other things,&lt;/a> hosts &lt;a href="http://www.kernel.org/">kernel.org&lt;/a>. We are more than grateful for this offer, which will improve our responsiveness, especially during exposure on &lt;a href="http://slashdot.org/">Slashdot&lt;/a> or &lt;a href="http://www.osnews.com/">OSNews&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This transition means that we have to redesign several aspects of the server infrastructure. One of these things is the user account handling. Because of the interactive nature of the main website and the bug tracker, much of the functionality is tied to user accounts. Up to now we have been able to use the user database of the main website to authenticate users against &lt;a href="http://dev.haiku-os.org/">dev.haiku-os.org&lt;/a>. However, in the new environment, we have to break this connection, until a better solution is implemented.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On Monday the 9th of June, users of &lt;span class="geshifilter">&lt;code class="cpp geshifilter-cpp">dev.&lt;span style="color: #007788;">haiku&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color: #000040;">-&lt;/span>os.&lt;span style="color: #007788;">org&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/span> will no longer be able to log in with the account they created on the main &lt;a href="http://www.haiku-os.org">website.&lt;/a> If you have ever logged in on dev.haiku-os.org, you will be affected by this change. You will receive an email with a new (randomly generated) password, which you will be able to change to your liking.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Read on for a short list of questions and answers.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Haiku Code Drive 2008 to Sponsor Four Students</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2008-05-30_haiku_code_drive_2008_to_sponsor_four_students/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2008 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2008-05-30_haiku_code_drive_2008_to_sponsor_four_students/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="field field-type-text field-field-body">
&lt;div class="field-items">
&lt;div class="field-item odd">
&lt;p>It's official! Thanks to the incredible generosity of our community, and with a little help from Google, the Haiku Code Drive 2008 will sponsor four students, bringing the number of students that will be coding for Haiku this summer to nine. This is one more student than last year's eight sponsored by the GSoC alone! Shown below are the four selected students and their projects, in the order that the community ranked them through the &lt;a href="../poll/2008-08-22/haiku_code_drive_2008_poll">Haiku Code Drive poll&lt;/a>:&lt;/p>
&lt;a name="bfs">&lt;/a>
&lt;p class="icon-person-medium">&lt;strong>Salvatore Benedetto:&lt;/strong> &lt;a href="../community/haiku-code-drive-2008/projects#bfs">BFS stress-testing, UDF port to new FS Haiku API&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;a name="cups">&lt;/a>
&lt;p class="icon-person-medium">&lt;strong>Jovan Ivankovic:&lt;/strong> &lt;a href="../community/haiku-code-drive-2008/projects#cups">CUPS port&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;a name="icmp">&lt;/a>
&lt;p class="icon-person-medium">&lt;strong>Yin Qiu:&lt;/strong> &lt;a href="../community/haiku-code-drive-2008/projects#icmp">ICMP error handling and propagation&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;a name="dv">&lt;/a>
&lt;p class="icon-person-medium">&lt;strong>JiSheng Zhang:&lt;/strong> &lt;a href="../community/haiku-code-drive-2008/projects#dv">DV media node&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The response from the community to our call for donations to fund this program was incredible. In just two weeks, we received 120 donations from 24 countries (Australia, Austria, Belgium, Brazil, Canada, Czech Republic, Denmark, Finland, France, Germany, Hungary, Indonesia, Ireland, Italy, Lithuania, Netherlands, New Zealand, Poland, Russia, Slovakia, Sweden, Switzerland, the United Kingdom and USA), for a total of approximately $7,500. The promptness, degree of generosity, and global reach of the response by the community to the Haiku Code Drive is unprecedented in the history of our project, and hopefully a sign of things to come in the future.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Haiku Code Drive 2008 Poll &amp; Fundraiser Update</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2008-05-22_haiku_code_drive_2008_poll_fundraiser_update/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2008 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2008-05-22_haiku_code_drive_2008_poll_fundraiser_update/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="field field-type-text field-field-body">
&lt;div class="field-items">
&lt;div class="field-item odd">
&lt;p>It's been one week since we kicked off the &lt;a href="../community/haiku-code-drive-2008">Haiku Code Drive 2008&lt;/a> program, and the response so far has been absolutely awesome: in just seven days the community has contributed more than US$5,000 to fund the program, and the donations keep coming in! This is happening thanks to the generosity of the community, and now you have the opportunity to influence where you want the funds that you donated to go:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The &lt;strong>&lt;a href="../poll/2008-08-22/haiku_code_drive_2008_poll">Haiku Code Drive 2008 Poll&lt;/a>&lt;/strong> has started and will run until May 29, 11:59 (US PST), so go cast your vote now! You will need to login, so if you don't have an account with the Haiku website, this is a good time to &lt;a href="../user/register">create one from here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Introducing the Evanston Haiku User Group (eHUG)</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2008-05-07_introducing_the_evanston_ehug/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2008 19:19:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2008-05-07_introducing_the_evanston_ehug/</guid><description>I am pleased to announce that a new Haiku User Group is being started in Chicago. The Evanston Haiku User Group (eHUG) is the second user group in the US focused on Haiku, and we have a temporary website at ehug.wordpress.com. We are very similar to other user groups already in existence, but one of the differences between the eHUG and other HUGs is the fact that one of our primary goals is to design and build a computer specifically for Haiku.</description></item><item><title>Steady Progress towards Alpha 1</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2008-05-18_steady_progress_towards_alpha_1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 May 2008 11:27:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2008-05-18_steady_progress_towards_alpha_1/</guid><description>This weekend, the Haiku project has seen some nice leaps forward. Two items are especially noteworthy: Ingo Weinhold and Axel Dörfler have finally nailed bug 2059. This bug specifically prevented serious use of Haiku for anything else than testing, since it meant that the kernel could crash at any time, especially when there was heavy disk activity. All that was supposed to be written to disk at the time of the crash was lost.</description></item><item><title>Call to Arms: Haiku Code Drive 2008</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2008-04-28_call_to_arms_haiku_code_drive_2008/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2008 19:27:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2008-04-28_call_to_arms_haiku_code_drive_2008/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="field field-type-text field-field-body">
&lt;div class="field-items">
&lt;div class="field-item odd">
&lt;img src="../themes/shijin/icons/people_64.png" align="right" border="0" hspace="20" vspace="5" alt="The Haiku Community" title="The Haiku Community" height="64" width="64">&lt;p>&lt;a href="../news/2008-04-21/haiku_gets_five_students_spots_for_gsoc_2008">Google assigned Haiku five student slots&lt;/a> for the Google Summer of Code 2008, so we had to narrow down our final choice from the many high quality student applications. This was tough: many good applications had to be left out, and we really hate leaving people out, particularly those who had shown an interest in Haiku. So we started entertaining the idea of sponsoring a few of these students ourselves. Today we introduce you to the Haiku Code Drive 2008, a program designed to raise funds from the community in order to sponsor students to produce code for Haiku. This is how it's going to work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We contacted all the GSoC students that applied for Haiku but did not make it, and asked them if they were interested in carrying out their proposed project for a $2,500 stipend each. From their response, we have created this &lt;a href="../community/haiku-code-drive-2008/applications">list of students and their projects&lt;/a>; these are the candidates for the Haiku Code Drive 2008 program. Now we are asking you, the Haiku community, to fund the program by making donations. We will then hold a public poll so that the community can influence which candidates/projects they want to sponsor. At the end of the poll/donation period, we will determine how many and which of the students will be sponsored based on the donated funds and the results of the poll. Check out all the &lt;a href="../community/haiku-code-drive-2008#calendar">details of the program&lt;/a> here, including a &lt;a href="../community/haiku-code-drive-2008#calendar">timeline with tentative dates&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Teldar's BeServed Open Sourced, Code Merged into Haiku Repository</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2008-04-25_teldars_beserved_open_sourced_code_merged_into_haiku_repo/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2008 10:33:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2008-04-25_teldars_beserved_open_sourced_code_merged_into_haiku_repo/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="field field-type-text field-field-body">
&lt;div class="field-items">
&lt;div class="field-item odd">
&lt;span class="inline right">&lt;a href="http://www.teldar.com">&lt;img src="http://www.haiku-os.org/files/screenshots/2008-04-25_TeldarLogo.gif" alt="" title="" class="image img_assist_custom" width="448" height="150">&lt;/a>&lt;/span>&lt;p>As recently noted by Haiku developer Axel Dörfler on &lt;a href="http://www.freelists.org/archives/haiku-development/04-2008/msg00665.html">the development mailing list&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="">Teldar Corporation&lt;/a> has open sourced their BeServed network file sharing solution for BeOS and donated the code to Haiku. We are now pleased to announce that the donated code has been merged into the Haiku repository, and &lt;a href="http://svn.berlios.de/viewcvs/haiku/haiku/trunk/src/tests/add-ons/kernel/file_systems/beserved/">is available here&lt;/a>. The package, donated to Haiku under the MIT license, contains user management and servers for several operating systems including, Microsoft Windows® and Linux®. While Haiku already has a native networking file system that has been in the works by Ingo Weinhold, the availability of the BeServed code will allow cross-pollination between the two code bases, eventually resulting in а powerful and solid native networking solution for Haiku.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kevin Musick of Teldar Corporation had these words for us: "I am pleased to donate BeServed in its entirety to the Haiku project. After Be, Inc.'s demise, BeServed was no longer commercially viable and the pressures of my career and a young family forced me to pursue other opportunities. However, I am encouraged to see Haiku's progress and the ongoing commitment of the community. While I no longer have the bandwidth to participate in the project, I hope that BeServed will be useful in some small way. Congratulations on your progress and best wishes for continued success!"&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Haiku Gets Five Student Slots for GSoC 2008</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2008-04-21_haiku_gets_five_students_spots_for_gsoc_2008/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2008 20:42:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2008-04-21_haiku_gets_five_students_spots_for_gsoc_2008/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="field field-type-text field-field-body">
&lt;div class="field-items">
&lt;div class="field-item odd">
&lt;p>After a quite intensive and challenging review and selection process, we are pleased to announce that Haiku has been assigned &lt;a href="http://code.google.com/soc/2008/haiku/about.html">five (5) student slots for the Google Summer of Code 2008&lt;/a>. This year, Google accepted many more mentor organizations than ever before, which made the allotment of students slots a lot more competitive. We also received applications of very high quality, which is definitely a blessing, but also made the Haiku mentor's task of narrowing down to a final selection much tougher. After thorough review of all the applications, and carefully taking into consideration factors such as immediate benefits for our project, the likelihood of getting long-term contributors, and the availability of an appropriate mentor for any given project, we have come up with the final list of students that will be coding for Haiku during the GSoC 2008 program. Here it is:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Haiku takes over Google, SoC renamed</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2008-04-01_haiku_takes_over_google_soc_renamed/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2008 13:17:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2008-04-01_haiku_takes_over_google_soc_renamed/</guid><description>With the help of a generous donator, Haiku, Inc. has acquired a major share of Google, Inc. and is now in the process of reorganizing Google for a major focus shift that will allow for wide distribution of Haiku R1 to OEMs. Distribution contracts have been signed with major mobile phone makers for an unprecedented availability of Phone and Handheld Integrated System Haiku (PHISH).
Also, as of this year, the Summer Of Code project is now officially renamed Summer of Assembler Poetry (SoAP).</description></item><item><title>3ivx 5.02 Brings MPEG-4 ASP Video Support to Haiku</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2008-03-26_3ivx_5_02_brings_mpeg_4_asp_video_support_to_haiku/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2008 00:50:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2008-03-26_3ivx_5_02_brings_mpeg_4_asp_video_support_to_haiku/</guid><description>David McPaul, on behalf of 3ivx Technologies Pty. Ltd, has just announced on the Haiku mailing list the release of the latest version (5.02) of the 3ivx MPEG-4 ASP video decoder and encoder for the BeOS R5 platform, including an experimental 3ivx decoder for Haiku. Available on the 3ivx website, this release includes many bug fixes, frame accurate seeking, experimental support for mp4 files and aac audio, and a Haiku version of the 3ivx decoder.</description></item><item><title>BeBook and Be Newsletters Available Online</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2008-03-21_bebook_and_be_newsletters_available_online/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2008 03:53:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2008-03-21_bebook_and_be_newsletters_available_online/</guid><description>It's been almost one year since we announced our conversations with ACCESS Co. Ltd. targeted at releasing legacy BeOS related documents, and today we are happy to inform the community that this project has finally arrived to a happy conclusion: the BeBook and all the Be Newsletters are now available online. As an emerging open source project, documentation for Haiku is still hard to come by; and while our Documentation Team works on creating Haiku-specific material, the BeBook and the Be Newsletters will provide valuable reference material for all developers, new and experienced alike.</description></item><item><title>Haiku Makes it Into Google Summer of Code 2008</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2008-03-17_haiku_makes_it_into_google_summer_of_code_2008/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2008 19:09:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2008-03-17_haiku_makes_it_into_google_summer_of_code_2008/</guid><description>We are very pleased to announce that, for the second straight year, Haiku has been accepted as a mentor organization for the Google Summer of Code. The student application period will start soon, so if you are a student who would like to work on a Haiku project for the GSoC 2008, please check out our List of GSoC Ideas and Students: How to Apply pages for detailed information on how to apply.</description></item><item><title>Haiku to Exhibit at First LugRadio Live USA</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2008-03-03_haiku_to_exhibit_at_first_lugradio_live_usa_2008/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2008 03:39:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2008-03-03_haiku_to_exhibit_at_first_lugradio_live_usa_2008/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="field field-type-text field-field-body">
&lt;div class="field-items">
&lt;div class="field-item odd">
&lt;p>&lt;span class="inline right">&lt;img src="http://www.haiku-os.org/files/screenshots/lugradio.thumbnail.png" alt="Haiku to exhibit at LugRadio Live USA 2008 at the Metreon, San Francisco" title="Haiku to exhibit at LugRadio Live USA 2008 at the Metreon, San Francisco" class="image thumbnail" height="200" width="158">&lt;/span>The good news following our recent presence at the &lt;a href="http://www.socallinuxexpo.org/scale6x/" target="_blank">SCaLE conference&lt;/a> and the great exposure that it resulted in continues to pour in. Haiku has now been invited to have a booth at the &lt;a href="http://lugradio.org/live/USA2008/" target="_blank">LugRadio Live USA 2008&lt;/a>, the first LugRadio live event to be held in the US. Needless to say, we could not refuse the irresistible offer. The event will take place in San Francisco on the weekend of April 12 and 13, at the &lt;a href="http://westfield.com/metreon/" target="_blank">The Metreon&lt;/a> entertainment center located at the heart of the city (&lt;a href="http://maps.google.com/maps?f=q&amp;hl=en&amp;geocode=&amp;q=101+4th+Street,+San+Francisco,+CA&amp;sll=37.785131,-122.404389&amp;sspn=0.007953,0.014849&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;ll=37.786148,-122.404282&amp;spn=0.007953,0.014849&amp;z=16&amp;iwloc=addr" target="_blank">map&lt;/a>).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>LugRadio is an event that covers a range of topics about free software, Open Source, digital rights, technology and more. Combined with a compelling list of speakers, exhibitors and birds of a feather sessions, this event is said to offer what feels like a combination of a rock concert and a computer conference. To bring this unique atmosphere to San Francisco, LugRadio Live USA 2008 USA will have around &lt;a href="http://lugradio.org/live/USA2008/speakers" target="_blank">30 speakers&lt;/a> including Miguel de Icaza and Ian Murdock, &lt;a href="http://lugradio.org/live/USA2008/exhibition" target="_blank">over 20 exhibitors&lt;/a>, an eclectic range of BOF and other sessions, and the live recording of LugRadio in front of an audience.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Haiku Inc. Transition Update</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2008-02-04_haiku_inc_transition_update/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2008 10:06:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2008-02-04_haiku_inc_transition_update/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="field field-type-text field-field-body">
&lt;div class="field-items">
&lt;div class="field-item odd">
&lt;p>It has been several months since we announced the departure of project founder Michael Phipps from Haiku and the transition period that ensued for Haiku Inc. This is an attempt to give the community a most probably long awaited update on where we stand today, what has been done so far and what remains to be done to bring the Haiku Inc. transition to a successful conclusion.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3>Who we are&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>First, let's try to put a face to the transition team, so that you know who is behind all this. Under the initiative of Stephan (Stippi) Aßmus, a "transition team" was setup with the main goal of
reorganizing Haiku Inc.. To that end, an interim board of directors (BOD) endorsed by the Haiku admins is being put in place; this BOD is only transitional and will eventually be replaced by one elected with votes from a broader representation base. The interim BOD has not been formally sworn in yet, but it is scheduled to include the following individuals:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Developer interviews in Deutschlandradio Kultur</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2008-02-01_developer_interviews_in_deutschlandradio_kultur/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2008 15:35:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2008-02-01_developer_interviews_in_deutschlandradio_kultur/</guid><description> Gerrit Stratmann has just informed me that the interviews he did with Axel Dörfler, Ingo Weinhold, Michael Lotz and myself during BeGeistert 018 will appear tomorrow, February 2nd 2008 in Deutschlandradio Kultur between 14:00 and 15:00 CET. A downloadable version will later be made available on the website of the series at www.breitband-online.de.</description></item><item><title>Haiku Recognition Award for Project Founder Michael Phipps</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2008-01-23_haiku_recognition_award_for_parting_project_founder/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2008 00:14:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2008-01-23_haiku_recognition_award_for_parting_project_founder/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="field field-type-text field-field-body">
&lt;div class="field-items">
&lt;div class="field-item odd">
&lt;p>&lt;span class="inline right">&lt;img src="http://haiku-os.org/files/screenshots/2008-01-23_mphipps-farewell-video.png" alt="Farewell video for Michael Phipps" title="Farewell video for Michael Phipps" class="image img_assist_custom" height="245" width="300">&lt;span class="caption" style="width: 298px;">&lt;strong>Farewell video:&lt;/strong> &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pareAq4BmDM" target="_blank">YouTube&lt;/a> | &lt;a href="http://www.archive.org/details/HaikuRecognitionAwardForProjectFounderMichaelPhipps" target="_blank">Download&lt;/a>&lt;/span>&lt;/span>
Project founder, long time leader and Haiku visionary Michael Phipps departed from the project last year. Michael's list of achievements is long: he did not just provide an overall vision for Haiku, but he also set up &lt;a href="../about/haiku_inc">Haiku Inc.&lt;/a>, and over the years put in countless hours of work, keeping the development effort on track whenever it seemed to drift away from the goals, and single-handedly managing the infrastructure supporting the project. Without Michael, Haiku would most probably not be what it has become today.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Michael gave his goodbye in a &lt;a href="http://haiku-os.org/blog/mphipps/2007-09-18/what_a_long_strange_trip_its_been">moving letter to the Haiku community&lt;/a> but, somehow, it feels as if we never reciprocated with a proper farewell. So we decided to do something special to show our heartfelt appreciation. We are thereby presenting Michael Phipps with the first ever &lt;a href="../files/screenshots/2008-01-24_mphipps_award.thumbnail.jpg" onclick="launch_popup(2012, 800, 572); return false;" target="_blank">Haiku Recognition Award&lt;/a>. This is a very special award with a personal touch, as it has been signed by members of the community present at the recent BeGeistert 018 conference held in Düsseldorf, Germany, and is also accompanied by a &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=pareAq4BmDM" target="_blank">farewell video&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>OpenJDK Porters Group Votes to Sponsor Java Port to Haiku</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2008-01-21_openjdk_porters_group_votes_to_sponsor_java_port_to_haiku/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2008 17:38:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2008-01-21_openjdk_porters_group_votes_to_sponsor_java_port_to_haiku/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="field field-type-text field-field-body">
&lt;div class="field-items">
&lt;div class="field-item odd">
&lt;p>&lt;span class="inline right">&lt;img src="../files/screenshots/logo_haiku-openjdk.png" alt="OpenJDK Porters Group Votes to Sponsor Java Port to Haiku" title="OpenJDK Porters Group Votes to Sponsor Java Port to Haiku" class="image img_assist_custom" height="124" width="250">&lt;/span>We are pleased to announce that the proposal submitted by the &lt;a href="http://haiku-os.org/news/2008-01-03/new_java_for_haiku_team_formed">recently formed Haiku Java Team&lt;/a> to the &lt;a href="http://openjdk.java.net">OpenJDK Porters Group&lt;/a> has been accepted by a unanimous vote. This makes Haiku the first OS platform to be sponsored by the Porters Group, and it means that the port is now officially part of the OpenJDK family of projects endorsed by Sun. Referring to the Haiku Java Team proposal, OpenJDK Ambassador for Sun Microsystems Tom Marble said: "I believe that encouraging broad adoption of OpenJDK on as many operating systems and architectures as possible is essential to furthering our goals of Java ubiquity. I'm glad to support this project."&lt;p></description></item><item><title>New Year, New Tool to Empower the Haiku Community</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2008-01-08_new_year_new_tool_to_empower_the_haiku_community/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2008 01:31:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2008-01-08_new_year_new_tool_to_empower_the_haiku_community/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="field field-type-text field-field-body">
&lt;div class="field-items">
&lt;div class="field-item odd">
&lt;p>&lt;span class="inline right">&lt;img src="http://haiku-os.org/files/screenshots/logo_oss-conf-2007.png" alt="" title="" class="image img_assist_custom" height="220" width="257">&lt;/span>&lt;a href="http://www.socallinuxexpo.org/scale5x/">SCaLE 5x&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="http://haiku-os.org/index.php?q=gallery&amp;g2_itemId=1288">Haiku Tech Talks at Google&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="http://www.linuxpicnic.org/twiki/bin/view/Picnix16/">Picn*x XVI&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="http://haiku-os.org/news/2007-05-01/haiku_at_open_source_conference_in_venezuela">CNSL 3&lt;/a> in Venezuela, &lt;a href="http://haiku-os.org/news/2007-04-07/haiku_lecture_at_fisl_8_0_foss_conference_in_brazil">FISL 8.0&lt;/a> in Brazil, &lt;a href="http://haiku-os.org/news/2007-03-06/haiku_to_be_presented_at_numerica">NUMERICA&lt;/a> in France, &lt;a href="http://www.t-dose.org">T-DOSE&lt;/a> in the Netherlands, &lt;a href="http://k-of.jp/2007/kof.html">Kansai Open Source Forum&lt;/a> in Japan. The list of 2007 events where Haiku had a presence is very long. In fact, never in the past has Haiku had so much public exposure as it did during 2007. And as the project keeps making progress towards its first release, this trend of increased exposure before the eyes of the open source and computing world in general is expected — and desired — to continue. In the first two months of 2008 alone, Haiku will be at &lt;a href="http://begeistert.org">BeGeistert 018&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="http://www.socallinuxexpo.org/scale6x/">SCaLE 6x&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="http://www.fosdem.org/2008/">FOSDEM 2008&lt;/a>, not to mention the &lt;a href="http://haiku-os.org/conference/2008/haiku_coding_event">Haiku hacking event&lt;/a> that is taking place this very same week. With very few exceptions, these events are all the result of initiatives by one or more community members.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In an attempt to assist the effort of these community members who drive such initiatives and to lure more of them to follow suit, we have added to the Haiku website the ability to easily publish information about conferences and events, as a means to increase their exposure and as a tool to further engage the participation of the community in this events.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>New Java for Haiku Team Formed</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2008-01-03_new_java_for_haiku_team_formed/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2008 20:43:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2008-01-03_new_java_for_haiku_team_formed/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="field field-type-text field-field-body">
&lt;div class="field-items">
&lt;div class="field-item odd">
&lt;p>&lt;span class="inline right">&lt;img src="http://haiku-os.org/files/screenshots/logo_haiku-openjdk.png" alt="" title="" class="image img_assist_custom" height="124" width="250">&lt;/span>We are very excited to announce the creation of a new project team that will bring Java technologies to the Haiku. This team was established under the initiative of Haiku developer and team lead Bryan Varner, and is officially endorsed by the Haiku development team. In fact, discussions have taken place between Bryan and the rest of the core Haiku developers to start building synergy to ensure the viability of the Java Team's goals within the Haiku project.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The team's initial goal will be to port OpenJDK to Haiku. We want to have the Haiku port included within the structure of &lt;a href="http://openjdk.java.net">Sun's OpenJDK project&lt;/a>, and discussions have been taking place with members of t
he &lt;a href="http://openjdk.java.net/groups/porters/">OpenJDK Porters Group&lt;/a> to pursue this objective. After a meeting between Bryan, the Haiku core developers and Dalibor Topic, member and moderator of the Porters Group discussion list, we &lt;a href="http://mail.openjdk.java.net/pipermail/porters-dev/2007-December/000035.html">submitted a proposal&lt;/a> in order to find a sponsor member within the Porters Group to make the &lt;a href="http://mail.openjdk.java.net/pipermail/announce/2008-January/000053.html">official proposal to the OpenJDK project&lt;/a> as a whole. OpenJDK Groups have two weeks to vote on sponsorship of this proposal. A majority vote is required from one group for approval.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Haiku Files: a new source of Haiku nightly builds</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2007-12-21_haiku_files_a_new_source_of_haiku_nightly_builds/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Dec 2007 07:07:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2007-12-21_haiku_files_a_new_source_of_haiku_nightly_builds/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="field field-type-text field-field-body">
&lt;div class="field-items">
&lt;div class="field-item odd">
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://haiku-files.org">&lt;span class="inline right">&lt;img src="http://haiku-os.org/files/screenshots/haiku-files-logo.png" alt="Visit Haiku Files" title="Visit Haiku Files" class="image img_assist_custom" height="51" width="300" border="0">&lt;/span>&lt;/a>Until very recently, the community of Haiku testers and developers, as well as those curious geeks who wanted to give Haiku a spin, relied on the services of HaikuHost.com to download nightly builds of hard disk raw and VMware images. This site, which was operated by Jonathan Freeman, has &lt;a href="http://www.freelists.org/archives/openbeos/11-2007/msg00102.html">recently closed its doors&lt;/a>, so we felt we needed a replacement. Let me introduce you to &lt;a href="http://haiku-files.org">Haiku Files&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>WebKit port well underway</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2007-12-04_webkit_port_well_underway/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2007 17:03:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2007-12-04_webkit_port_well_underway/</guid><description>The Haiku project is proud to be once again part of Google's Code-In.
Together with 16 other open source projects we'll mentor students between 13 and 17 years of age through various large and small tasks. The aim is to introduce them to the work and community of open source projects, while benefitting ourselves from their work and energy, and maybe even by gaining future contributers.
If you know people in the right age bracket that might be interested, point them to Google's Code-In site that has all the information.</description></item><item><title>BeGeistert 018 plus Coding Event</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2007-12-03_begeistert_018/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Dec 2007 20:20:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2007-12-03_begeistert_018/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="field field-type-text field-field-body">
&lt;div class="field-items">
&lt;div class="field-item odd">
&lt;p>Many Haiku fans have been eagerly waiting for the next BeGeistert, and the official word is out now: &lt;a href"http://www.begeistert.org">BeGeistert 018 -- Phoenix&lt;/a> is coming back to Düsseldorf, where it will be held on January 12 and 13, 2008. But the good news does not end here: as a prelude to BeGeistert, a coding asylum event with the expected presence of many Haiku core developers has been organized on the same week and at the sample place.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Haikuware.com Thank You Award Results</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2007-12-03_haikuware_com_thank_you_award_results/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Dec 2007 17:37:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2007-12-03_haikuware_com_thank_you_award_results/</guid><description> The results of the second Haikuware.com Thank You Award are in, and with a mere two votes lead, the Thank You Award went to Ingo Weinhold. Congratulations!
If a contribution within the next two months strikes you as especially noteworthy, contact me with the details to get that person's name up for consideration.</description></item><item><title>Vote for Second Haikuware.com Thank You Award</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2007-11-29_vote_for_second_haikuware_com_thank_you_award/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2007 19:56:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2007-11-29_vote_for_second_haikuware_com_thank_you_award/</guid><description>Haikuware.com's Thank You Awards are granted every two months according to the results of an open poll. The award was created, as the name suggests, to show the community's appreciation for an individual or organisation contributing to the Haiku project.
The first award went to Axel Dörfler for his outstanding and tireless contributions over the past years.
You can vote for a candidate for the next Thank You Award and the accompanying $50 until 1st December 2007.</description></item><item><title>$4,000 Donation Received from Google for GSoC 2007 Participation</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2007-11-22_4000_donation_received_google_gsoc_2007_participation/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2007 01:49:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2007-11-22_4000_donation_received_google_gsoc_2007_participation/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="field field-type-text field-field-body">
&lt;div class="field-items">
&lt;div class="field-item odd">
&lt;p>Haiku Inc. recently received from Google a check for $4,000 for its participation in the last &lt;a href="http://code.google.com/soc/2007/">Google Summer of Code 2007&lt;/a> program. This is ten percent of the total $40,000 that Google disbursed to sponsor the &lt;a href="http://haiku-os.org/news/2007-04-11/its_official_eight_students_to_code_for_haiku_at_gsoc_2007">eight Haiku related projects&lt;/a> alloted for GSoC 2007. We want to thank Google for giving us the opportunity to participate in the program for the first time this year, and hope they will consider us again for next year.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Google Summer of Code is a program designed to sponsor students to work in open source projects during the three summer months. Open source software projects like Haiku apply to become mentoring organizations, and put forward projects that students from all over the world can apply for. The mentoring organizations provide mentors to guide the students throughout the program and to assist them in the successful completion of their project. For each successfully completed project, Google pays $4,500 to the student and $500 to the mentoring organization.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Haiku Gets Featured Speaker Spot &amp; Booth at SCaLE 6x Expo</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2007-11-13_haiku_gets_featured_speaker_spot_booth_at_scale_6x_expo/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2007 13:10:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2007-11-13_haiku_gets_featured_speaker_spot_booth_at_scale_6x_expo/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="field field-type-text field-field-body">
&lt;div class="field-items">
&lt;div class="field-item odd">
&lt;p>&lt;span class="inline right">&lt;img src="http://haiku-os.org/files/screenshots/125x125_scale06-exhibiting.gif" alt="Haiku to be featured at SCaLE 6x Expo on February 9 &amp;amp; 10, 2008" title="Haiku to be featured at SCaLE 6x Expo on February 9 &amp;amp; 10, 2008" class="image img_assist_custom" height="125" width="125">&lt;/span>I am pleased and very excited to announce that our application for a booth and a feature speaker spot at the &lt;a href="http://www.socallinuxexpo.org">SCaLE 6x Expo&lt;/a> have both been accepted. Yes, you read well: we will not only have a booth (for the second consecutive year), but Haiku developer and “Googler” Bruno G. Albuquerque will also be presenting our project and operating system as one of the few featured speakers that SCaLE invites every year among prominent members of the open source community. This is the first time Haiku is awarded a speaker spot at a renowned open source event, and we are proud of this achievement.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Reinventing Haiku</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2007-10-18_reinventing_haiku/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2007 09:50:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2007-10-18_reinventing_haiku/</guid><description>2007 has been a year of change for Haiku. None of it has been quite like this, however. Haiku, as an organization, is reinventing itself. First of all, on Aug. 31, Michael Phipps announced to the Haiku admin team that he intended to move on. Here are some of his words on the subject:
"... I think that it is time that I move on. Haiku has become something that I do because I have to.</description></item><item><title>AHCI SATA driver ready for testing</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2007-10-01_ahci_sata_driver_ready_for_testing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2007 10:45:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2007-10-01_ahci_sata_driver_ready_for_testing/</guid><description>Marcus Overhagen announced that his AHCI SATA driver is now ready for testing. If you have an AHCI compliant chipset, and a SATA hard drive attached, you may want to give his driver a try.
Most current motherboards are AHCI compliant - it is the defacto SATA device driver standard. This driver allows you to run Haiku on modern hardware natively, without using a PATA emulation that may be provided by your BIOS.</description></item><item><title>NORCAL-HUG Event: GSoC 2007 Haiku Mentor Appreciation Day</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2007-09-30_norcal_hug_event_gsoc_2007_haiku_mentor_appreciation_day/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Sep 2007 23:43:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2007-09-30_norcal_hug_event_gsoc_2007_haiku_mentor_appreciation_day/</guid><description>Jorge 'Koki' Mare and his fellow NorCal Haiku User Group members have graciously put together an event in honor of Stephan Aßmus, Oliver Ruiz Dorantes and myself to take place Sunday, October 7th. This will be from 1PM to 5PM at the Wild Palms Hotel in Sunnyvale, CA, where we are staying for the Google SoC Mentor Summit. If you live in the area, please check Jorge's post on the NORCAL-HUG site and sign up!</description></item><item><title>Announcing NORCAL-HUG</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2007-09-24_announcing_norcal_hug/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2007 23:26:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2007-09-24_announcing_norcal_hug/</guid><description>Posted to the Haiku mailing list earlier today was an announcement of another Haiku user group. BeOS in its heyday had user groups -- BUGs -- and it is good to see the appearance of corresponding groups for our favorite underdog operating system. Below are all the details as written by Jorge Mare (aka Koki) himself.
Hello Haiku Fans,
During the Haiku gathering at the Picn*x event last August, a few of us who live in and around the San Francisco Bay Area talked about presenting Haiku at user group meetings in the area.</description></item><item><title>Haiku at the Google Summer of Code Mentor Summit, October 6th</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2007-09-20_haiku_at_the_google_summer_of_code_mentor_summit_october_6th/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2007 23:18:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2007-09-20_haiku_at_the_google_summer_of_code_mentor_summit_october_6th/</guid><description>Each year after the Summer of Code is over, Google holds an informal Mentor Summit at their Mountain View, CA office to allow mentors to meet each other and talk about their experiences in the program. This also allows Google to get first-hand suggestions on what was done right and what could be improved in the program. This year the Summit is being held on Saturday, October 6th.
I am glad to report that three Haiku mentors will be attending the Summit: Stephan Aßmus, Oliver Ruiz Dorantes and myself.</description></item><item><title>2007 Google Summer of Code Summary</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2007-09-19_2007_google_summer_of_code_summary/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2007 22:31:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2007-09-19_2007_google_summer_of_code_summary/</guid><description>2007 was our first year involved in the Google Summer of Code. Looking back on it, it is easy to say that it was a resounding success. We were able to handle 8 students. Work accomplished included a mostly-complete FireWire stack, major improvements in networking, and more. Click Read More for summaries of every student projects.
FireWire stack for Haiku Student: JiSheng Zhang
Mentor: Jérôme Duval
JiSheng spent his summer porting the FreeBSD Firewire stack to Haiku.</description></item><item><title>PC Active: Haiku, the rebirth of BeOS</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2007-09-14_pc_active_haiku_the_rebirth_of_beos/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Sep 2007 19:04:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2007-09-14_pc_active_haiku_the_rebirth_of_beos/</guid><description>The Dutch magazine PC-Active published an article on Haiku in their October issue, based on an interview I gave a few months ago. We are even on the cover! From the article: &amp;quot;Years ago, the alternative operating system BeOS had a small, but very loyal group of supporters. They had a strong belief in the future of 'their' operating system. In 2001, the company behind BeOS ceased to exist. Now, half way through 2007, there is a new group enthousiastic followers.</description></item><item><title>Haiku Turns 6!</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2007-08-18_haiku_turns_6/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2007 17:00:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2007-08-18_haiku_turns_6/</guid><description>We are excited to announce that having reached the 18th of August, 2007, the Haiku project is now six years old!
Read on for some more details...
When the decision to start Haiku these six years ago was made (then still called OpenBeOS), the motivation to reach the goal of creating a functioning BeOS clone was very high. Over time this motivation has seen many ups and downs, and there have been times where development was really stagnant, but there were always the other times in which you could really feel how the system got forward.</description></item><item><title>Haiku Store Opens for Business and Community Contributions</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2007-08-06_haiku_store_opens_for_business_and_community_contributions/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2007 00:43:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2007-08-06_haiku_store_opens_for_business_and_community_contributions/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="field field-type-text field-field-body">
&lt;div class="field-items">
&lt;div class="field-item odd">
&lt;p>As another avenue to spread awareness of the Haiku project, the Haiku project has opened a store for official Haiku merchandise at &lt;a href="http://www.cafepress.com/haiku_os/">CafePress&lt;/a>. Find T-shirts, mousepads, coffee mugs, and more! Most items are sold at Haiku's cost and any proceeds go directly to Haiku. Read more for how you can contribute designs for the store. What's more is that this is a community-driven effort. Got a great idea for Haiku stuff? Here are the guidelines:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>FalterCon 2007</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2007-08-02_faltercon_2007/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2007 23:21:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2007-08-02_faltercon_2007/</guid><description>After the cancelation of WalterCon 2007 in San Francisco, the few that already registered for the event took their already bought airplane tickets as an opportunity to organise a community driven replacement for that event.
They called their gathering FalterCon 2007 - with the obvious pun intended. It's held on Saturday, August 11, from 11:00 AM to 4:00 PM in the Sunnyvale Baylands Park at the Linux 16th Anniversary Picnic.</description></item><item><title>WalterCon 2007 Canceled, Michael Phipps at LinuxWorld</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2007-07-24_waltercon_2007_canceled_michael_phipps_at_linuxworld/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2007 22:12:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2007-07-24_waltercon_2007_canceled_michael_phipps_at_linuxworld/</guid><description>It is with much regret and disappointment that I must announce that the Haiku project have decided to cancel WalterCon 2007 for lack of community interest. Those who have already registered will have all money refunded.
The perceived reason for this would be late announcement combined with the community being spread across the globe. Efforts are already under way to prevent such problems stemming from last-minute planning and to make WalterCon not only a success, but a hit.</description></item><item><title>WalterCon Registration Now Open</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2007-07-11_waltercon_registration_now_open/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jul 2007 14:49:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2007-07-11_waltercon_registration_now_open/</guid><description> Registration is finally open. Sorry about the long delay, folks. In addition to the financial setup, there have been major technical difficulties which we are working around. More details can be found at the WalterCon website, including the just-published agenda.</description></item><item><title>WalterCon 2007 Announced</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2007-07-03_waltercon_2007_announced/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jul 2007 15:42:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2007-07-03_waltercon_2007_announced/</guid><description>The upcoming Haiku conference WalterCon 2007 has finally been announced: this year, it will be held in San Francisco, California, on August 11 and 12.
As last year, we've prepared a website that hopefully contains all the information you need to decide whether or not you want to attend. The conference will feature training-oriented sessions, though the agenda has not been completed yet. Take your chance to get to know some of the people behind Haiku!</description></item><item><title>Open Sound System 4.0 is coming to Haiku</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2007-07-03_open_sound_system_4_0_is_coming_to_haiku/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jul 2007 15:30:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2007-07-03_open_sound_system_4_0_is_coming_to_haiku/</guid><description>Haiku developer Fran&amp;ccedil;ois Revol has done an initial port of the Open Sound System to Haiku. OSS has been open sourced by 4front Technologies recently, and powers the audio hardware of many Unix derivates.
OSS features an impressive list of supported devices - the port aims to seemlessly integrate with Haiku's media subsystem, the OSS drivers will just work like any other of the currently available audio drivers.
For further information, please refer to this announcement made on the OSS developer mailing list.</description></item><item><title>Audio CD File System in the Works</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2007-05-16_audio_cd_file_system_in_the_works/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2007 20:43:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2007-05-16_audio_cd_file_system_in_the_works/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="field field-type-text field-field-body">
&lt;div class="field-items">
&lt;div class="field-item odd">
[img_assist|nid=1687|title=CDDA-FS running in Haiku|desc=|link=popup|align=right|width=200|height=136]&lt;p>Haiku developer Axel Dörfler has started to work on a CDDA file system
for playing audio CDs for Haiku. CDDA-FS allows Haiku users to view
and play music tracks from mounted audio CDs as if they were WAV files.
CDDA-FS also supports CD-Text which means that information like album
titles, artist names, and song titles available from the CD itself will
be shown as file attributes, so that they can be viewed and edited in
Tracker.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>While CDDA-FS is not finished yet, it can already be used to play back
CD contents as you can see from the screenshot. The file system is
accompanied by a small test application "cdda_text" which also runs
under BeOS and prints all information CDDA-FS can retrieve from the
specified CD.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Haiku Distribution Guidelines Released and Development Mailing List Created (Updated)</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2007-05-15_haiku_distribution_guidelines_released_and_development_mailing_list_created_updated/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2007 07:39:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2007-05-15_haiku_distribution_guidelines_released_and_development_mailing_list_created_updated/</guid><description>First of all, we now have a separate development mailing list. We actually had such a list a long time ago, but it didn't work out well. We want to try it again because quite a few development issues were discussed in private which can't be an ideal solution for an open-source project. The general mailing list will from now on be used for our community and non-development discussions.</description></item><item><title>Haiku Getting a FreeBSD Network Driver Compatibility Layer</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2007-05-08_haiku_getting_a_freebsd_network_driver_compatibility_layer/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2007 01:33:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2007-05-08_haiku_getting_a_freebsd_network_driver_compatibility_layer/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="field field-type-text field-field-body">
&lt;div class="field-items">
&lt;div class="field-item odd">
&lt;p>Thanks to the work of one of the most active code contributors lately, Hugo Santos, Haiku is getting a generic &lt;a href="http://www.freebsd.org">FreeBSD&lt;/a> network driver compatibility layer that will allow FreeBSD network drivers to be compiled and used in Haiku with few, if any changes. At the time of this writing, not only has Hugo &lt;a href="http://svn.berlios.de/viewcvs/haiku/haiku/trunk/src/libs/compat/freebsd_network/">committed the compatibility layer to the Haiku tree&lt;/a>, but he has also succeeded in building two FreeBSD drivers (if_em/Intel Pro 1000 and &lt;a href="http://svn.berlios.de/viewcvs/haiku/haiku/trunk/src/add-ons/kernel/drivers/network/pcnet/dev/le/">if_le/PCNet&lt;/a>) which are now capable of running in Haiku.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>WalterCon 2007 survey</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2007-05-03_waltercon_2007_survey/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 May 2007 01:37:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2007-05-03_waltercon_2007_survey/</guid><description> If you have any interest in attending WalterCon, our annual users group meeting, either this year or in the future, please fill out this survey to help us plan. Thanks!
Survey</description></item><item><title>Haiku at Open Source Conference in Venezuela</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2007-05-01_haiku_at_open_source_conference_in_venezuela/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2007 02:57:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2007-05-01_haiku_at_open_source_conference_in_venezuela/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="field field-type-text field-field-body">
&lt;div class="field-items">
&lt;div class="field-item odd">
&lt;span class="inline right">&lt;img src="http://haiku-os.org/files/screenshots/cnsl.png" alt="" title="" class="image img_assist_custom" height="62" width="220">&lt;/span>&lt;p>We were pleased to hear that Haiku community member Axzel Marín Graü is scheduled to give a presentation about Haiku at the &lt;a href="http://www.cnsl.org.ve/Sucre">National Open Source Software Congress&lt;/a> (CNSL 3) to be held in Sucre, Venezuela, this coming May 18th and 19th. During his presentation titled "Open Source is not only GNU/Linux. Introduction to Haiku," Axzel will give an overview of the project, talk about the progress made so far in development, and conduct a brief demo to show Haiku in action.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Documentation Team Started and Seeks Help</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2007-04-18_documentation_team_started_and_seeks_help/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2007 17:30:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2007-04-18_documentation_team_started_and_seeks_help/</guid><description>With the release of the BeBook under the Creative Commons license, ACCESS Co. Ltd enables us to provide the potential developers of today with all the documentation of the BeOS API. But to ensure that API documentation will be available and up to date for the future generations of developers, the Haiku project announces a structured effort on the writing of the Haiku API documentation from scratch. The documentation team is small and young and any help would be very much appreciated.</description></item><item><title>JMicron Supports SATA Implementation in Haiku (updated)</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2007-04-14_jmicron_supports_sata_implementation_in_haiku/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Apr 2007 09:25:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2007-04-14_jmicron_supports_sata_implementation_in_haiku/</guid><description>Note: JMicron monitors user comments and encourages all Haiku supporters to post their comments at the Haiku Website, instead of mailing them directly. Thanks for your support!
We are pleased to announce that JMicron Technology Corporation has offered to give our project support in the implementation of SATA technology for Haiku. JMicron has pledged to support the development effort by providing the required technical documentation as well as hardware for testing.</description></item><item><title>It's Official: Eight Students to Code for Haiku at GSoC 2007</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2007-04-11_its_official_eight_students_to_code_for_haiku_at_gsoc_2007/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2007 02:10:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2007-04-11_its_official_eight_students_to_code_for_haiku_at_gsoc_2007/</guid><description>Google has given their final word, and we are now pleased to announce that Haiku has been assigned 8 student slots for the Google Summer of Code 2007, which is one more than we had initially hoped for. Here is a list of the accepted applications, also as a way of introduction of the eight students that were selected from a total of 42 applications.
Update: Added usernames and linked to user's page.</description></item><item><title>Google Summer of Code 2007: Update</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2007-03-27_google_summer_of_code_2007_update/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Apr 2007 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2007-03-27_google_summer_of_code_2007_update/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="field field-type-text field-field-body">
&lt;div class="field-items">
&lt;div class="field-item odd">
&lt;span class="inline right">&lt;a href="../" onclick="launch_popup(1628, 1024, 768); return false;" target="_blank">&lt;img src="http://haiku-os.org/files/screenshots/shot_haiku_nfs_002_working.thumbnail.png" alt="Playing an MP3 over NFS on Haiku" title="Playing an MP3 over NFS on Haiku" class="image thumbnail" height="150" width="200">&lt;/a>&lt;span class="caption" style="width: 198px;">&lt;strong>Playing an MP3 over NFS on Haiku&lt;/strong>&lt;/span>&lt;/span>
&lt;p>Yesterday, Google has assigned 7 preliminary student slots to us, which is as many as we wanted to have. Haiku would like thank all the students that have applied for projects and those that have assisted in this step of the program. Overall, we received 42 student applications. In the next days we will finalize the list of accepted student projects for Haiku.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Haiku Lecture at FISL 8.0 FOSS Conference in Brazil</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2007-04-07_haiku_lecture_at_fisl_8_0_foss_conference_in_brazil/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Apr 2007 21:59:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2007-04-07_haiku_lecture_at_fisl_8_0_foss_conference_in_brazil/</guid><description>Haiku developer and Google engineer Bruno G. Albuquerque is scheduled to give a lecture about Haiku at the upcoming 8th International Free Software Forum (FISL 8.0), to be held in Porto Alegre, RS, Brazil, on April 12th, 13th and 14th. This lecture, one of the six presentations given by Google at this event, will cover general aspects of Haiku and will include a hands-on demonstration as well.
Title: Introducing Haiku Presenter: Bruno G.</description></item><item><title>ACCESS Co. Releases BeBook and Be Newsletters</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2007-04-03_access_co_releases_bebook_and_be_newsletters/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Apr 2007 17:00:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2007-04-03_access_co_releases_bebook_and_be_newsletters/</guid><description>We are very pleased to announce that ACCESS Co. Ltd., the current holders of the BeOS intellectual property, has responded positively to our request for permission to reproduce the BeBook and all the Be Newsletters. As a result, we will be able to release these BeOS legacy documents under a Creative Commons license.
"ACCESS is very pleased to be able to support the Haiku project by making these documents more widely available to interested developers,"</description></item><item><title>Extended Deadline for GSoC 2007 Applications (Updated)</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2007-03-25_extended_deadline_for_google_soc_2007_applications/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2007 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2007-03-25_extended_deadline_for_google_soc_2007_applications/</guid><description> Google has extended the student application deadline for Google Summer of Code 2007 to 12:00 AM UTC on March 27, 2007. Students that are still interested in working on a project for Haiku are urged to finish their application and get it in by the new deadline.</description></item><item><title>Google Summer of Code 2007: We Are In!</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2007-03-15_google_summer_of_code_2007_we_are_in/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2007 11:37:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2007-03-15_google_summer_of_code_2007_we_are_in/</guid><description>We are pleased and at the same time thrilled to inform the community that Google has accepted our application to become a mentor organization for the Google Summer of Code 2007. Yes, we have made it! Students now have until March 24 to apply for any of our project ideas from the GSoC Web App for Student Applicants. If you are a student and are interested in working on one of our project ideas, please check out our List of GSoC Ideas and Students: How to Apply pages for detailed information.</description></item><item><title>Haiku to be Presented at Numerica</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2007-03-06_haiku_be_presented_numerica/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2007 13:50:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2007-03-06_haiku_be_presented_numerica/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="field field-type-text field-field-body">
&lt;div class="field-items">
&lt;div class="field-item odd">
&lt;span class="inline right">&lt;a href="http://haiku-os.org/files/screenshots/2007-03-06_NUMERICA-artparty-web-flyer.thumbnail.jpg">&lt;img src="http://haiku-os.org/files/screenshots/2007-03-06_NUMERICA-artparty-web-flyer.thumbnail.jpg" alt="" title="" class="image thumbnail" height="200" width="141">&lt;/a>&lt;/span>&lt;p>Long time Haiku developer François Revol (a.k.a. mmu_man) is scheduled to give a Haiku presentation at the first Numerica Art Party, an event sponsored by A.D.A.N., the French Association for the Development of Digital Art. Numerica #01 will be taking place from March 9th through the 11th in &lt;a href="http://maps.google.com/maps?f=q&amp;hl=en&amp;q=Montbeliard,+France&amp;layer=&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;om=1&amp;z=6&amp;ll=47.428087,6.899414&amp;spn=6.852467,21.950684&amp;iwloc=addr">Montbeliard, France&lt;/a>. The &lt;a href="http://numerica.demoscene.tv/dotclear/index.php/2007/02/25/11-haiku-conference">Haiku Conference&lt;/a> by François is scheduled for Saturday March 10h, from 7:00pm to 8:00pm (GMT+01:00), and will be broadcast live on the web TV &lt;a href="http://demoscene.tv">demoscene.tv&lt;/a>. Stay tuned!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For more information regarding registration, remote entries, competitions, and timetable, please visit the &lt;a href="http://numerica.demoscene.tv/">Numerica website&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Google Summer of Code 2007 Drive</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2007-03-03_google_summer_of_code_2007_drive/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Mar 2007 08:32:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2007-03-03_google_summer_of_code_2007_drive/</guid><description>The application period for the Google Summer of Code 2007 is close, and as Haiku prepares to submit its application to attempt becoming a mentor organization, we are initiating a drive with the goal engaging the Haiku community at large. We will be submitting our application on March 5th or 6th, and expect to know whether our application has been accepted on March 14th, the day that Google is scheduled to announce the accepted mentoring organizations on code.</description></item><item><title>Haiku Getting UserlandFS, NetFS</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2007-02-20_haiku_getting_userlandfs_netfs/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2007 18:12:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2007-02-20_haiku_getting_userlandfs_netfs/</guid><description>We are excited to announce that Haiku developer Ingo Weinhold has recently committed UserlandFS to the repository. UserlandFS is designed to provide, for the first time in Haiku (and the BeOS platform), a stable and flexible environment for file system add-on development. Along with UserlandFS, Ingo has also committed several file system modules, including a Reiser FS 3.6 read-only implementation, a RAM FS (which is still work in progress), and NetFS, a Haiku-specific networking file system.</description></item><item><title>Haiku Tech Talk at Google a Success</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2007-02-14_haiku_tech_talk_at_google_ends_successfully/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2007 09:23:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2007-02-14_haiku_tech_talk_at_google_ends_successfully/</guid><description>Yesterday was our big day at Google, and we can say with a good degree of confidence that the Haiku Tech Talk was quite successful. We had a very special guest for this event: former Be Inc. CEO Jean Louis Gassée, not only joined us at Google for our presentation, but also gave a few words of support and encouragement for our project. It was great to have JLG's presence, as well as that of the several ex-Be engineers who showed up for the talk.</description></item><item><title>SCaLE 5x First Day Report - Part 2</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2007-02-11_scale_5x_first_day_report_part_2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2007 19:08:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2007-02-11_scale_5x_first_day_report_part_2/</guid><description>After our first report, Michael's stuff finally arrived and we were able to set up Haiku on a projector screen, which actually helped bring more attention to our booth. The impression that I have been getting from the people visiting our booth is that the reception of our ideal of a desktop OS designed for, focused on, and optimized for the desktop is very positive. It has been a very encouraging experience so far.</description></item><item><title>SCaLE 5x First Day Report - Part I</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2007-02-10_scale_5x_first_day_report_part_i/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2007 21:28:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2007-02-10_scale_5x_first_day_report_part_i/</guid><description>SCaLE 5x started this morning and it has been a lot of fun so far. Axel, Michael (Phipps), Jorge (Mare) and myself (BGA) came down to the exhibit floor early this morning to setup the booth in advance of the opening. We have a 10x10 booth with a table and a couple of chairs, so we setup a small form factor desktop PC hooked up to a 20 inch LCD monitor, and a couple of laptops, an IBM running Haiku natively, and a MacBook Pro running Haiku inside Parallels.</description></item><item><title>Details of Haiku Presence at SCaLE 5x</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2007-02-09_details_of_haiku_presence_at_scale_5x/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2007 08:55:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2007-02-09_details_of_haiku_presence_at_scale_5x/</guid><description>We finally have the specific details regarding the activities planned by the Haiku Project at the SCaLE 5x Conference. It's going to be two days filled with action, including an exhibit booth with a projector demonstrating Haiku, and two Birds of a Feather (BOF) presentations.
SCaLE 5x floor plan; Haiku is at booth #42. Haiku Exhibit We will be at booth #42. We are planning on having a projector running Haiku on a backwall screen, and a couple of hands-on PCs so that visitors can actually play with Haiku.</description></item><item><title>Symbolic Milestones</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2007-01-28_symbolic_milestones/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2007 22:58:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2007-01-28_symbolic_milestones/</guid><description>Some will argue that these were just meaningless numbers, nevertheless we have reached significant milestones today: 1000th bug entry, and even better, 20000th subversion change. Recent subversion changes include many bug fixes and several additions in the file system area.
Several file system add-ons were ported from BeOS (Haiku has a different VFS interface):
NTFS, using a GPLed libntfs, should even handle writing if you don't mind some risk of losing data.</description></item><item><title>Haiku Website: Taking One Little Step Forward</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2007-01-21_haiku_website_taking_one_little_step_forward/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2007 22:42:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2007-01-21_haiku_website_taking_one_little_step_forward/</guid><description>BodyWe finally have the long promised new website. It has taken much longer than expected, but hopefully the wait was worth it. I would like to briefly introduce some of the (not so obvious) changes, and try to explain how to make the best of the Haiku website as a tool for the community to contribute to our project.
About Section Haiku Gallery
For starters, there is now a new Haiku Gallery.</description></item><item><title>Haiku Tech Talks to be Held at Google</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2007-01-15_haiku_tech_talks_at_google/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2007 10:41:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2007-01-15_haiku_tech_talks_at_google/</guid><description>BodyWe are very excited to inform the community that a series of Haiku Tech Talks have been scheduled at Google. Long time Haiku developer and OpenBFS Team leader Bruno Albuquerque (BGA), now working at Google since last year, has made arrangements for these talks, giving us a precious opportunity to introduce the Haiku Project to many Google engineers.
The Haiku talks are scheduled to be held at the following Google locations in the dates shown below:</description></item><item><title>VMWare Graphics Driver for Haiku in the Works</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2007-01-12_vmware_graphics_driver_haiku_works/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2007 07:21:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2007-01-12_vmware_graphics_driver_haiku_works/</guid><description>BodyHaiku using VMWare driver in Intel MACEric Petit has recently given us the great news on the Haiku mailing list that he has started work on a VMWare graphics driver/accelerant for Haiku. This driver is expected not only to make Haiku snappier when run in VMWare, but it will also enable Haiku's ability to select different screen resolutions and changing them without rebooting the system, a feature that is not available when video is running in VESA mode.</description></item><item><title>2007 New Year Greeting</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2007-01-01_new_year_greeting/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2007 00:10:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2007-01-01_new_year_greeting/</guid><description>BodyAnother year is gone, and a new one has just began. Looking back, 2006 was a good year for Haiku: we saw not only gains in functionality, features and stability, but also in looks. The USB and the network stacks where two prominent areas where progress was made; lots of other additions and improvements were also made under the hood, and, of course, the expected bug fixes, which were many.</description></item><item><title>Xmas Present for WalterCon 2006 Attendants</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2006-12-18_xmas_present_for_waltercon_2006_attendants/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2006 02:03:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2006-12-18_xmas_present_for_waltercon_2006_attendants/</guid><description>At the WalterCon 2006 conference recently held in Orlando, we had planned a drawing with prizes from our sponsors. Unfortunately, due to an internal communication mishap, the drawing did not happen. But since we still want to show our gratitude to everyone who attended WalterCon, we have decided to give out one of the software packages donated by the event sponsors to each of the attendees, as a small token of appreciation.</description></item><item><title>Haiku to Exhibit at SCaLE 5x Conference</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2006-12-14_haiku_to_exhibit_at_scale_5x_conference/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2006 19:36:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2006-12-14_haiku_to_exhibit_at_scale_5x_conference/</guid><description>We are excited to announce that the Haiku Project is scheduled to exhibit at SCaLE 5x, the Fifth Annual Southern California Linux Expo, to be held at The Westin Los Angeles Airport hotel on the weekend of February 10 and 11, 2007. This is our debut at a major open source conference and represents an important first step towards becoming a widely recognized member of the global open source community.</description></item><item><title>Chinese Language Support for Haiku</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2006-12-08_chinese_language_support_for_haiku/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2006 19:12:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2006-12-08_chinese_language_support_for_haiku/</guid><description>We are pleased to announce that Haiku has taken its first steps towards supporting the Chinese language. Developer Anthony Lee has graciously donated to Haiku the code of BeCJK, an input server add-on based input method which will allow Haiku users to enter text in the Chinese language.
We have now set out to find a good set of Chinese fonts that could be used in Haiku, and Anthony is giving us some advise on that front too.</description></item><item><title>Haiku Network Stack Takes First Baby Steps</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2006-12-06_haiku_network_stack_takes_first_baby_steps/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2006 01:32:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2006-12-06_haiku_network_stack_takes_first_baby_steps/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="field field-type-text field-field-body">&lt;h3 class="field-label">Body&lt;/h3>&lt;div class="field-items">&lt;div class="field-item">&lt;span class="inline right">&lt;a href="../" onclick="launch_popup(269, 1024, 640); return false;" target="_blank">&lt;img src="../files/screenshots/2006-12-07_vision-in-haiku_1.thumbnail.png" alt="IRC client Vision running on Haiku" title="IRC client Vision running on Haiku" class="image thumbnail" height="125" width="200">&lt;/a>&lt;span class="caption" style="width: 198px;">&lt;strong>IRC client Vision running on Haiku&lt;/strong>&lt;/span>&lt;/span>&lt;p>Thanks to the dedicated work of lead developer Axel Dörfler, the Haiku network stack has started taking its first baby steps. After &lt;a href="https://lists.berlios.de/pipermail/haiku-commits/2006-December/009647.html">this commit&lt;/a>, Axel himself and several others have reported successfully running the Vision IRC client in Haiku. Setting up the network requires editing a couple of configuration files, but it should be fairly straighforward for those brave enought to give it a try; Axel explains &lt;a href="https://lists.berlios.de/pipermail/haiku-commits/2006-December/009649.html">how to do it here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Great work Axel!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Flash Support Coming to Haiku</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2006-11-27_flash_support_coming_to_haiku/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2006 03:01:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2006-11-27_flash_support_coming_to_haiku/</guid><description>While this is not part of the core Haiku development, we still feel it is important for our platform and our Haiku fans to report this news. We are excited to tell you that Haiku developer Michael Lotz is porting the open source Flash player Gnash to Haiku. This port is based on the latest Gnash 0.7.2 release, and uses the AGG rendering backend (which Haiku uses for its graphics system), and a native GUI.</description></item><item><title>Icon Facts</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2006-11-06_icon_facts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2006 22:19:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2006-11-06_icon_facts/</guid><description>With this article, I want to introduce you to some interesting facts about the new Icon format that Haiku is using. At first sight, they are just scalable vector icons, and Haiku is not the only operating system to have them. But the interesting bits are in the implementation details which should make Haiku stand out from the rest.
The first unique feature is that Haiku uses a special vector storage format, that has been specifically designed to store icons; we call it the Haiku Vector Icon Format, or HVIF for short.</description></item><item><title>Icon Contest: And the Best Rated Icon Set Award goes to...</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2006-11-03_icon_contest_and_best_rated_icon_set_award_goes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2006 07:33:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2006-11-03_icon_contest_and_best_rated_icon_set_award_goes/</guid><description>Stippi's Icon Set The community has spoken, and as project leader Michael Phipps recently announced at WalterCon 2006, we have a winner for the Best Rated Icon Set Award: the honor goes to Stephan Assmus, for his Stippi icon set. Stippi came in first place with the highest average rating, closely followed in second place by the Honey, Zumi and Mc Clintock icon sets.
With the results of the open rating in hand, there is now work left towards creating the final icon guidelines.</description></item><item><title>My Experience at WalterCon 2006</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2006-11-01_my_experience_at_waltercon_2006/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2006 04:55:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2006-11-01_my_experience_at_waltercon_2006/</guid><description>BodySince I live in South Florida I had to take the opportunity to attend WalterCon 2006 since it was only three hours away in Orlando. My involvement in Haiku has not been tremendous at this point, but it and BeOS have always had a special place in my heart. I hoped attending the conference would bring back some of my passion for developing on Haiku. I'm glad to report this was the case.</description></item><item><title>WalterCon 2006 Report</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2006-10-31_waltercon_2006_report/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2006 19:29:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2006-10-31_waltercon_2006_report/</guid><description>WalterCon 2006 was held this past weekend in Orlando, Florida, and for those who have been waiting to know what it was all about, the wait is over. Jem Matzan of The Jem Report was at WalterCon, and he has written an interesting article on the conference that gives an overview of the event, and also makes some insightful observations as someone new to the project and the platform.</description></item><item><title>Networking Status Update</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2006-10-28_networking_status_update/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2006 11:15:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2006-10-28_networking_status_update/</guid><description>Work on the networking stack is making slow but steady progress. UDP and IPv4 protocols are mostly done, TCP can send out data, but receiving is not yet implemented.
Current work is concentrating on getting TCP ready, and to implement a network server. This server is responsible for configuring the stack when it&amp;#39;s started, and to take over inetd services and similar things that can or even should live in userland.</description></item><item><title>Haiku Lecture at Open Source Event in Brazil</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2006-10-01_haiku_lecture_at_open_source_event_in_brazil/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2006 08:24:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2006-10-01_haiku_lecture_at_open_source_event_in_brazil/</guid><description>Under the sponsorship of Google, BFS Team lead engineer Bruno Albuquerque is scheduled to give a Haiku-related lecture at the upcoming Encontro Mineiro de Software Livre 2006 (Minas Gerais Open Source Forum 2006) to be held on October 10, 11 and 12 at the Ouro Preto City Convention Center. Titled &amp;quot;Haiku OS -- Challenges of Creating an Operating System&amp;quot;, the lecture will introduce Haiku with a focus on the technical challenges and the motivations behind the creation of the project.</description></item><item><title>Icon Contest: What's Next?</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2006-09-28_icon_contest_whats_next/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2006 05:51:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2006-09-28_icon_contest_whats_next/</guid><description>September 23 was the last day of the rating period for the Haiku Icon Contest. We want to thank the authors of the great artistic work submitted to the contest, as well as those who took the time to rate the icons. Interest in the contest was very high, as reflected by the more than two thousand unique visitors that made their voice heard during the three week rating period.</description></item><item><title>Haiku Icon Contest: Time's up! Go Rate Them!</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2006-09-02_haiku_icon_contest_times_up_go_rate_them/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2006 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2006-09-02_haiku_icon_contest_times_up_go_rate_them/</guid><description>Time is up for the Haiku Icon Contest submissions, and it is now everybody&amp;#39;s chance to make their voice heard. Head over to the rating page, and tell us what you think about the fourteen gorgeous icon sets that were submitted to the contest. In the rating page you can view the icon sets side by side for comparison purposes, as well as preview each icon set on a virtual desktop.</description></item><item><title>HaikuBounties.org donations to Haiku</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2006-08-26_haikubounties_org_donations_to_haiku/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2006 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2006-08-26_haikubounties_org_donations_to_haiku/</guid><description>We owe a long due recognition to a Haiku contributor who came up with some great ideas, implemented them, and turned them into much needed funding for our project. We are referring to Karl vom Dorff, creator of HaikuBounties.org, a website where contributors can make monetary donations for specific areas of development, and developers can take coding challenges in exchange for the donated bounties. Karl started HaikuBounties.org early this year, and through the course of just a few months, he was able to raise close to $2000!</description></item><item><title>Marketing: We are all in this together</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2006-08-22_marketing_we_are_all_in_this_together/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2006 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2006-08-22_marketing_we_are_all_in_this_together/</guid><description>One of the toughest challenges among people interested in Haiku is the lack of accurate information about the project, as well as documentation. This is particularly bad for people outside of the English-speaking world. There are initiatives within the Haiku Project to rectify this situation, and we are already seeing these efforts gradually coming to fruition. For example, a new Haiku website is now being worked on, which is designed to provide more and better information, and to make Haiku more accessible to more potential contributors.</description></item><item><title>Marcom For Fun</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2006-08-18_marcom_for_fun/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Aug 2006 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2006-08-18_marcom_for_fun/</guid><description>Happy 5th Birthday, Haiku! Has it been five years, already? Seems like just yesterday. Let&amp;#39;s celebrate with a new article. :)
Welcome, IBM. Seriously.
Apple created an ad with the above text when the IBM PC came out. That was pretty bold, considering that IBM had a market cap hundreds of times that of Apple at that time. That is the sort of marketing that either makes a huge splash or flops badly.</description></item><item><title>Clarifying the Haiku Icon Contest</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2006-08-16_clarifying_the_haiku_icon_contest/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2006 22:18:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2006-08-16_clarifying_the_haiku_icon_contest/</guid><description>Since it appears that there may have been some confusion about the recently announced Haiku Icon Contest , we want to make a few clarifications in order to clear up any doubts about the contest.
The objective of the Haiku Icon Contest is to help develop design guidelines for the eventual creation of a full Haiku Icon Set. Just to give you an idea, the guidelines would look something like the Tango guidelines, but would be specific to Haiku.</description></item><item><title>Help needed: Web Design</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2006-08-05_help_needed_web_design/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2006 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2006-08-05_help_needed_web_design/</guid><description>Please help us create a nice theme for our new website which is based on Drupal, a popular community-oriented content management system with emphasize on navigation based on tags and relations instead of a static page tree. The website&amp;#39;s structure is already in place (it&amp;#39;s what you see in front of you). All we need is a nice theme.
You may add a smaller quick-links navbar for some of the main navigation entries (e.</description></item></channel></rss>