<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Virtualizing Haiku on Haiku Project</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/guides/virtualizing/</link><description>Recent content in Virtualizing Haiku on Haiku Project</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>2001-2021 Haiku Inc.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2013 17:06:04 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.haiku-os.org/guides/virtualizing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Virtualizing Haiku in QtQEMU</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/guides/virtualizing/qtqemu/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2020 21:49:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/guides/virtualizing/qtqemu/</guid><description>Virtual instances of operating systems are perfect for all kinds of testing purposes that need to be done in a safe and isolated environment. Installing Haiku in a virtual machine is a solution for people who do not want to install it on their physical computers, but wish to become familiar with it.
This guide will describe the process of running Haiku in a virtual machine (VM) using QEMU 4.1.0 and an .</description></item><item><title>Emulating Haiku on DigitalOcean</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/guides/virtualizing/digitalocean/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2019 23:41:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/guides/virtualizing/digitalocean/</guid><description>DigitalOcean is one of the most popular KVM Cloud providers that allow the end user to upload raw disk images. As they don&amp;rsquo;t allow booting from ISO, we will need to use VirtualBox or other virtualization software for installing Haiku. This guide assumes that you already have a DigitalOcean account, you&amp;rsquo;re at least partly familiar with the interface and that you have already installed Haiku in a VM. You will need to obtain a disk image (*.</description></item><item><title>Setting up Haiku in Vultr</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/guides/virtualizing/vultr/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2019 19:04:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/guides/virtualizing/vultr/</guid><description>Vultr allows one to upload a custom iso on their instances. With this, many new possibilities are open - such as setting up a buildbot, automated testing, benchmarking and more. This task assumes you have a Vultr account and that you are aware that it will charge you for setting up and running an instance.
Preparing a direct ISO link Vultr doesn&amp;rsquo;t allow one to upload a custom iso from a local machine.</description></item><item><title>Emulating Haiku in KVM</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/guides/virtualizing/kvm/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/guides/virtualizing/kvm/</guid><description>For Google Code-In 2019, Vrondir created a video on how to install Haiku in KVM [79 MiB].
Virtual instances of operating systems are perfect for all kinds of testing purposes that need to be done in a safe and isolated environment. Therefore, installing Haiku in a virtual machine is an ideal solution for people who do not want to install it on their physical computers but want to become familiar with it.</description></item><item><title>Emulating Haiku In ESXi</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/guides/virtualizing/vmware-esxi/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2019 20:10:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/guides/virtualizing/vmware-esxi/</guid><description>In 2017, Max Levchuk created a tutorial video for VMware ESXi [5 MiB].
Virtualizing an operating system might be a good way to give it a test run, or to use it alongside your main OS. ESXi is a platform that allows easy deployment of virtual machines on baremetal servers, and setting up a Haiku ESXi VM might be a good idea if you intend to develop Haiku or applications for it.</description></item><item><title>Virtualizing Haiku in Veertu Desktop</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/guides/virtualizing/veertu-desktop/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/guides/virtualizing/veertu-desktop/</guid><description>Virtual instances of operating systems are perfect for all kinds of testing purposes that need to be done in a safe and isolated environment. Installing Haiku in a virtual machine is a solution for people who do not want to install it on their physical computers, but wish to become familiar with it.
This guide will describe the process of running Haiku on a virtual machine (VM) using Veertu Desktop.</description></item><item><title>Emulating Haiku in VMware Fusion</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/guides/virtualizing/vmware-fusion/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2016 10:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/guides/virtualizing/vmware-fusion/</guid><description>For Google Code-In 2019, Thinker Pal created a video on how to install Haiku in VMware Fusion [24 MiB].
Start by downloading a Haiku ISO image, do select the closest mirror to enjoy higher transfer rates. Verify using the checksums to make sure that the downloaded files are not corrupted as they are big files. VMware Fusion is available for free.
Go to section: Installing and running Haiku from an ISO image Additional Steps Troubleshooting Installing and running Haiku from an ISO image This method is pretty much similar to installing on an actual machine.</description></item><item><title>Virtualizing Haiku in Parallels Desktop</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/guides/virtualizing/parallels-desktop/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2016 21:36:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/guides/virtualizing/parallels-desktop/</guid><description>For Google Code-In 2017, Villyam created a video on how to install Haiku in Parallels Desktop [10 MiB].
Virtual instances of operating systems are perfect for all kinds of testing purposes that need to be done in a safe and isolated environment. Installing Haiku in a virtual machine is a solution for people who do not want to install it on their physical computers, but wish to become familiar with it.</description></item><item><title>Virtualizing Haiku in SimNow</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/guides/virtualizing/simnow/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2016 06:09:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/guides/virtualizing/simnow/</guid><description>For Google Code-In 2017, Arnav Bhatt created a video on how to install Haiku in SimNow [8 MiB].
This article is aimed at developers, as AMD SimNow is both a Virtual machine and an AMD hardware emulator. If you just want to try Haiku out, you might want to use another VM that is more aimed at end users.
Go to section: Downloading Haiku Downloading AMD SimNow Installing AMD SimNow Preparing the Virtual Machine Running the Virtual Machine Downloading Haiku There are several methods offered to install Haiku.</description></item><item><title>Virtualizing Haiku in VMware Workstation</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/guides/virtualizing/vmware-workstation/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2016 18:11:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/guides/virtualizing/vmware-workstation/</guid><description>For Google Code-In 2019, Zotyamester created a video on how to install Haiku in VMware Workstation [59 MiB].
Virtual instances of operating systems are perfect for all kinds of testing purposes that need to be done in a safe and isolated environment. Installing Haiku in a virtual machine is a solution for people who do not want to install it on their physical computers, but wish to become familiar with it.</description></item><item><title>VirtualBox Serial Debugging on Windows</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/guides/virtualizing/virtualbox-windows-debugging/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2013 13:02:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/guides/virtualizing/virtualbox-windows-debugging/</guid><description>This tutorial uses VirtualBox version 4.2.6. You can set Port Mode as either Host Pipe Mode or Raw File Mode when serial debugging with VirtualBox.
With Raw File Mode, you can easily and quickly save the debugged onto a .txt file whereas it might be rather difficult for to check out the content of debugging real time. When it comes to Host Pipe Mode, it&amp;rsquo;s a little more complicated than the Raw File Mode, but you can confirm what is being debugged real time.</description></item><item><title>Virtualizing Haiku in Hyper-V</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/guides/virtualizing/hyper-v/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2013 10:32:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/guides/virtualizing/hyper-v/</guid><description>For Google Code-In 2017, Arnav Bhatt created a video on how to install Haiku in Hyper-V [11 MiB].
There are two methods for installing Haiku: RAW images and Anyboot images. RAW images consist of a pre-installed environment, whereby the Virtual Hard Disk is of a fixed size. By using a RAW image, you do not need to go through the installation process. The Anyboot images, on the other hand, can be burnt to a CD-RW or DVD-RW, or even a USB drive but they can also be used in Hyper-V, to create a virtual CD-ROM that can be used to install Haiku onto a virtual Hard Disk or even to just boot into Haiku directly.</description></item><item><title>VirtualBox Serial Debugging on Linux</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/guides/virtualizing/virtualbox-linux-debugging/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2013 15:30:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/guides/virtualizing/virtualbox-linux-debugging/</guid><description>This tutorial describes using a feature of VirtualBox that writes the output of a serial port into a file on the host machine. Because Haiku, by default, writes debug information to the COM1 port, you can use it to quickly extract stacktraces to text files, for example.
This tutorial is based on following tools:
Debian Wheezy VirtualBox 4.1.18 Haiku R1A4.1 It should also work on platforms other than Linux.</description></item><item><title>Virtualizing Haiku in Bochs</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/guides/virtualizing/bochs/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2013 06:28:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/guides/virtualizing/bochs/</guid><description>The required files can be found on the &amp;ldquo;Get Haiku&amp;rdquo; page of this website which is located here.Both the raw and anyboot images are available there, do select the closest mirror to enjoy higher transfer rates. Bochs is available for free on their website which can be found here.
Go to section: Running Haiku from a Raw or Anyboot image. Additional Steps. Troubleshooting. Running Haiku from a Raw or Anyboot image.</description></item><item><title>Virtualizing Haiku in VirtualBox</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/guides/virtualizing/virtualbox/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2011 16:46:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/guides/virtualizing/virtualbox/</guid><description>For Google Code-In 2017, Jakub Pajdowski created a video on how to install Haiku in VirtualBox [6 MiB].
Virtual instances of operating systems are perfect for all kinds of testing purposes that need to be done in a safe and isolated environment. Installing Haiku in a virtual machine is a solution for people who do not want to install it on their physical computers, but wish to become familiar with it.</description></item><item><title>Emulating Haiku in Bhyve</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/guides/virtualizing/bhyve/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/guides/virtualizing/bhyve/</guid><description>Virtual instances of operating systems are perfect for all kinds of testing purposes that need to be done in a safe and isolated environment. Installing Haiku in a virtual machine is a solution for people who do not want to install it on their physical computers, but wish to become familiar with it.
In this guide the Haiku operating system is being run under virtual circumstances using FreeBSD and Bhyve.</description></item><item><title>Emulating Haiku in Xen</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/guides/virtualizing/xen/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/guides/virtualizing/xen/</guid><description>Virtual instances of operating systems are perfect for all kinds of testing purposes that need to be done in a safe and isolated environment. Therefore, installing Haiku in a virtual machine is an ideal solution for people who do not want to install it on their physical computers but want to become familiar with it.
The guide was tested on an Ubuntu Linux installation, but it should work on any Linux distribution that supports Xen.</description></item><item><title>Emulating Haiku on Amazon Web Services</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/guides/virtualizing/aws/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/guides/virtualizing/aws/</guid><description>Amazon Web Services (or, in short, AWS) is one of the most prominent cloud computing platforms that&amp;rsquo;s widely used both by private individuals and businesses alike. Since booting directly from an ISO file is not possible, we will have to create an Amazon Machine Image (AMI) based on a virtual appliance.
Go to section Preparing for this tutorial Preparing the virtual disk image Preparing the environment Preparing the AMI Deploying the AMI on the AWS platform Preparing for this tutorial Disk files represent physical devices but in the form of a file.</description></item></channel></rss>