<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>hardware on Haiku Project</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/tags/hardware/</link><description>Recent content in hardware on Haiku Project</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>2001-2021 Haiku Inc.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 08:50:00 +0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.haiku-os.org/tags/hardware/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Haiku, Inc. sponsoring hardware purchases for RISC-V port</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2021-07-01_haiku_inc_sponsoring_hardware_purchases_for_risc_v_port/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 08:50:00 +0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2021-07-01_haiku_inc_sponsoring_hardware_purchases_for_risc_v_port/</guid><description>RISC-V is an interesting, relatively new and open source hardware platform. The inventors of RISC-V created a company called HiFive and that company recently released a desktop-class System on a Chip (SoC) board called HiFive Unmatched. Long before this release Haiku developer Alexander von Gluck (kallisti5) had pre-ordered this board and had begun work on the Haiku port to RISC-V, making some progress on the boot loader, u-boot support and memory mapping.</description></item><item><title>I'll Be Able To Start That Hardware For Open Source Catalog Soon</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/blog/michael_crawford/2008-11-01_ill_be_able_to_start_that_hardware_for_open_source_catalog_soon/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2008 11:04:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/blog/michael_crawford/2008-11-01_ill_be_able_to_start_that_hardware_for_open_source_catalog_soon/</guid><description>I have some happy news: I&amp;rsquo;ll be able to start coding the cheap hardware for Open Source catalog soon, I expect by the middle of the coming week.
For reasons of personal preferences as well as sharpening a salable job skill, I&amp;rsquo;ll be doing it in Python. I have a friend who is an expert web programmer who could advise me on the design of the database schema.
I will also start by reviewing the available Python code libraries to find components that I can reuse.</description></item><item><title>Cheap Hardware For Open Source Developers</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/blog/michael_crawford/2008-10-26_cheap_hardware_for_open_source_developers/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2008 12:47:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/blog/michael_crawford/2008-10-26_cheap_hardware_for_open_source_developers/</guid><description>Matt Zehner, a teacher at Branham High School in San Jose, sponsors the school&amp;rsquo;s SPARE e-Waste recycling program: Students Promoting Awareness of Recycling and the Environment.
Their focus is on putting discarded hardware back into productive use so it doesn&amp;rsquo;t enter the waste stream, as many electronic products are full of toxic materials like lead and arsenic.
His club was featured in the Cambrian Times&amp;rsquo; article Branham High School club masters art of turning trash into treasure.</description></item><item><title>Axel does not have a secret patch</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/blog/stippi/2007-08-12_axel_does_not_have_a_secret_patch/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2007 07:14:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/blog/stippi/2007-08-12_axel_does_not_have_a_secret_patch/</guid><description>&lt;p align="justify">
Whenever I was with Axel and saw Haiku running on his IBM ThinkPad T40p, I was almost convinced, that he must have forgotten to commit a rather effective patch, though he swore that that was not the case. I have never seen the app_server perform so well on any other machine.</description></item><item><title>The Attack Of The Warriors, Part 2: IO-Warrior24 - 16 Bit Multipurpose I/O Ports</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/documents/dev/the_attack_of_the_warriors_part_2_io_warrior24_16_bit_multipurpose_i_o_ports/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2006 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/documents/dev/the_attack_of_the_warriors_part_2_io_warrior24_16_bit_multipurpose_i_o_ports/</guid><description>BodyThe code discussed in this article can be found here.
The IO-Warrior24 device from Code Mercenaries is equipped with 16 general purpose I/O (input/output) pins. When enabling the so-called special mode functions, more or less pins are reassigned to serve a special purpose. You can select between:
I2C, IIC: a two-wire serial Inter-IC-Bus allowing connection to RAMs, EEPROMs, ADCs,DACs and a lot more. LCD: parallel communication with alphanumerics Liquid-Christal-Display units SPI: a four-wire serial Serial-Peripheral-Interface-Bus similar to I2C LED-Matrix: a serial communication bus to control LEDs in a multiplexed matrix configuration RC5IR: Infrared Remote control according to the RC5 code We&amp;#39;ll now examine this impressive manifold of functions step-by-step.</description></item><item><title>The Attack Of The Warriors, Part 1</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/documents/dev/the_attack_of_the_warriors_part_1/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2005 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/documents/dev/the_attack_of_the_warriors_part_1/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="field field-type-text field-field-body">
&lt;div class="field-items">
&lt;div class="field-item odd">
&lt;p>&lt;em>The code discussed in this article can be found &lt;a href="../../files/HaikuNewsletter57Article1Archive1.zip">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The warrior family MouseWarrior, KeyWarrior, JoyWarrior and IO-Warrior of the German company Code Mercenaries (&lt;a href="http://www.codemercs.com" title="www.codemercs.com">www.codemercs.com&lt;/a>) enables you to communicate with your PC via USB in a manifold way to various external devices. All members of the family are full USB V1.1/2.0 compliant, low speed devices using the HID 1.1 (Human Interface Device) device class. If you are missing the GeekPort - it&amp;#39;s back again.&lt;/p> &lt;p>Let&amp;#39;s start with a really simple device, the JoyWarrior24 A8-8 USB joystick controller.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>