<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Getting Involved on Haiku Project</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/community/getting-involved/</link><description>Recent content in Getting Involved on Haiku Project</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>2001-2021 Haiku Inc.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2009 22:15:56 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.haiku-os.org/community/getting-involved/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Promotion</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/community/getting-involved/promotion/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 15:16:45 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/community/getting-involved/promotion/</guid><description>Promotion is a crucial part of ensuring Haiku continues to grow. Without spreading the word, we cannot gain new users and volunteers.
The Haiku Promotion team The Haiku Promotion Team, in its second iteration (there used to be a Promotion Team but the team slowly languished due to its members becoming inactive in the Haiku community), aims to restart promotion efforts and revitalise Haiku in the process. The promotion team currently consists of:</description></item><item><title>Documenting</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/community/getting-involved/documenting/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2015 16:08:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/community/getting-involved/documenting/</guid><description>Documentation is one of the most critical, but overlooked areas of open source devlopment. This is true in respects of both developer documentation and end user documentation, which are both needed to make a project viable. Documentation for Haiku is published via a number of means, depending on its intended purpose and spans various subjects.
Check out the following areas where we need help our documentation:
The Haiku User Guide The ​Haiku User Guide is intended to help new users navigate the operating system; point out areas where Haiku differs from other desktop operating systems and to provide tutorials (called 'workshops') to power users so that they can use more advanced features of the operating system.</description></item><item><title>Testing</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/community/getting-involved/testing/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2015 18:12:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/community/getting-involved/testing/</guid><description>Haiku cannot be a stable platform without people trying to find bugs in it and telling the developers. Testing is a very important job. Luckily, testers do not need specialized skills, such as the ability to write code, but they do come in handy. All that is needed is sufficient familiarity with computers to be able to install Haiku. The job merely entails seeing what works and what doesn’t under Haiku, particularly with existing BeOS applications.</description></item><item><title>Designing</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/community/getting-involved/designing/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2015 17:18:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/community/getting-involved/designing/</guid><description>A person with experience in graphic design has potential to be a very great help in ensuring that Haiku looks good and presents itself well to the public. The areas of design which a skilled hand is needed by an open source project are varied, but the style used needs to remain true to the over all branding of the project.
The Haiku project needs UX/UI designers, graphic designers and all sorts of visual artists.</description></item></channel></rss>