<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Building Haiku on Haiku Project</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/guides/building/</link><description>Recent content in Building Haiku on Haiku Project</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>2001-2021 Haiku Inc.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2015 15:40:25 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.haiku-os.org/guides/building/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Compiling Haiku for RISCV64</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/guides/building/compiling-riscv64/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2020 10:18:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/guides/building/compiling-riscv64/</guid><description>Haiku can be compiled for devices using the RISC-V 64bit processor architecture. (RV64GC)
Unstable The state of the RISC-V port is early. Only the bootloader currently runs. Create a compiler toolchain Building the RISCV64 compiler toolchain is quite easy using Haiku&amp;rsquo;s configure tool.
For a complete list of flags for the configure script, see Haiku&amp;rsquo;s Configure Options
Perform a git clone haiku and buildtools Within the haiku source directory, create your workspace for RISCV64 via mkdir generated.</description></item><item><title>Compiling Haiku for SPARC</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/guides/building/compiling-sparc/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2020 10:18:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/guides/building/compiling-sparc/</guid><description>Haiku can be compiled for devices using the SPARC 64bit processor architecture.
Unstable The state of the SPARC port is early. Only the bootloader currently runs. Create a compiler toolchain Building the SPARC compiler toolchain is quite easy using Haiku&amp;rsquo;s configure tool.
For a complete list of flags for the configure script, see Haiku&amp;rsquo;s Configure Options
Perform a git clone haiku and buildtools Within the haiku source directory, create your workspace for SPARC via mkdir generated.</description></item><item><title>Compiling Haiku for PowerPC</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/guides/building/compiling-powerpc/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2013 02:45:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/guides/building/compiling-powerpc/</guid><description>PowerPC Compiler Toolset Building the PowerPC compiler toolset is quite easy and involves generating gcc binaries for your platform. For a complete list of flags for the configure script, see Haiku's Configure Options
From the haiku source directory, run the following. (be sure to adjust the options to match your build environment.) ./configure --cross-tools-source ../buildtools --build-cross-tools ppc
If you want to run configure again to tweak some more options, you need to tell it to configure for PowerPC.</description></item><item><title>Haiku Port Status</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/guides/building/port_status/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2012 14:13:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/guides/building/port_status/</guid><description>Haiku builds for several computer architectures, below is a list of each architecture with additional information. The interest column does not reflect any architecture preference by the Haiku project, only current real-world developer interest. x86 (Tier 1)The platform of choice for most traditional desktop and laptop computers PlatformInterestTargetHaiku LoaderHaiku KernelApplication ServerStatus 32-bit x86 PC (Compat)Highx86_gcc2Production 32-bit x86 PCHighx86Stable 64-bit x86 PCHighx86_64Production ARM (Tier 2)Newly revitalized line of processors excelling at low power consumption and low cost.</description></item><item><title>Compiling for x86_64</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/guides/building/compiling-x86_64/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2012 08:54:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/guides/building/compiling-x86_64/</guid><description>x86_64 Compiler Toolset Building the x86_64 compiler toolset is quite easy and involves generating GCC binaries for your platform. For a complete list of flags for the configure script, see Haiku&amp;rsquo;s Configure Options.
x86_64 exclusively uses gcc8, this differs from our 32-bit x86_gcc2 builds which include both gcc2 (for BeOS compatibility) and gcc8 as a secondary architecture.
From the Haiku source directory, run the following to compile the build tools (be sure to adjust the options to match your build environment):</description></item><item><title>Compiling Haiku for x86</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/guides/building/compiling-x86/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2012 15:36:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/guides/building/compiling-x86/</guid><description>gcc2h / gcc8 hybrid builds Haiku can be build as a hybrid image meaning that it contains gcc2 as well as gcc8 binaries. More information on this can be found on the gcc-hybrid page.
This configuration is the default and is required to run both BeOS legacy applications as well as modern one using the recent programming language features available in newer gcc versions.
Building Haiku from Haiku When building from Haiku, all the required tools are already installed in the release image, therefore you can run configure without any arguments:</description></item><item><title>Compiling Haiku for Arm</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/guides/building/compiling-arm/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2012 19:18:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/guides/building/compiling-arm/</guid><description>Haiku can be compiled for devices leveraging the ARMv7 or later processor architecture.
Unstable The state of the ARM port is extremely early. Roll up your sleeves and help out! Create a Compiler Toolchain Building the ARM compiler toolchain is quite easy using Haiku&amp;rsquo;s configure tool.
For a complete list of flags for the configure script, see Haiku&amp;rsquo;s Configure Options
Perform a git clone haiku and buildtools Within the haiku source directory, create your workspace for ARM via mkdir generated.</description></item><item><title>Get the Haiku Source Code / Pushing Patches to Haiku 101</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/guides/building/get-source-git/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2011 16:07:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/guides/building/get-source-git/</guid><description>Haiku&amp;rsquo;s source code is currently being hosted in a Git based repository with Gerrit code review. Anonymous access will allow anyone to download Haiku&amp;rsquo;s source code; However, the authenticated (non-anonymous) method is required for submitting patches.
Although most contributors tend to disclose their real names, we do not have a real name policy and a couple of contributors contribute to Haiku pseudonymously. That means that it&amp;rsquo;s possible for anyone to contribute.</description></item><item><title>Pre-requisite Software</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/guides/building/pre-reqs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2010 23:51:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/guides/building/pre-reqs/</guid><description>The tools you need to compile software for Haiku, or to compile Haiku itself, depend on the platform that you are using for building Haiku.
The Haiku operating system can be a very convenient development environment for working on Haiku, but using Haiku is not not strictly necessary. It may also not be practical to use Haiku in some very special cases, such as when writing some drivers - using a virtual machine to test your changes may be much more practical.</description></item><item><title>Haiku Hybrids</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/guides/building/gcc-hybrid/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2009 14:05:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/guides/building/gcc-hybrid/</guid><description>What is a Haiku Hybrid? Haiku hybrid images are Haiku releases which can compile and execute programs built for incompatible ABIs. This may mean different architectures like x86-64 and x86, or different, incompatible compilers like gcc2.95 and gcc8.x for x86. Currently only the latter case is supported. gcc2.95 gives Haiku binary compatibility with native legacy applications written for the BeOS. In a Haiku Hybrid, there is the primary GCC or architecture and the secondary GCC or architecture.</description></item><item><title>Creating an OptionalPackage</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/guides/building/optional-package/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2009 01:23:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/guides/building/optional-package/</guid><description>With the introduction of package management, optional packages - and therefore this page - became obsolete. This page details the steps in creating an OptionalPackage. In addition to being a regular binary distribution archive, an OptionPackage includes a plain text file called .OptionalPackageDescription and possibly the license file. NOTE: With the recent incorporation of package management, OptionalPackages are obsolete. Haiku package files (HPKG) replace them. See PackageManagement/BuildingPackages and HaikuPorter / BuildRecipes for instructions on creating HPKG's.</description></item><item><title>UserBuildConfig &amp; BuildProfiles</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/guides/building/userbuildconfig/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2009 01:19:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/guides/building/userbuildconfig/</guid><description>In addition to configure options, UserBuildConfig is another, very powerful opportunity for customizing your build. As of changeset [29161], Haiku's build system supports two locations for UserBuildConfig:
$(HAIKU_TOP)/build/jam/UserBuildConfig
$(HAIKU_TOP) refers to the top level of your local copy of the Git tree. If you use an external object directory, the UserBuildConfig at this location will apply to all of them. $(HAIKU_OUTPUT_DIR)/UserBuildConfig
Typically, $(HAIKU_OUTPUT_DIR) is $(HAIKU_TOP)/generated. However if you use an external object directory, then it UserBuildConfig is in that top-level directory.</description></item><item><title>Using Jam</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/guides/building/jam/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2009 18:01:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/guides/building/jam/</guid><description>Haiku uses a custom fork of Perforce's Jam. This mailing list thread helps to explain the decision to fork jam. As of August 2019, this is the current version. If a different version is reported, then you will need to build and install jam from source. jam -v Jam 2.5-haiku-20111222. OS=LINUX. Copyright 1993-2002 Christopher Seiwald.
Command Line Options Only some of the options are being discussed here. See jam -h for a full listing of available options.</description></item></channel></rss>