<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>What is Haiku? on Haiku Project</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/about/</link><description>Recent content in What is Haiku? on Haiku Project</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>2001-2021 Haiku Inc.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2009 21:27:31 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.haiku-os.org/about/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Trademark Policy</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/about/trademark_policy/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Aug 2010 18:34:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/about/trademark_policy/</guid><description>Haiku, Inc. owns the 'Haiku'&amp;reg; name, HAIKU logo&amp;reg;, HAIKU Background Leaf&amp;trade;, and HAIKU Leaf&amp;trade; (registered) trademarks. As an open source project, the name and brand that is associated with the Project is vital to the Project's reputation and the sense of familiarity that end-users expect from the Software. Anyone is able to freely use the code that comprises Haiku, however the trademarks of Haiku cannot freely be used in the same liberal manner.</description></item><item><title>Haiku, Inc.</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/about/haiku_inc/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2010 15:27:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/about/haiku_inc/</guid><description>Haiku, Inc. was founded in New York State's Division of Corporations as a Not-for-Profit Organization in July of 2003 by the founder, long time leader, and visionary of the Haiku Project, Michael Phipps. It is recognized by the IRS as a 501(c)(3) public charity, specifically as a Type C corporation pursuant to Section 201 of the Not-for-Profit Corporation Law. Here are the IRS letters of recognition of exempt status : initial, final In a single sentence the purpose of Haiku, Inc.</description></item><item><title>Project History</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/about/history/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2009 21:36:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/about/history/</guid><description>Here is a list of important milestones along the history of the Haiku project.
August 18, 2001: Project starts as OpenBeOS. This is the first OK, let's start message on the Haiku mailing list. April 2002: app_server prototype 5 was released. It was the first release that was able to render windows. June 2004: First WalterCon conference held in Columbus, Ohio. New project name Haiku is announced, and the new logo disclosed.</description></item><item><title>Haiku Movies</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/about/movies/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2009 21:34:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/about/movies/</guid><description>Here is a listing of Haiku movies on the web.
Haiku Rocks - WalterCon 2006 promotional video by DarkWyrm YouTube BitTorrent (MPEG, 54MB) Haiku-files.org (MPEG, 54MB) Haiku Tech Talk at Google - February 13, 2007 by Axel Dörfler, Bruno G. Albuquerque and Michael Phipps YouTube Haiku-files.org (DivX, 195MB) Haiku presentation at NUMERICA #1, France - March 10, 2007 by François Revol Archive.org (DivX, 795MB) FalterCon 2007 - Haiku at Picn*x - August 11, 2007 by Michael Summers and Urias McCullough, edited and produced by Phil Greenway YouTube Haiku-files.</description></item><item><title>General FAQ</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/about/faq/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2009 21:30:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/about/faq/</guid><description>Frequently Asked Questions Here are some Frequently Asked Questions about Haiku. For development related topics, please check out the Development FAQ.
Common Questions What is Haiku? Why isn&amp;rsquo;t it called HaikuOS? Where does the name Haiku come from? Is Haiku based on Linux? Why not Linux? Is Haiku then based on BeOS? I&amp;rsquo;ve never seen Haiku. What does it look like? Can I use Haiku as my primary Operating System?</description></item><item><title>Security</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/about/security/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2009 21:27:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/about/security/</guid><description>We take the security of our infrastructure and operating system seriously. Personal data is an important resource, and we want to ensure users can place their trust in Haiku.
Haiku Infrastructure Our infrastructure contains sensitive personal user data, and we aggressively keep this information private on a need-to-know basis at all times.
If you have discovered a vulnerability, CVE, or exploit that you believe puts user data at risk, please submit a detailed report to contact@haiku-inc.</description></item></channel></rss>