<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>survey on Haiku Project</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/tags/survey/</link><description>Recent content in survey on Haiku Project</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>2001-2021 Haiku Inc.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Mar 2021 19:54:14 +1100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.haiku-os.org/tags/survey/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Haiku Survey February/March 2021</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/blog/jt15s/2021-03-04_haiku_survey_februarymarch_2021/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Mar 2021 19:54:14 +1100</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/blog/jt15s/2021-03-04_haiku_survey_februarymarch_2021/</guid><description>Hi all, hope you are all having a great start to March! kallisti5 has put together a survey to help determine the priorities the Project should focus on for the immediate future. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t already, we would really appreciate if you filled out the survey - it is 100% anonymous and you do not have to enter any personal details. You can fill out the survey here.
Please do not hesitate to give your feedback on Haiku in the survey - your feedback can influence decisions we make in the future.</description></item><item><title>Results: S&amp;T Evaluation and Web Survey</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/blog/czeidler/2013-09-23_results_st_evaluation_and_web_survey/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2013 00:27:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/blog/czeidler/2013-09-23_results_st_evaluation_and_web_survey/</guid><description>Most work on my PhD thesis is done and I like to provide you with the results from our research at Uni Auckland on Stack &amp;amp; Tile. At BeGeistert 023 (October 2010) I conducted a user evaluation of Stack &amp;amp; Tile to answer the question whether stacking and tiling within an overlapping window manager bring any benefits to the user. At the end of last year I used a web survey to investigate if and how Stack &amp;amp; Tile is used by actual users.</description></item><item><title>Survey results in</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2011-08-20_survey_results/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2011 15:53:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2011-08-20_survey_results/</guid><description>
&lt;p>Last year Dr. Miroslav Stimac asked the Haiku community to participate in a survey to gauge interest in Haiku, usage pattern and wishes for the future, and obtain some general demographic data. This was part of his master thesis "&lt;i>The desktop operating system Haiku&lt;/i>" that can now be &lt;a href="http://www.cuvillier.de/flycms/de/html/30/-UickI3zKPS77f08=/Buchdetails.html">ordered as PDF or printed book&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Miroslav is so kind to provide chapter 6 with the survey and his analysis as a &lt;a href="../../files/Survey-Results-OS-Haiku.pdf">free download&lt;/a>. While naturally being quite technical at times, it offers some interesting numbers that may also become useful when considering strategies in the future. At last we now have some hard empirical data instead of vague feelings concerning size or interests of our community at this point of Haiku's evolution.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Survey about Haiku and BeOS</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2010-07-08_survey_about_haiku_and_beos/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2010 14:33:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2010-07-08_survey_about_haiku_and_beos/</guid><description>Miroslav Stimac, a part time student at the FernUniversitaet in Hagen, is writing a master thesis about Haiku and asks you to answer his survey at www.haiku-survey.com. The survey is relatively short, and should be answered in about two minutes.
The aggregated results of the survey are expected to be published in early 2011, so don&amp;rsquo;t hold your breath.</description></item></channel></rss>