<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>documentation on Haiku Project</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/tags/documentation/</link><description>Recent content in documentation on Haiku Project</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>2001-2021 Haiku Inc.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2018 22:37:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.haiku-os.org/tags/documentation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Application Patterns</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/development/apps-patterns/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2018 22:37:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/development/apps-patterns/</guid><description>There are several common patterns or approaches that you will use when developing Haiku native applications. These are listed below:
These tutorials were created by DarkWyrm unless otherwise stated.
Using the Layout API [PDF] - by waddlesplash Using attributes in your application [PDF] Using attributes in Queries[PDF] Monitoring the File System with the StorageKit [PDF] Registering a new file type [PDF] Using fonts [PDF] Creating a new UI Control [PDF] Using application scripting [PDF] Adding scripting to your applications [PDF] Enabling Drag &amp;amp; Drop [PDF] Exposing re-usable parts of your application with Replicants [PDF] Tutorial Project: Create a text editor [PDF]</description></item><item><title>Prepare for Publishing</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/development/apps-prepare/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2018 22:31:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/development/apps-prepare/</guid><description>The are many tasks you should look in to before publishing your new or latest application.
Translating your application using catkeys files Create an icon for your application</description></item><item><title>BeBook and Be Newsletters Available Online</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2008-03-21_bebook_and_be_newsletters_available_online/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2008 03:53:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2008-03-21_bebook_and_be_newsletters_available_online/</guid><description>It's been almost one year since we announced our conversations with ACCESS Co. Ltd. targeted at releasing legacy BeOS related documents, and today we are happy to inform the community that this project has finally arrived to a happy conclusion: the BeBook and all the Be Newsletters are now available online. As an emerging open source project, documentation for Haiku is still hard to come by; and while our Documentation Team works on creating Haiku-specific material, the BeBook and the Be Newsletters will provide valuable reference material for all developers, new and experienced alike.</description></item><item><title>Overview of Messaging in the Application Kit</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/blog/nielx/2007-07-15_overview_of_messaging_in_the_application_kit/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jul 2007 10:00:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/blog/nielx/2007-07-15_overview_of_messaging_in_the_application_kit/</guid><description>For the API Documentation team I&amp;rsquo;ve prepared an overview of the messaging functions in the Application Kit, mind map style. This image should be the guide to writing the actual API documentation.
Please redirect comments on the technical content to the haiku-development list. They are highly appreciated!</description></item><item><title>Documentation Team: Membership and Organisational Structure</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/documents/dev/documentation_team_membership_and_organisational_structure/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 May 2007 13:46:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/documents/dev/documentation_team_membership_and_organisational_structure/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="field field-type-text field-field-body">
&lt;div class="field-items">
&lt;div class="field-item odd">
&lt;p>This document outlines the team structure of the &lt;a href="../../about/teams/documentation">Documentation Team&lt;/a>. It will describe how the privileges and duties are distributed between the three main entities: Contributors, Members and the Coordinator. It will also describe how the advancement system works.&lt;p></description></item><item><title>Report on the API Documentation Team Meeting of May 19th 2007</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/blog/nielx/2007-05-19_report_on_the_api_documentation_team_meeting_of_may_19th_2007/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 May 2007 10:12:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/blog/nielx/2007-05-19_report_on_the_api_documentation_team_meeting_of_may_19th_2007/</guid><description>This is a report of the meeting of the API documentation team that was held on May 18th 2007 at 19:00 GMT on freenode.org in the #haiku-doc channel. The full IRC log is hosted by John Drinkwater. Here are some of the highlights for those that don't want to read the complete document. In this meeting people introduced themselves to the group. There was discussion on the working process, and it was decided to create a three phase working process and to start on the support kit.</description></item><item><title>ANNOUNCEMENT: First API Documentation Team Meeting</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/blog/nielx/2007-05-15_announcement_first_api_documentation_team_meeting/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2007 11:30:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/blog/nielx/2007-05-15_announcement_first_api_documentation_team_meeting/</guid><description>On Friday the 18th of May, 19:00 GMT (21:00 in Amsterdam, 20:00 in London), I'd like the documentation team to meet. This meeting is for all the people interested in the API documentation, whether or not you are actually planning on contributing or not. We would like to hear as much different opinions as possible.
The meeting will be on IRC, on freenode irc.freenode.net), in the channel #haiku-doc. This space is open for everyone.</description></item><item><title>Haiku Documentation Team How-To</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/documents/dev/haiku_documentation_team_how_to/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Apr 2007 23:58:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/documents/dev/haiku_documentation_team_how_to/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="field field-type-text field-field-body">
&lt;div class="field-items">
&lt;div class="field-item odd">
&lt;p>This how-to describes getting started with contributing to the Haiku documentation and the software you will need. The documentation team has a mailing list that can be found here:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Documentation Team Started and Seeks Help</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2007-04-18_documentation_team_started_and_seeks_help/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2007 17:30:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2007-04-18_documentation_team_started_and_seeks_help/</guid><description>With the release of the BeBook under the Creative Commons license, ACCESS Co. Ltd enables us to provide the potential developers of today with all the documentation of the BeOS API. But to ensure that API documentation will be available and up to date for the future generations of developers, the Haiku project announces a structured effort on the writing of the Haiku API documentation from scratch. The documentation team is small and young and any help would be very much appreciated.</description></item><item><title>A crash course in inline source code documentation with Doxygen</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/documents/dev/a_crash_course_in_inline_source_code_documentation_with_doxygen/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2002 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/documents/dev/a_crash_course_in_inline_source_code_documentation_with_doxygen/</guid><description>BodySo I&amp;#39;m sure a number of you out there were a bit skeptical as to whether or not I&amp;#39;d be able to churn out two Doxygen newsletter articles in a row (I sure didn&amp;#39;t think I&amp;#39;d manage :). Well, just to spite all of us non-believers, here I am with a shiny new tutorial on documenting your source code with Doxygen. The things I&amp;#39;m going to cover here are just the basic meat-and-potatoes parts of Doxygen that I use on a day to day basis; for anything else, please consult the online Doxygen manual; it&amp;#39;s really quite handy :).</description></item></channel></rss>