<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>sound on Haiku Project</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/tags/sound/</link><description>Recent content in sound on Haiku Project</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>2001-2021 Haiku Inc.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2020 12:00:00 +0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.haiku-os.org/tags/sound/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>System Sounds Contest Wrap-up</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2020-12-07-contest-results/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2020 12:00:00 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2020-12-07-contest-results/</guid><description>Contest for Haiku System Sounds is finally over; and ladies and gentlemen, we have a winner!
Before going into details, lots of thanks to all participants and voters are in order. Thanks to you, Haiku now has a cohesive high-quality sound set, that will hopefully make using Haiku even more pleasant and accessible.
Without further ado, the winner is Garrett Kabler, with the sound theme &amp;ldquo;grubs-sparkly-tones&amp;rdquo; (previously named as &amp;ldquo;burgs-sparkly-tones&amp;rdquo;, name changed by the author due to a possible identity mixup)!</description></item><item><title>Contest for System Sounds</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2020-09-11-system-sound-contest/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2020 13:00:00 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2020-09-11-system-sound-contest/</guid><description>UPDATE (2020/12/08): The contest has concluded. See this blog post for the results.
It wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be wrong to say that, Haiku is a unique operating system. It takes its roots from BeOS, the OS everyone envied back in the day. Haiku continues to follow its footsteps, trying to deliver that same experience. What could be better than complementing this unique operating system with a set of unique system sounds?
As R1 steadily approaches, we are looking for contestants (amateur, professional, enthusiast) to produce system sound effects for Haiku.</description></item></channel></rss>