<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="https://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Recent blog posts on Haiku Project</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/blog/</link><language>en-US</language><author>Haiku, Inc.</author><rights>(C) 2001-2021 Haiku, Inc. All rights reserved.</rights><updated>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 12:28:21 +1000</updated><item><title>Update #3 from the Promotion Team</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/blog/jt15s/2021-07-29_update_3_from_the_promotion_team/</link><author>jt15s</author><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 12:28:21 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/blog/jt15s/2021-07-29_update_3_from_the_promotion_team/</guid><description>&lt;p>Hello all! This is the third update from the Haiku Promotion Team.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="beta3-released">Beta3 Released&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>As you have noticed, Beta3 has been released! Huge shout out to kallisti5, who was the release coordinator for Beta3. Making a major release of Haiku is a daunting task to all involved!&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="new-team-members">New Team Members&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Since I last wrote in March this year, we welcomed the following members to the Team:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>animortis&lt;/li>
&lt;li>AlwaysLivid&lt;/li>
&lt;li>jeremyf&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="switching-to-ircmatrix">Switching to IRC/Matrix&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>It was brought to our attention that the way the Promotion Team communicated was not a very transparent one – we communicated through a group private message on the Haiku forums. Thus, the decision was made to switch to IRC/Matrix, because it is a trusted technology, and it can be accessed from all major platforms including Haiku. Now, anyone can see what we are discussing and working on and can participate in our discussions! If you wish to join, we have a discussion room at #haiku-promo on OFTC, with bridges to Matrix.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="promotion-team-kanban">Promotion Team Kanban&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We were also informed that our Kanban, quite paradoxically, did not work on Haiku. We are still considering options to switch, including trying out a solution from Atlassian, or using the existing Haiku development tracker. We will post on this blog once a decision has been made.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="social-media-accounts">Social Media Accounts&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>You may have seen that we have requested access to the Haiku Twitter and LinkedIn accounts. We believe that the accounts have become a lot like RSS feeds, which, is not inherently bad, but for an open-source project like ours with users and developers asking for help on social media platforms, we could do a lot better. We will keep you updated once the policies for the accounts have been finalised and we start posting on the accounts.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="haikus-20th-anniversary">Haiku’s 20th Anniversary&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Now that Beta3 is released, the next big event on the cards is our 20th Anniversary! If you go to the history page on this website, you can see that we started on the 18th of August 2001.
We will need someone to design 20th Anniversary graphics for us, so if you are up to the task, don’t hesitate to send me a PM on the forums or post in the IRC/Matrix room.
Currently, we have merchandise planned for this special occasion (we should have more news to share on that soon), but any ideas for events or other items for purchase are welcomed.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="looking-ahead-to-beta4">Looking ahead to Beta4&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>After Beta3, there will be Beta4. Why are we thinking of Beta4 so soon, you might ask? Well, the time after a major release is often a time when activity tends to slump for a bit. We want to keep that momentum going, so we are thinking of what we can do for the next major release.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We are considering putting on spotlight on many of Haiku’s built-in apps. Many of them have been neglected for years and need a developer’s TLC (tender, loving care). For example, the Mail app uses an older protocol, and the UI needs some improvement! To do this, we will put out Calls for Contributions, blog posts that let people know what needs work.&lt;br>
Additionally, there are many things that have been on our “wish list” for a while that need contributors. A single-sign-on system for all of Haiku’s web services (i.e., Trac, Gerrit, forums) is something that we have wanted for a long time. Furthermore, we still need to migrate from Pootle to another web translation service since Pootle is no longer maintained. We also need a major reorganisation of our website and documentation, as the organisation of our documentation is quite confusing. We will most likely put out Calls for Contributions for these, wherever applicable.&lt;br>
A tentative release date set on Trac is the 31st of January 2022. This is a tentative release date meaning that it is subject to change. Beta3 had the initial tentative date of sometime in April, however it was released on the 25th of July (or 26th depending on where you live in the world). It is the aim of the Haiku Project to have a major release at least once a year.&lt;br>
Additionally, there will be more tickets that will be assigned to Beta4; we have 688 active tickets in the R1 milestone so expect plenty more tickets to be added!
If you have anything you want to see in Beta4, a &lt;a href="https://discuss.haiku-os.org/t/beta-4-wishlist/11092">Beta4 wish list thread&lt;/a> has been started on the forums so feel free to post there.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="closing-words">Closing Words&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>As always, if you have any feedback or suggestions for the Promotion Team don’t hesitate to contact us via IRC/Matrix, or post in the forums under the Marketing category. Stay safe!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>GSOC 2021:Progress Report of Improvements to clang-format</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/blog/saloni/2021-07-27_gsoc_2021progress_report_of_improvements_to_clang-format/</link><author>saloni</author><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2021 12:17:53 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/blog/saloni/2021-07-27_gsoc_2021progress_report_of_improvements_to_clang-format/</guid><description>&lt;p>This blog will contain all the information about what I have done till now.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I started with the input preferences directory and started solving the issues according to haiku guidelines.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A few changes have been made to clang-format. This work takes a lot of time because it needs a complete understanding of how the llvm code works. As there was number of files, it was difficult to figure out which file should contain the solution of the problem but PulkoMandy really helps me alot.
While working on this project I learn new things which were really good!&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="preserve-the-indentation-of-comments">Preserve the indentation of comments&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In the Haiku coding style, comments are sometimes indented one level more than the code (when they refer to the line above them) but clang-format doesn’t accept these one level indented comments and change their indentation to previous line indentation&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> if (a)
 return ;
  // Comment to remain as it is
else {
 return;
}
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>So, this comment was previously getting equal to indentation of return statement. Then, I write some code which checks the indentation of previous line and compares with the original line and formats according.
&lt;a href="https://github.com/viveris/llvm-project/commit/b2338537b8699662efaa5b51f1cf1daf6ae28c0a">Please have a review&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After this I added a functionality that this code should only work when “haiku” is passed as argument because some people may not want that for their project.
&lt;a href="https://github.com/viveris/llvm-project/commit/05661e0e9937699753192b298f04ecc5c46206f9">Please have a review&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="removal-of-braces-for-multiline-control-statements">Removal of braces for multiline control statements&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>According to haiku guidelines, if there is single line control statement then the braces should be removed otherwise not.&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>if (acceptFirstClickBox) {
acceptFirstClick
= acceptFirstClickBox-&amp;gt;Value() == B_CONTROL_ON;
}
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>In the above case clang-format was removing the braces for such conditions. So, I got a &lt;a href="https://reviews.llvm.org/D95168">patchset&lt;/a> from llvm which I firstly set as the base code for this.
&lt;a href="https://github.com/viveris/llvm-project/commit/ca492a8015c091fccb4fd1cc6f910f2f1a48a99b">Base code &lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After that some changes were made and the redundant braces remover code was removed.
&lt;a href="https://github.com/viveris/llvm-project/commit/d69e542e38fb23c834cd96feac961498ff2c1cf4">Revert the redundant code&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After that finally, the final commit was made which removes the extra changes and sets the correct indentation mode matching with Haiku.
&lt;a href="https://github.com/viveris/llvm-project/commit/c5377b0c71dab755a2dc121f9e14b015d4a4d122">Please have a review&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="line-break-after-return-type-in-function-definitions">Line break after return type in function definitions&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Functions with one arguments were not properly detected. But the functions with no or more than one argument, code formatted correctly.&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>void
MouseView::MouseUp(BPoint) {
fButtons = 0;
Invalidate(_ButtonsRect());
fOldButtons = fButtons;
}
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>In this above example the clang format was not breaking after the return type with one argument but when I passed no or more than 1 argument it breaks correctly, This issue took alot of time as firstly I tried with different configuration but nothing works then I supposed that any function needs to be called for the break after return type but found nothing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then I tried with llvm latest code also but even then it doesn&amp;rsquo;t formatted correctly. After that, I came to know that this was a problem in llvm code and was mising this specific case. At,last I write the code for this specific case in the &lt;strong>isFunctionDeclarationName&lt;/strong> function.
&lt;a href="https://github.com/viveris/llvm-project/commit/f488bd9b43130e186cb0f86067f8d0a447b3f7b8">Please have review&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="ongoing-review">Ongoing review&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="unusual-indentation-of-blayoutbuilder-block">Unusual indentation of BLayoutBuilder block&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The block was getting formatted incorrectly&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code> BLayoutBuilder::Group&amp;lt;&amp;gt;(this, B_VERTICAL)
.AddGroup(B_HORIZONTAL)
.SetInsets(B_USE_WINDOW_SPACING, B_USE_WINDOW_SPACING,
B_USE_WINDOW_SPACING, 0)
.Add(fSettingsView)
.End()
.Add(new BSeparatorView(B_HORIZONTAL))
.AddGroup(B_HORIZONTAL)
.Add(fDefaultsButton)
.Add(fRevertButton)
.AddGlue()
.End();
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>The clang-format formats this block such that the indentation level of all these lines become equal which was against Haiku guidelines. So according to the community this block needs special handling. The options was:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Have some very specific code to detect the use of BLayoutBuilder and the specific indentation it needs&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Annotate the sourcecode with some comments to tell clang-format to not touch this part of the code.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>As the haiku code contains number of such block, so it will become messy to use &lt;strong>clang-format&lt;/strong> &lt;strong>off&lt;/strong>. So, I just proceed with first option.
As, I was not familiar with how the indentation of this block is to be done as differnt file was following different rule so, I planned a meeting with Preetpal in which she explains me the process for this block and I write some code for this which correctly indented this block even after giving any incorrect indentation.
&lt;a href="https://github.com/saloniig/llvm-project/commit/45d221cda510e9dba5bc1f1e94d21d1393caa59e">Please have a review&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then one issue remained unsolved in which the .SetInsets line was exceeding the column limit i.e. 80 according to Haiku guidelines. This line was not getting properly breaked and merged. After spending time with the code looking into this issue I found that when I changed this block LineComment block the block was getting formatted correctly as expected.
I looked into this to find such condition and change it according to the requirements but found nothing.
So, now I am working on this to write some code that will call required functions to format it correctly. I made some changes and write some code but it breaks at some point. I am looking for it and is working side by side on it.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="extra-space-before--operator-in-for-loop">Extra space before ++ operator in for loop&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>In for loop the extra space was added before the ++ operator.&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>for (itr = fMouseSettingsObject.begin(); itr != fMouseSettingsObject.end();
++itr)
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>Then, I take a look at files and see the configurations and made the changes for Haiku.
&lt;a href="https://github.com/saloniig/llvm-project/commit/8b7b1163109295afa7af86c19c4e338cbe8a7b89">Please have a review&lt;/a>
But the PulkoMandy suggested me that there can be much better option than this and suggested me to look into ContinuationIndentor.cpp file which will contain some function which is violating our defined options style configuration which were&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>UseTab set to &lt;strong>UT_Always&lt;/strong> so even if it tries to do alignment, it
should be using only tabs.
set bracket style to &lt;strong>BAS_DontAlign&lt;/strong> so it should not be aligning things this way.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>But we both look into it and tried to find appropriate function but till now got nothing. It’s a WIP task and working on that also.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="tabs-are-converted-into-spaces">Tabs are converted into spaces&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Output of Haiku-format is converting tabs into spaces :&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>
private:
BString fTitle;
BBitmap* fPrimaryIcon;
bool fSelected;
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;p>whereas the expected output is :&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>
private:
BString fTitle;
BBitmap* fPrimaryIcon;
bool fSelected;
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;p>The basic idea is :&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>indented 1 tab: qualifiers (volatile, virtual, static)
indented 3 tabs: type of fields and return type of functions
indented 2 tabs: function or field name
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>I have writted the code for it that need some changes which is under progress.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can find the sources on &lt;a href="https://github.com/viveris/llvm-project">Github&lt;/a> and my weekly blogs &lt;a href="https://hackace2.wordpress.com/category/gsoc/">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thankyou :)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>GSoC 2021 Progress Update 3: Coding style checker bot for Gerrit</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/blog/ritz/2021-07-21_gsoc_2021_progress_update_3_coding_style_checker_bot_for_gerrit/</link><author>ritz</author><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 17:55:41 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/blog/ritz/2021-07-21_gsoc_2021_progress_update_3_coding_style_checker_bot_for_gerrit/</guid><description>&lt;p>Tl;dr I have completed the bot with basic functionality for my local gerrit instance&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Link to &lt;a href="https://discuss.haiku-os.org/t/gsoc-2021-coding-style-checker-bot-for-gerrit-haiku-project/10772">Introductory blog&lt;/a>&lt;br>
Link to &lt;a href="https://discuss.haiku-os.org/t/gsoc-2021-progress-update-1-coding-style-checker-bot-for-gerrit-haiku-project/10814">Progress 1&lt;/a>&lt;br>
Link to &lt;a href="https://discuss.haiku-os.org/t/gsoc-2021-progress-update-2-coding-style-checker-bot-for-gerrit-haiku-project/10962">Progress 2&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As I have said before I divided my project in the following parts&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>For every event (change, patch etc.), trigger the Concourse CI pipeline.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Implement pipeline in concourse CI for fetching the Git repo and running the haiku-format tool on the relevant files and creating appropriate reports out of the tool.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Implement REST API call to post the result back to Gerrit reviews as a robot comment.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Since last time I started working on creating a report that could be displayed under patchset comments by the bot. I started by looking at various flags of &lt;code>clang-format&lt;/code> command out of which &lt;code>--dry-run&lt;/code>, &lt;code>--Werror&lt;/code> seemed to be working just fine. But I wanted to run the tool only on the files that have been updated/added since last commit and not the entire project. Eventually I found a better way for this i.e. &lt;code>git-clang-format&lt;/code> python script which is already present in the &lt;a href="https://github.com/viveris/llvm-project/blob/viv_haiku_format/clang/tools/clang-format/git-clang-format">llvm project&lt;/a>. After installing &lt;code>clang-format&lt;/code>, we just need to put this script in &lt;code>/usr/bin/&lt;/code> folder. We can invoke the script using &lt;code>git clang-format&lt;/code> directly. &lt;code>git clang-format --diff --style=haiku HEAD~1&lt;/code> would run &lt;code>clang-format&lt;/code> with haiku style on the files that have been updated/added since last commit and showcase the diff of it. In order to use this diff information later I dumped the output of the previous command in a file named &lt;code>diff.txt&lt;/code>. To use it in my concourse workflow, I added the &lt;code>git-clang-format&lt;/code> script on my local server that I created last time using golang to host the &lt;code>clang-format&lt;/code> file. Now this seemed rather promising so I went ahead onto the next task i.e. Implement REST API call to post the result back to Gerrit reviews as a robot comment.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Before starting GSoC, I had already achieved posting the comments on Gerrit using REST API. Anybody interested can look into &lt;a href="https://gerrit-review.googlesource.com/Documentation/config-robot-comments.html">https://gerrit-review.googlesource.com/Documentation/config-robot-comments.html&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://gerrit-review.googlesource.com/Documentation/rest-api-changes.html">https://gerrit-review.googlesource.com/Documentation/rest-api-changes.html&lt;/a> &lt;code>Set Review&lt;/code> Section&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The following is the API signature:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>POST /changes/{change-id}/revisions/{revision-id}/review
[HEADER]
- Authorization: 'Basic &amp;lt;Basic-Auth-Key&amp;gt;'
- Content-Type: application/json
[BODY]
{
&amp;quot;tag&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;test tag&amp;quot;,
&amp;quot;message&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;Hi! This is robot!&amp;quot;,
&amp;quot;labels&amp;quot;: {
&amp;quot;Verified&amp;quot;: 1
}
}
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>Now the url for calling the above API requires &lt;code>change-id&lt;/code> and &lt;code>revision-id&lt;/code>. After searching for it I found that &lt;code>change-id&lt;/code> and &lt;code>revision-id&lt;/code> are already stored in the &lt;code>.gerrit_version.json&lt;/code> file inside the container under the cloned repo folder which is created by the gerrit resource. Below is a sample &lt;code>.gerrit_version.json&lt;/code>&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>[
{
&amp;quot;change_id&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;test~master~I2a33f7448147f9aab068df24e4a31bb7f0e974f4&amp;quot;,
&amp;quot;revision&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;916609dc2d5f6d4a51bb6510fc37d4366efbae97&amp;quot;,
&amp;quot;created&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;2021-06-03T15:38:59Z&amp;quot;
}
]
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>Now I needed to parse &lt;code>change_id&lt;/code> and &lt;code>revision&lt;/code> from this json file so I used the &lt;code>jq&lt;/code> utility. I created the necessary commands for &lt;code>jq&lt;/code> and stored &lt;code>change_id&lt;/code> and &lt;code>revision&lt;/code> in the &lt;code>CHANGE_ID&lt;/code> and &lt;code>REVISION_ID&lt;/code> variable respectively. I then created a basic logic for assigning +1 to the &lt;code>verified&lt;/code> variable in case the files are formatted correctly according to haiku coding guidelines and -1 in case the files are not properly formatted. Then I constructed the necessary json input for the API.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I pulled up the curl command for calling the API from postman, added the variables created previously at necessary fields and added the entire curl command formed inside the pipeline.yml file. Now it was time for testing the pipeline so I ran a new build manually, everything seemed to be working perfectly except the fact that it would also print terminal color codes along with diff in the patchset comments (patchset comments in gerrit do not seem to support coloring text). After looking for various ways to remove it I settled with using &lt;code>git config color.diff false&lt;/code>. Now it was time for the final test.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First I created a new change set in my local gerrit that &lt;strong>added&lt;/strong> a new &lt;strong>unformatted&lt;/strong> .cpp file and everything worked perfectly. &lt;code>clang-format&lt;/code> ran only one file and gave &amp;ldquo;-1&amp;rdquo; in &amp;ldquo;Verified&amp;rdquo; in the patchset along with the diff in the comment.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then I added another change set in my local gerrit that &lt;strong>updated&lt;/strong> already existing .cpp to the &lt;strong>formatted&lt;/strong> one according to haiku guidelines. This time again everything worked perfectly and &lt;code>clang-format&lt;/code> ran only on this updated cpp file and did not report any issues, only &amp;ldquo;Verified&amp;rdquo; was changed to &amp;ldquo;+1&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The following pipeline.yml was used for it.&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>resource_types:
- name: gerrit
type: registry-image
source:
repository: docker.io/bluedocks/gerrit-resource
resources:
- name: test
type: gerrit
source:
url: &amp;quot;http://hrithik:8090&amp;quot;
query: &amp;quot;status:open project:test&amp;quot;
jobs:
- name: job
public: true
plan:
- get: test
trigger: true
- task: check_coding_style
config:
inputs:
- name: test
platform: linux
image_resource:
type: registry-image
source:
repository: ubuntu
tag: 20.04
run:
path: /bin/sh
args:
- -c
- |
apt update &amp;amp;&amp;amp; apt install -y wget curl jq python3 git python-is-python3
# setup clang-format and git-clang-format
wget http://hrithik:9000//clang-format
wget http://hrithik:9000//git-clang-format
chmod 777 ./clang-format
chmod 777 ./git-clang-format
mv ./clang-format /usr/bin
mv ./git-clang-format /usr/bin
cd ./test
git config color.diff false
git clang-format --diff --style=haiku -q HEAD~1 &amp;gt; diff.txt
cat diff.txt
# check if diff.txt is empty or not and set verified
if [ -s diff.txt ]
then
verified=-1
else
verified=1
fi
echo &amp;quot;verified: $verified&amp;quot;
BASE_URL=http://hrithik:8090
CHANGE_ID=$(jq -r '.change_id' ./.gerrit_version.json)
REVISION_ID=$(jq -r '.revision' ./.gerrit_version.json)
TOKEN=Y2hlY2tlcmJvdDpnUlBONXdQQ0tVOTIxTUNzNitBc1dXclNSYzd4Mm9wWlNXNzNtYTRUOFE=
jq --null-input -M --rawfile message diff.txt --arg verified $verified \
'{
&amp;quot;tag&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;test tag&amp;quot;,
&amp;quot;message&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;```\n\($message)\n```&amp;quot;,
&amp;quot;labels&amp;quot;: {
&amp;quot;Verified&amp;quot;: $verified
}
}' &amp;gt; data.json
curl --location --request POST &amp;quot;${BASE_URL}/a/changes/${CHANGE_ID}/revisions/${REVISION_ID}/review&amp;quot; \
--header &amp;quot;Authorization: Basic ${TOKEN}&amp;quot; \
--header 'Content-Type: application/json' \
--data-binary '@data.json'
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>So end to end everything is working well on my local machine :)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now my main focus would be on integrating my work in haiku infrastructure.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As always suggestions and ideas are welcome.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Haiku activity report - June 2021</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/blog/pulkomandy/2021-07-10-haiku_activity_report_june_2021/</link><author>pulkomandy</author><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 08:53:07 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/blog/pulkomandy/2021-07-10-haiku_activity_report_june_2021/</guid><description>&lt;p>Hello, it&amp;rsquo;s time for the June activity report! (yes, not much innovation in the
tagline for these reports lately. I&amp;rsquo;m out of ideas, or maybe just lazy to find new ones).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Before we dig into the report, two important announcements (in case you are not
following the other news on the website, since both were already announced separately).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The beta 3 release process is going well, and there are some &lt;a href="https://discuss.haiku-os.org/t/haiku-r1-beta3-test-candidate-2-availability/10980/26"> testing candidate images available for testing. If you have some time to install one of these and
see if everything is running fine on your hardware, that would be great!&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The second announcement is that Haiku Inc. recently funded RISC-V hardware for
two Haiku developers, X512 and kallisti5. They have both been working on the
RISC-V port and X512 got it booting to the desktop on virtual machines. The
next step is getting it to run on real hardware, and, as expected (if you already
have done similar things), the virtual and real hardware don&amp;rsquo;t behave in exactly
the same way. Anyway, you can find progress reports on the forums if you want to
know more about the low level details of this.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Of course, this hardware sponsoring would not be possible without the donations
and sponsoring from the community. Thanks to everyone who made this possible!
See &lt;a href="../community/organization/funding/">our funding page&lt;/a> for more
information about ways to donate money to Haiku.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you are a Haiku developer or contributor, you can contact &lt;a href="https://haiku-inc.org">Haiku inc&lt;/a> for your
funding requests, it can be for buying some specific hardware, or negociating a
paid contract if that allows you to spend more time working on Haiku or related
things. You can also join our &lt;a href="https://liberapay.org/Haiku">Liberapay team&lt;/a>
to collect a part of the donations sent to the team, and make your Liberapay profile
more visible to donators if they want to target you directly. You need an invitation
to join the team, please contact one of the existing team members so they can invite you.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With that being said, let&amp;rsquo;s look at what happened in Haiku sourcecode this month!
Of course with the release announcement, everyone has been scrambling to get their
changes in at the last minute, so it has been a bit more busy than usual (this
is only my arbitrary and subjective perception of things, with no statistics to
back it).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This report covers revisions hrev55130-hrev55223.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3>POSIX compatibility&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The USER and GROUP variables (indicating the current user and group id) are now
set even for applications running outside of Terminal. This also fixes compatibility
with BeOS, which did this correctly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>korli modified the strace utility (which is used to log system calls made by an
application) to translate signal numbers to human readable names.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>He also added an implementation of ppoll, which is not yet part of the POSIX
standard, but will be added in the next version of it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>korli (definitely our POSIX person) also added some commonly present fields in
the rusage struct. While we already implemented all the fields required by POSIX,
several other UNIX systems implement a few more, and it&amp;rsquo;s very common that applications
will try to use these without testing if they are available. This results in annoying
build failures and requires custom patches. Currently, the new fields are always set
to 0, the plan is to implement some of them later. Even if this is not required by
POSIX, and potentially misleading, it seems a good idea to introduce all the fields
at the same time, so we only introduce one new version of the rusage structure, saving
us some complications in providing binary compatibility with previous applications.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>He also added the &lt;strong>STDC_NO_THREADS&lt;/strong> define to our header files since we don&amp;rsquo;t
currently have support for C11 native threads.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>madmax fixed the behavior of the confstr function in some edge cases, improving
the behavior of the getconf command line utility.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3>Font rendering and text management&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>madmax has fixed several issues with font rendering. First, he fixed font metrics
for bitmap fonts (which are rendered using fixed bitmaps, rather than vector
graphics).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>John Scipione largely reworked the code of BTextView to compute the text position
in the view. Mainly this avoids a problem in Tracker where the text would sometimes
be completely outside the view when trying to rename an icon.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PulkoMandy added the Noto Emoji font to the font fallback system, providing some
more of the missing characters commonly used in text and websites.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3>Drivers&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>kallisti5 fixed some problems in the XHCI (USB3) driver, making it better at
recovering from error situations.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>rudolfc made a lot of progress on the Intel video card driver, improving support
for VGA, DVI and HDMI output on SandyBridge and IvyBridge systems, which was not
really working before. DisplayPort is also working on some devices already, but
may need a little more testing. This work also enables some machines to drive two displays, in clone
mode so far. Many parts of the driver were reworked to allow for this, and it
opens for support of more modern cards later on, as well as maybe more work on
actual dual screen (not cloned) support (but let&amp;rsquo;s not get ahead of ourselves).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>mmu_man extended the &amp;ldquo;poke&amp;rdquo; driver to allow opening by multiple applications at
the same time, and to set the IOPL flag when the device is opened. This driver
allows any application to perform I/O access. It previously allowed that only
through dedicated ioctl system calls, but with the IOPL flag, it also enables
applications to directly use the IN and OUT assembler instructions on x86 CPUs.
This is similar to the equivalent driver in FreeBSD and can be used to port tools
like Flashrom, which requires such low level access to handle some devices.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The wavelan wifi driver is now completely removed. This driver was ported from
FreeBSD, and the FreeBSD version was removed in FreeBSD 13. After some investigation,
it seems this driver supports only very old hardware that couldn&amp;rsquo;t connect to
WPA Wifi networks, so, it seems a bit useless in the modern days. There was no
reason to keep it up to date.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>korli added suppot for controlling the keyboard backlight on asus laptops.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>korli disabled the intel pstates (power saving/CPU idling) driver for Atom Silvermont
and Airmont CPUs, which are not compatible with the way the driver works currently,
resulting in unbootable systems.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PulkoMandy reworked the SDHCI (SD cards) driver which could in some cases try
to send a command to the hardware before the previous one was completed, resulting
in de-synchronization between the driver and the hardware, and the OS waiting forever
for a reply from the hardware. While the driver is still not working perfectly
with all hardware, at least it should now not freeze the system.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3>Kernel&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>korli fixed some permission flags on x86 processors related to handling of
signals, I/O access, and disallowing user threads to enable or disable interrupts.
This allows DosBox to run correctly (it unintentionally disabled interrupts, which
led to kernel panics later on). Besides this fix specific to DosBox, this led
to some other changes in related areas after studying what other OS are doing
there.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>korli also improved the C++ demangler in the kernel debugger to handle some more
cases, allowing to get readable information from C++ symbol names in kenrel
panic backtraces.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3>Non-X86 architectures&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Work continues on merging X512 RISC-V work in Haiku. This month, we merged some
parts of the virtio driver rework, updates to the uname command to report the
new CPU architecture, various initial patches to the kernel headers, addition
of the RISC-V architecture to our ELF handling code, implementation of the
system_info function, data alignment problems in the AHCI (SATA) driver, and
made the classic ATI driver (for mach64 cards) work outside of x86 platforms,
so he could use it with QEMU emulating a RISC-V machine (a combination that
may be a bit unlikely on real hardware).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Han Pengfei continues the work on the ARM port. Starting with fixing some build
failures due to a change in the kernel console font (also used by the ARM
bootloader when there is no hardware textmode available and only a framebuffer).
He also rewrote the ARM linker script using the RISC-V one as a base, which
fixed some issues with the early initialization of Haiku. Now we finally have
some output on the UART port, making it much easier to debug the next issues
without being completely in the dark.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3>bootloader&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The EFI loader now always include support for GPT partitions. Previously, this
support was only enabled for x86 systems (and the bootloader was not running on
anything else), but with the progress on RISC-V, kallisti5 could now find and
fix the problem.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>X512 added support for the J and K keys to navigate up and down in the bootloader
menu. This is useful on platforms where the BIOS (or equivalent firmware) does
not provide a keyboard driver good enough to use the arrow keys.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>kallisti5 packaged a copy of the EFI bootloader file in the system partition.
This makes it a bit easier to find it when preparing an EFI machine for booting
Haiku (previously it had to be copied from the EFI partition which is not mounted
by default). Later on this can be used to automatically update the bootloader,
whereas this currently needs to be done manually.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>jessicah, kallisti5 and beaglejoe (almost a new contributor, they had submitted another patch in February but had not been properly greeted then, so, welcome!) reworked the enumeration of available boot partitions in the EFI
bootloader, which in some cases would find several partitions, but not manage
to decide which one to boot from. This was a long running problem and in fact
pre-dates the beta 2 release. tqh was also involved previously in reworking
various parts of the code to simplify it, and these last few commits completed
the work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>jessicah also modified the bootloader to always put the bootsplash icons at the same
position. Before this change, the official bootloader (with the Haiku logo) and
test builds (not using the logo) would align the icons differently. When using
mismatched kernels and bootloaders, this would result in a glitch with misaligned
icons. Not anymore!&lt;/p>
&lt;h3>File Systems&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The ongoing GSoC project about XFS is going well, and finally all the remaning
patches from the previous years have been finalized and merged. The next phase
of the GSoC project will be on doing new development on access to filesystem
attributes, and then start the work on write support.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>korli fixed handling of inodes with &amp;ldquo;metadata checksum&amp;rdquo; in the ext2/3/4 filesystem.
These inodes have a checksum covering more bytes than is the default in ext2.
The implementation in Haiku didn&amp;rsquo;t agree with the Linux one on how much data should be used.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3>Applications and user interface&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Jessica Tallon made her first contributions (welcome!) with automatic resizing
of the HaikuDepot screenshot window to always match the screenshot size, and
also added support for playing webradios from m3u playlists in MediaPlayer.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>madmax fixed the scrolling of large menus that don&amp;rsquo;t fit on screen, as well
as computation of the width of items in the menus.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>korli fixed TextSearch to not attempt to open directories as files and search
for text in them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>nielx fixed problems with the recently added i18n (language translation) support
in the Cortex application (which is a bit specific because it reuses some strings
many times from different add-ons, and we didn&amp;rsquo;t want translators to re-translate
them multiple times).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>CodeForEvolution added an animated icon to the shutdown dialog when waiting for
applications to terminate. This was one of the nice little details from the BeOS
user interface that had been missing in Haiku for a long time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>apl-haiku continues his work on HaikuDepot, and moved several tasks to background
threads, to provide a more smooth running experience to users.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3>Documentation&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>John Scipione updated the documentation for BTextView with a general class overview.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>AlwaysLivid updated the README to include a &amp;ldquo;getting involved&amp;rdquo; link. This is part
of a much larger ongoing work to completely reorganize the website and more clearly
separate user oriented and developer oriented documentation, to facilitate onboarding
of both new users and new developers.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3>Sourcecode cleanup&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>mt continues his work on running Haiku code through various static analyzers to
find and fix problems. This month the work includes removing some &amp;ldquo;set but never
used&amp;rdquo; variables, fixing some printf format strings, and correcting invalid
ASSERT calls in the gutenprint printer driver. He also fixed the
build in DEBUG mode for the new libnetservices library (providing an updated version
of our HTTP APIs).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>AlwaysLivid removed a copy of the libunwind code that had been added to Haiku but
never used for anything.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>David Sebek (another new contributor, welcome!) fixed some format string problems
in devfs when built in debug mode. This is part of a larger patch series to fix
&amp;ldquo;trim&amp;rdquo; support on SATA disks, the other parts are still being reviewed on Gerrit.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3>Media&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>PulkoMandy reverted an old change that broke listing of audio and video formats
in the Media Kit. This restored support for Youtube video playbacks (and unfortunately,
it is still possible to crash app_server by playing a video in Youtube).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>mt modified the cddb lookup tool (which allows to get album and track names online
for audio CDs) to point to a new online database, since the previously used freedb
is now offline.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>CodeForEvolution added MIME types for Markdown files and fixed some other minor
issues in the MIME database.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3>Buildsystem&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The usual work around a new release was done by kallisti5 (the release manager for the
upcoming beta3 release): updating the version reported in our system headers,
increasing the release image size to fit everything in, and switching our
package repositories to a new, less confusing identifier. Historically, repositories
were identified by their URL, but this proved problematic when attempting to set
up repository mirrors. The identifier and URL had been separated before the
beta2 release, but, in order to provide a smooth upgrade path to beta1 users,
the distincion had not been put into full use yet, and the identifier was still
an HTTP URL. It is now instead a &amp;ldquo;tag:&amp;rdquo; URI, following IETF best practises on
the matter.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>jessicah replaced the use of mtools in building the EFI bootable images with our
own tool fatshell. This reduces our dependencies to uncommon 3rd party tools,
making Haiku easier to build on more platforms.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3>Networking&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>PulkoMandy fixed a bug in handling of HEAD requests and 204 responses in the HTTP
client. Both of these are special because the response has only headers and no
contents. The code was a bit confused about that and would return an error when
in fact, everything was fine. In particular, this made it impossible to load
some pages on the Gerrit code review tool, which is a bit annoying since that is
the main place where we handle patches and code review.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The web browser was finally updated to a more recent WebKit release. This was
made possible because the buildbots for creating haikuports packages are now
running a pre-release version of beta3. This was needed to build the latest versions
of WebKit, which rely on new APIs in the app_server not yet available in beta 2.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This new WebKit version has some known regressions, that will be fixed in a later
update (some are already fixed thanks to the work of jessicah, nephele and PulkoMandy
to investigate the problems, but one important issue remains with text sometimes
completely disappearing from webpages).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>GSoC 2021 Progress Update 2: Modernizing Cardie (Caya)</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/blog/jadedctrl/2021-07-09_gsoc_2021_progress_update_2_modernizing_cardie_caya/</link><author>jadedctrl</author><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 11:58:06 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/blog/jadedctrl/2021-07-09_gsoc_2021_progress_update_2_modernizing_cardie_caya/</guid><description>&lt;p>Looks like it&amp;rsquo;s time for me to clutter the blog again!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To start: Since the last update, Caya has been hard-forked and renamed to
&lt;a href="https://github.com/jadedctrl/cardie">&amp;ldquo;Cardie&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a> (short for &amp;ldquo;cardinal&amp;rdquo;),
which at least fits the &amp;ldquo;bird theme&amp;rdquo; of libpurple clients.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>… And the name&amp;rsquo;s fitting, since it&amp;rsquo;s now a fairly functional libpurple client.
:-)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../files/blog/jadedctrl/cardie-2.png">&lt;img style="max-width: 80%" src="../files/blog/jadedctrl/cardie-2.png" />&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="libpurple-support">libpurple support&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>There are a few features not implemented yet, which keeps it behind the XMPP
add-on in terms of functionality, but the core is there: Configuring
and managing accounts for any protocol, joining/creating/leaving rooms,
chatting, sending/receiving your own status, room invitations, managing roster,
purple-side chat commands, etc.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This means Cardie is now (at a base-level) usable for just about any protocol
that purple supports, even through third-party plugins.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Getting started on the add-on was a bit tricky, and it took a few days to
get things working― libpurple didn&amp;rsquo;t take too well to multiple instances
running simultaneously (as the other protocols do, in dedicated threads), and
symbols failed to load with the add-on― leading me to take a &lt;em>slightly&lt;/em>
different approach compared to the other add-ons: A background process runs in
parallel to Cardie when purple account(s) are used, and each account&amp;rsquo;s thread
exchanges messages with that process.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Aside from that, it&amp;rsquo;s gone fairly smoothly― libpurple&amp;rsquo;s pleasant to work with,
and the folks over at #pidgin are friendly and helpful.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="add-on-changes">Add-on changes&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>In add-on news that&amp;rsquo;s dyed something other than purple, I got together a
native IRC add-on within a day. It isn&amp;rsquo;t polished by any means, and was done
more as practice and proof of concept: Writing a protocol add-on really doesn&amp;rsquo;t
take that long. I&amp;rsquo;d recommend using libpurple&amp;rsquo;s IRC plugin if you can though,
it&amp;rsquo;s definitely more featureful― though in both cases, you might want to use
ZNC as a go-between, since SSL in both the native add-on and with libpurple
isn&amp;rsquo;t quite working yet.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As for more underlying changes to the add-on spec, protocol add-ons can now
specify custom chat commands, &amp;ldquo;templates&amp;rdquo; for certain parts of the GUI (for
contacts&amp;rsquo; &amp;ldquo;edit&amp;rdquo; window and room joining/creation), and custom items in the
user-list right-click menu. These are optional, only there if you need/want
the flexibility.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="ui-changes">UI changes&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>As far as general UI/functionality goes, user commands are now supported
(&amp;quot;/help&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;/kick&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;/ban&amp;rdquo;, etc), there is tab-completion for usernames,
time-stamps with messages, unique color per chat-user, roster management,
and the room list is now organized by associated account.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Finally, windows/dialogues with a &amp;ldquo;neutral&amp;rdquo; context have a drop-down menu where
the user can select the account they&amp;rsquo;d like to deal with― for example, you can
select the correct account in the &amp;ldquo;Join a room&amp;rdquo; window, among others― but in
contexts tied to a specific account (inviting someone to a room), the option is
unavailable.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="next-up">Next up&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>For the last phase of GSoC, I&amp;rsquo;m planning on finishing off the last few bits
unsupported by the purple add-on (getting SSL working foremost, remote logs,
user statuses, contact images, roster saving), and writing ports for a couple
plugins. (On that note, I&amp;rsquo;d like to thank Begasus for updating the
libpurple port and kindly reporting some compilation errors with Cardie!)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Aside from that, I&amp;rsquo;m going to focus on some well-needed polishing and bugfixing―
there are some usability/UI tweaks that especially need to happen, much of
which I&amp;rsquo;ve put into the
&lt;a href="https://github.com/JadedCtrl/Cardie/issues">issue tracker&lt;/a>. If there&amp;rsquo;s any
problems you notice, or anything you&amp;rsquo;d like to see, please pop it in.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cheers!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>GSoC 2021: XFS support progress update</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/blog/xiaojie/2021-07-06_gsoc_2021_xfs_support_progress_update/</link><author>xiaojie</author><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jul 2021 01:33:24 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/blog/xiaojie/2021-07-06_gsoc_2021_xfs_support_progress_update/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="xfs-project-progress">XFS project progress&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Hi, I am going to make a short summary of the XFS project work since last post.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Anyway, you can find my post named &lt;a href="https://discuss.haiku-os.org/t/gsoc-2021-project-xfs-support-progress/10790">&lt;em>&amp;lsquo;GSoC 2021 Project: XFS support progress&amp;rsquo;&lt;/em>&lt;/a> on the forum. It records part of the work. Of course, the most is on Gerrit. &lt;a href="https://review.haiku-os.org/q/topic:%22xfs%22+(status:open%20OR%20status:merged)">topic:&amp;ldquo;xfs&amp;rdquo; on Gerrit&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We could find all remaining patches are merged. But, by the way, not all problems. There is a problem leaving. To be honest, I just learned how to use GDB under linux to debug today&amp;hellip; I lack big project experience before so it is also new skills for me. Now I need to fix it soon and then move to next step quickly, if there is no other changes, it will be attributes read support. So it is also why I choose to write summary at this time. I need to continue my attempt afterwards.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Above is current state about XFS work progress. Then, let me review my work and study.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Before I turn to fix the problems on Gerrit. I send many emails to CruxBox. That&amp;rsquo;s not good. But I don&amp;rsquo;t know how to do my work at that time and just want to solve all problems at once. So I always want to find a perfect solution&amp;hellip;and ask many &amp;lsquo;strange&amp;rsquo; and not smart questions at that time, such as could we use smart pointers&amp;hellip; :P Anyway, thanks for CruxBox&amp;rsquo;s nice.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The turning point of the matter happened after CruxBox pushed a patch by himself. He made a start point for me. So I realized I should also do this. If I can fix all problems in one patch, it is good. If not, we could get it little by little. After that, we got several patches merged quickly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then about the code, except for some minor errors, in my view the mainly things can be said to be memory management and code reuse. For memory stuff, we chose to allocate it on heap and then use AutoDeleter/StackOrHeap to manage memory, since it can free memory automatically. For code reuse, in my mind, actually it is because XFS use B+Tree in different parts and there are always some methods are as same between them. So we got this problem. I just did it by review the code, and tried many times. I think it is also I got from CruxBox, just keep hacking.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then about XFS its own states on Haiku. From my view, it could be said like, now we can provide read support for XFS, incompletely. : (&lt;/p>
&lt;p>More details I will post on the forum after we arrived phase goals. What&amp;rsquo;s more, after we implement other part of read support basically, I guess we still need to find better way for tests. Now all our tests are based on images shared by CruxBox. Mainly for v4 linux kernel I think. So later we may need more check. I have prepared this will be a long-term job.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>GSoC 2021 Progress Update 2: Coding style checker bot for Gerrit</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/blog/ritz/2021-06-27_gsoc_2021_progress_update_2_coding_style_checker_bot_for_gerrit/</link><author>ritz</author><pubDate>Sun, 27 Jun 2021 14:50:01 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/blog/ritz/2021-06-27_gsoc_2021_progress_update_2_coding_style_checker_bot_for_gerrit/</guid><description>&lt;p>Link to &lt;a href="https://discuss.haiku-os.org/t/gsoc-2021-coding-style-checker-bot-for-gerrit-haiku-project/10772">Introductory blog&lt;/a>&lt;br>
Link to &lt;a href="https://discuss.haiku-os.org/t/gsoc-2021-progress-update-1-coding-style-checker-bot-for-gerrit-haiku-project/10814">Progress 1&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On my quest to finding a way to trigger my jobs anytime a commit happens in gerrit I was looking into &lt;a href="https://github.com/google/concourse-resources/tree/master/gerrit">this repo&lt;/a> and trying to make it work. I tried using it as a resource but it turns out either it&amp;rsquo;s not public anymore or it was deleted. Then I went through the list of forks in that repo and found &lt;a href="https://github.com/ecbaldwin/concourse-resources">this&lt;/a>. He claimed to have a base for a somewhat working resource after he made some changes. I cloned his repo and tried building the Dockerfile but it threw some errors. After struggling on it for quite some time and making some minor changes to the files I finally managed to build it and upload it to dockerhub. Then I tried using it as a resource but it failed to fetch my local gerrit repo. Also, the whole thing was written in go which was totally new to me so I started by learning &amp;ldquo;go&amp;rdquo; and after some time when I got the hang of it, I started the debugging phase.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First, I started with the idea of running the docker image manually in local, entering inside its shell and studying the behaviour of &lt;code>check&lt;/code> binary. I struggled a bit and had to look at the concourse documentation to learn about its I/O format. After studying, I created the necessary json input and provided it to &lt;code>check&lt;/code>. Unfortunately, it did not work, since my local gerrit url was not recognised. I found a &lt;code>--network=host&lt;/code> flag for docker run command which solves this issue and was able to get the desired output from the &lt;code>check&lt;/code>. So I concluded that the entire thing seems to be working perfectly when run manually on shell.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For reference &lt;code>check&lt;/code> input looks like this&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>{
&amp;quot;source&amp;quot;: {
&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;http://hrithik:8090/&amp;quot;,
&amp;quot;query&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;status:open project:test&amp;quot;
}
}
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>and &lt;code>check&lt;/code> output looks like this&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>[
{
&amp;quot;change_id&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;test~master~I2a33f7448147f9aab068df24e4a31bb7f0e974f4&amp;quot;,
&amp;quot;revision&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;916609dc2d5f6d4a51bb6510fc37d4366efbae97&amp;quot;,
&amp;quot;created&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;2021-06-03T15:38:59Z&amp;quot;
}
]
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>But still concourse was not fetching the repo, I read &lt;a href="https://github.com/concourse/registry-image-resource">this&lt;/a> and changed the type from &lt;code>docker-image&lt;/code> to &lt;code>repository-image&lt;/code> with full url of my docker hub image in my concourse pipeline YAML file. Along with this I had to put &lt;code>latest&lt;/code> tag during image push and update my docker image at dockerhub since it was giving manifest errors.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After all this struggle, finally it worked! :) I ran various experiments and it seems to be working perfectly i.e. triggering the job anytime a patchset is created. The Docker image can be found &lt;a href="https://hub.docker.com/r/bluedocks/gerrit-resource">here&lt;/a>. Below is my sample pipeline.yml I ran using it.&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>resource_types:
- name: gerrit
type: registry-image
source:
repository: docker.io/bluedocks/gerrit-resource
resources:
- name: test
type: gerrit
source:
url: &amp;quot;http://hrithik:8090&amp;quot;
query: &amp;quot;status:open project:test&amp;quot;
jobs:
- name: job
public: true
plan:
- get: test
trigger: true
- task: list_repo
config:
inputs:
- name: test
platform: linux
image_resource:
type: registry-image
source:
repository: busybox
run:
path: /bin/sh
args:
- -c
- |
ls -a test
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>While my mentors will be testing this docker image, I started working on the next phase of this project i.e. running haiku review tool with every job that gets triggered. For reference the basic parts in which I divided my project are given below:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>For every event (change, patch etc.), trigger the Concourse CI pipeline.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Implement pipeline in concourse CI for fetching the Git repo and running the haiku-format tool on the relevant files and create appropriate report out of the tool.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Implement REST API call to post the result back to Gerrit reviews as a robot comment.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Now in order to start working on haiku review tool I cloned this &lt;a href="https://github.com/viveris/llvm-project">repo&lt;/a> and as suggested by my mentor @suhel_mehta ran the necessary commands for building it. I used &lt;code>clang-format&lt;/code> binary on various C++ files and tried to familiarise myself with its working.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Since building haiku-review tool might take some time each time concourse is triggered, hence I created a simple server using golang to host the already built &lt;code>clang-format&lt;/code> binary file. Running the tool was an issue in alpine linux, so I had to use ubuntu linux as base docker image. Then I wrote the necessary commands required to run haiku-review tool in my pipeline.yml file and then ran the pipeline and it worked like a charm. Below is a sample pipeline.yml I ran using it.&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>resource_types:
- name: gerrit
type: registry-image
source:
repository: docker.io/bluedocks/gerrit-resource
resources:
- name: test
type: gerrit
source:
url: &amp;quot;http://hrithik:8090&amp;quot;
query: &amp;quot;status:open project:test&amp;quot;
jobs:
- name: job
public: true
plan:
- get: test
trigger: true
- task: haiku_review_tool
config:
inputs:
- name: test
platform: linux
image_resource:
type: registry-image
source:
repository: ubuntu
run:
path: /bin/sh
args:
- -c
- |
apt update &amp;amp;&amp;amp; apt install -y wget
wget http://hrithik:9000//clang-format
chmod 777 ./clang-format
./clang-format -style=haiku ./test/*.cpp
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;h2 id="suggestion-box">Suggestion Box:&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>These are couple of observations regarding haiku review tool&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>The llvm project is over a GB in size&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Building the clang-format tool takes some time&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>It doesn&amp;rsquo;t look like a good idea to clone llvm project and build it everytime the pipeline is triggered maybe we can provide prebuilt &lt;code>clang-format&lt;/code> hosted somewhere.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Also, I would like to hear from devs on what kind of report/analysis (by haiku review tool) will be helpful to present in the gerrit patchset comments (posted by robot)?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Translation Work Needed in Preparation for Beta 3</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/blog/jt15s/2021-06-08_translation_work_needed_in_preparation_for_beta_3/</link><author>jt15s</author><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 14:34:07 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/blog/jt15s/2021-06-08_translation_work_needed_in_preparation_for_beta_3/</guid><description>&lt;p>As we get closer to the release of Beta 3, it is important we ensure our translations are updated.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="current-state-of-translation-work">Current State of Translation Work&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>As of now, no new language has currently reached over 60% since Beta 2 was released last year.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Croatian translations are at 58%. &lt;strong>If no progress is made, this translation risks being removed from Beta 3!&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Korean, Hindi, Bulgarian, Czech and Norwegian were already under 60% in beta2 and are still under 60%, somewhere between 45% and 60% complete. &lt;strong>It would be really appreciated if these translations were made more complete so they can be included with the Beta 3 release.&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Languages that are already available on Pootle, but need a lot more work:
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Punjabi&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Slovenian&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Arabic (unfortunately this translation can’t be displayed due to lack of right-to-left text support in Haiku)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Serbian (both Latin and Cyrillic versions)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Macedonian&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Maori&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Low German&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Persian&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Na’vi&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="pootle">Pootle&lt;/h2>
&lt;div class="alert alert-info">&lt;p>&lt;strong>Translation Cut-off for Haiku&amp;#39;s User Interface&lt;/strong>&lt;br/>
The cut-off for interface translations on Pootle remains at 60%.
&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>All translators are encouraged to make an extra release-effort to bring their language as close as they can to 100%.&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>All language managers are urged to check and approve waiting submissions.&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="haiku-user-guide-translations">Haiku User Guide Translations&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;div class="alert alert-info">&lt;p>&lt;strong>Translation Cut-off for the Haiku User Guide&lt;/strong>&lt;br/>
The cut-off for User Guide translations on Pootle is higher at 80%.
&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
Since Beta 2, there have been a few changes here and there to the User Guide, so &lt;strong>languages that were about 100% translated back then will need a few updates to ensure they are fully translated for Beta 3.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-can-i-get-started-with-translation">How can I get started with translation?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>If you are &lt;strong>fluent&lt;/strong> in another language, &lt;strong>don&amp;rsquo;t hesitate to join in and help translate Haiku&lt;/strong>! By translating, you help us reach more people all over the world. To get started, read the following guides and follow the instructions provided:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://dev.haiku-os.org/wiki/i18n/GUI-Localization">User Interface Translation&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://dev.haiku-os.org/wiki/i18n/UserGuide">Haiku User Guide Translation&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Thanks to all those who have been working hard to ensure Haiku and its user guide are available for people all around the world!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>GSoC 2021 Progress Update 1: Modernizing Caya</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/blog/jadedctrl/2021-06-07_gsoc_2021_progress_update_1_modernizing_caya/</link><author>jadedctrl</author><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 09:19:49 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/blog/jadedctrl/2021-06-07_gsoc_2021_progress_update_1_modernizing_caya/</guid><description>&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s the end of the first GSoC period, so it&amp;rsquo;s about time I clutter the blog
again!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A good few changes have been made to Caya― most obviously support for
multi-user rooms and some UI changes. Multi-protocol add-ons are now supported,
the program is oriented around &amp;ldquo;Conversations&amp;rdquo; rather than &amp;ldquo;Contacts,&amp;rdquo; basic
moderation (kicking, banning, muting) works, etc.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The &lt;a href="https://github.com/JadedCtrl/Caya/blob/master/application/CayaProtocolMessages.h">protocol API&lt;/a>&amp;lsquo;s
expanded because of these general changes, and I don&amp;rsquo;t think it could be called
&amp;ldquo;stable&amp;rdquo; for another couple weeks at least― I still need to document it, and
some of the new additions might still be consolidated into others.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Anyway, it&amp;rsquo;s sometimes better to show than tell. Here&amp;rsquo;s before and after:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="../files/blog/jadedctrl/caya_og.png">&lt;img style="max-width: 80%" src="../files/blog/jadedctrl/caya_og.png" />&lt;/a>
&lt;br />&lt;br />
&lt;a href="../files/blog/jadedctrl/caya-1.png">&lt;img style="max-width: 80%" src="../files/blog/jadedctrl/caya-1.png" />&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>… could you tell I&amp;rsquo;m going for &amp;ldquo;Vision-esque?&amp;rdquo; :P&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m no UI designer, so any input&amp;rsquo;s greatly appreciated, really. Right now I&amp;rsquo;m
thinking on moving the &amp;ldquo;send&amp;rdquo; textbox to between the user-list and chat-list,
and giving each user a specific in-chat color. There should be a way of visually
marking a user as an arbitrary rank (moderator, admin, etc) in the user-list,
but I&amp;rsquo;m not sure that might be best done. Maybe custom text-prefixes (e.g., &amp;ldquo;@&amp;rdquo;
with IRC), or having a rank-based name-color…?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are a couple changes not shown in the screenshot, like displaying a user&amp;rsquo;s
status. When a chatroom member is marked &amp;ldquo;available,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;away,&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;offline,&amp;rdquo; the
color of their name in the user-list changes accordingly, from normal text color
to an increasingly lighter/darker tint.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, I think some good progress has been made, and I&amp;rsquo;m on track to get
started on the libpurple add-on. Caya is a good base to work with, and Gloox has
been surprisingly pleasant to work with.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Next up on the agenda, though, are changes that&amp;rsquo;ll give add-ons some much-needed
flexibility, as well as minor tweaks: Allowing protocols to define custom
commands/menu items for the room and user right-click menus, room creation with
custom slots dictated by protocol, room invitations, roster management, etc.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can find the sources on &lt;a href="https://github.com/jadedctrl/caya">Github&lt;/a>, and my
introductory post &lt;a href="../blog/jadedctrl/2021-05-18_gsoc_2021_project_modernizing_caya/">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cheers!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>GSoC 2021 Progress Update 1: Coding style checker bot for Gerrit</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/blog/ritz/2021-06-05_gsoc_2021_project_update_coding_style_checker_bot_for_gerrit/</link><author>ritz</author><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2021 19:46:42 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/blog/ritz/2021-06-05_gsoc_2021_project_update_coding_style_checker_bot_for_gerrit/</guid><description>&lt;p>Hey everyone! I am Hrithik (ritz), You can find about my project in my &lt;a href="https://discuss.haiku-os.org/t/gsoc-2021-coding-style-checker-bot-for-gerrit-haiku-project/10772">introductory blog&lt;/a>. Here&amp;rsquo;s what I have done so far.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I started by reading Concourse CI documentation in order to get myself familiarise with ci pipeline and various schema involved in it. I also looked at other resources provided by my mentors i.e. Suhel Mehta @suhel_mehta and Alexander von Gluck @kallisti5 . Below are some links if anyone wants to check out.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://concourse-ci.org/docs.html">CI Documentation&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://concourse-ci.org/examples.html">CI Examples&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://concoursetutorial.com/">Concourse tutorial by Stark &amp;amp; Wayne&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://blog.concourse-ci.org/introduction-to-task-inputs-and-outputs/">Blog on task inputs and outputs&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>After setting up Concourse CI and Gerrit instance locally, I started off by trying to implement a basic pipeline integrating both. So I created a test repo in gerrit and wrote a pipeline.yaml file for concourse having a simple job and tried to trigger it manually. Unfortunately I struggled to get the concourse clone the local gerrit repo and faced with errors. So I asked the same to concourse discord help channel and got to know that since concourse runs the job in a container it has a different meaning of &lt;code>localhost&lt;/code> in the url. So I changed the gerrit url in the gerrit.config file by replacing &lt;code>localhost&lt;/code> with my &lt;code>machine-name&lt;/code> and it started working!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My next target was to trigger the job automatically whenever a commit happens, so I added &lt;code>trigger:true&lt;/code> property in the get step.
I ran the whole thing only to later realise that it gets triggered everytime a merge happens in the master branch but not when a patchset towards master is created. I then looked more into how Gerrit works and got to know that commits get stored in &lt;code>refs/changes/&lt;/code> namespace which is created by Gerrit itself so the master never changes unless the commit gets merged hence it doesn&amp;rsquo;t get triggered whenever a patchset is created. Below is my pipeline.yml&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>resources:
- name: test
type: git
icon: github
source:
uri: &amp;quot;http://@hrithik:8090/test&amp;quot;
branch: master
jobs:
- name: job
public: true
plan:
- get: test
trigger: true
- get: commit
trigger: true
- task: hello
config:
inputs:
- name: test
platform: linux
image_resource:
type: registry-image
source:
repository: busybox
run:
path: cat
args: [&amp;quot;./test/help.txt&amp;quot;]
- task: bye
config:
platform: linux
image_resource:
type: registry-image
source:
repository: busybox
run:
path: echo
args: [&amp;quot;bye&amp;quot;]
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>I found this docker image on docker hub named &lt;a href="https://hub.docker.com/r/matbain/gerrit-resource">gerrit-resource&lt;/a> so I gave it a try and added it as my resource but it didn&amp;rsquo;t work either.&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>resource_types:
- name: gerrit
image:
type: docker-image
source:
repository: malston/gerrit-resource
resources:
- name: test
type: git
icon: github
source:
uri: &amp;quot;http://@hrithik:8090/test&amp;quot;
branch: master
resources:
- name: commit
type: gerrit
source:
uri: &amp;quot;http://@hrithik:8090/test&amp;quot;
branch: master
jobs:
- name: job
public: true
plan:
- get: test
trigger: true
- get: commit
trigger: true
- task: hello
config:
inputs:
- name: test
- name: commit
platform: linux
image_resource:
type: registry-image
source:
repository: busybox
run:
path: cat
args: [&amp;quot;./test/help.txt&amp;quot;]
- task: bye
config:
platform: linux
image_resource:
type: registry-image
source:
repository: busybox
run:
path: echo
args: [&amp;quot;bye&amp;quot;]
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>Right now I am looking into &lt;a href="https://github.com/google/concourse-resources/tree/master/gerrit">this resource&lt;/a>
It is starting to look like I might have to create a custom resource type myself if this doesn&amp;rsquo;t work out either.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Suggestions and ideas are always welcome :)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Haiku activity report - May 2021</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/blog/pulkomandy/2021-06-03-haiku_activity_report_may_2021/</link><author>pulkomandy</author><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 08:53:07 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/blog/pulkomandy/2021-06-03-haiku_activity_report_may_2021/</guid><description>&lt;p>Hello, it&amp;rsquo;s time for the May activity report!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Before starting the report, we would like to thank our donors for their donations. Your donations help us cover our expenses and help us reach our goal to hire people to work on Haiku full-time. We would also like to thank all the community for their countless hours of effort of implementing new features, triaging bugs, translating, supporting other users, and spreading the Haiku word all around.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This report covers revisions hrev55070-hrev55129.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3>Source code cleanup&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>mt is still hard at work fixing bugs found by various static analysis tools.
This month he fixed various format strings in userlandfs BeOS filesystem driver support, as well as a misaligned structure in cpu.h, and multiple definition of functions in various places.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>kallisti5 added some debug traces to the NFS4 filesystem driver to help investigate bug reports related to it.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3>Build system&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>extrowerk made some fixes to the configure script.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PulkoMandy updated the repository of packages used to build Haiku images. This is a mirror of some packages from the Haikuports repository, at fixed versions to avoid build breakages caused by too frequent haikuports updates.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>AlwaysLivid updated some of our example dockerfiles which show how to set up an environment for building Haiku or for cross-compiling applications from Linux.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3>User interface&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>nephele added a new method to BControlLook to get the scrollbar width. This will be used for example in HaikuWebKit, which draws its own scrollbars, to keep the size synchronized with native applications. Until now, this required having a real BScrollBar to compute the correct width.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The scrollbar width is adjusted according to the font size (as it already was), but now, different control look implementations can decide to have different rules for how wide a scrollbar should be.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>John Scipione is still working on improving our BTextView implementation, and made some changes to StyledEdit to fix some issues with the text area management there.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>nephele added a large font for the KDL console, which is enabled automatically on high resolution displays (more than 1080p) where the default font is likely to be too small. The new font is Spleen, an open source monospace bitmap font designed by Frederic Cambus.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3>System libraries and security&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>korli implemented stack protection support in Haiku (currently disabled by default, configurable at compile time). The idea of stack protection is to insert some markers in the stack, whenever a function is called. When the function exits, there is a check to make sure the marker was not overwritten.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This can catch some buffer overflow bugs (although it would be more helpful for this on architectures where the stack grows towards higher addresses), but is mostly used for detecting malicious code trying to inject itself into the system by exploiting bugs in a clever way.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>korli also fixed a case where we accidentally allow kernel to access userland memory, defeating the SMAP protection.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3>Preferences&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>PulkoMandy fixed a regression in Input preferences related to changes in the API for live detection of added and removed input devices.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Fredrik Modéen updated the Bluetooth preferences to store the settings in a BMessage instead of writing the raw data of a structure directly to disk. This makes it a lot easier to change the settings format later on.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3>C and POSIX compatibility&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>extrowerk fixed our features.h header to support C11 correctly. This header is used to hide some parts of our system libraries to provide strict conformance to C or POSIX APIs (providing none of the BSD or GNU extensions if strict mode is enabled). It also now handles enabling or disabling some functions that are specific to a given version of the C language.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>korli and PulkoMandy reworked the ioctl implementation to avoid undefined behavior related to the use of variadic arguments. The ioctl function is from POSIX and allows to configure file descriptors and communicate with drivers. The POSIX version gained extra arguments over time: initially it allowed to pass just an int, but then it was extended with some extra arguments. In other POSIX systems, it&amp;rsquo;s possible to know the number of arguments from the first integer argument. But in BeOS and in Haiku, a lot more freedom is left to driver as to how they use ioctls, and each driver is free to allocate values as it wants. As a result, we were always trying to get all possible arguments, even when they didn&amp;rsquo;t exist. This works on x86 CPUs due to the way they pass arguments, but could be a problem in other systems.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The new implementation of ioctl uses C++ or some tricks in C with structs and macros to implement the function without variadic arguments. As a result, the value of the unused parameters is forced to 0 now.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3>Networking&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>kallisti5 added more details about 10Gbps ethernet interfaces in ifconfig output. Now you can know which type of link you are using (there is a bit more choice there than for slower speed at the moment, hopefully things will become more standardized when 10GBps links become more popular).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>korli started updating Wifi drivers to FreeBSD 13. He also finished the work (started by A-star-ayush dusing a previous Google Summer of Code project) to implement TCP selective ACK. This should improve the performance of TCP, especially on lossy connections such as Wifi.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>korli also disabled the wavelanwifi driver (it only supports very old Wi-Fi cards, mostly PCMCIA ones which never worked in Haiku anyway), as well as the Firewire support (which has been incomplete for a very long time and is now unlikely to exist on modern hardware).&lt;/p>
&lt;h3>Package system&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>AGMS and PulkoMandy moved some work done on first boot of Haiku to compile time. This will make the first run of Haiku boot a little bit faster.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3>Other platforms ports&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>X512 has made major progress on RISC-V support, with Haiku fully running in TinyEMU (no actual RISC-V hardware is supported yet). This work is currently being submitted and reviewed on Gerrit, some of the first patches have already been merged.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This work resulted in cleanups in various places all around the system: removal of unneeded includes, conversion of code from C to C++, progress on virtio drivers which are heavily used by the emulator, etc.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The work from X512 also includes several other not obviously related fixes, such as simplifying the code in OpenTerminal, fixing of scripting in BTextView, and many other small fixes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PulkoMandy added the RISC-V logo to Pulse so it can properly show the results of this porting effort.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Han Pengfei fixed some issues with device tree initialization in the EFI bootloader, which will help with the ARM port and possibly the RISC-V port as well if it is used on UEFI platforms later.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>tqh is also helping on the ARM work and fixed some compiler warnings.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3>Drivers&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>An experimental driver for i2c input devices (mainly touchpads) was added but disabled by default. Unfortunately it doesn&amp;rsquo;t work reliably yet. This led to some refactoring of the existing USB HID input driver to separate the HID part. HID is a standard originally developed as part of USB for all sorts of input devices (keyboards, mouses, joysticks, tablets, &amp;hellip;) but it is now also used by I2C devices (embedded in laptops) as well as Bluetooth. So it made sense to have this code shared between the drivers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>kallisti5 fixed some bugs in the XHCI driver to improve error handling and recovery.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rudolfc is currently reworking the intel_extreme driver to finally support devices newer than Sandy Bridge. A small part of his work was already merged, but he is currently running a testing campaign with help of our forum users to validate some larger changes.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3>Wrap-up&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Last but not least, Máximo Castañeda (madmax) got commit access and officially joined the Haiku Developers Team. Welcome Máximo!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is it for May, folks. See you at the next report for June.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To support Haiku, please consider donating through our &lt;a href="https://www.haiku-inc.org/donate/">Submit A Donation&lt;/a> page, or check out our &lt;a href="https://liberapay.com/haiku.inc/">Liberapay&lt;/a> page to make a recurring donation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Registering your nickname for IRC</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/blog/humdinger/2021-05-26_registering_your_nickname_for_irc/</link><author>humdinger</author><pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 19:55:20 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/blog/humdinger/2021-05-26_registering_your_nickname_for_irc/</guid><description>&lt;p>We recently moved our IRC channels from Freenode to OFTC. I almost forgot to register my IRC nickname at the new service, and having just done that, I take the opportunity to describe how that&amp;rsquo;s done for my fellow - maybe newbie - IRC user.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="configure-vision">Configure Vision&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>First, you&amp;rsquo;ll have to configure Vision (or another IRC client) to connect to the OFTC network.&lt;br>
Enter the &lt;em>Network setup&lt;/em> and add a new network with the popup menu at the top. Fill in your personal details, including the desired nickname. You can add commands that are automatically executed when connecting to the network, like joining the #haiku channel and identifying/authenticating yourself, see further down.&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="../files/blog/humdinger/Vision_network_setup.png"/>
&lt;p>Now click on the &amp;ldquo;Change servers&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; button, add a new server, and enter the following settings:&lt;/p>
&lt;img src="../files/blog/humdinger/Vision_server_settings.png"/>
&lt;h3 id="registering-your-nickname">Registering your nickname&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>After connecting to the OFTC network, you&amp;rsquo;ll see if your nickname is already in use in the server&amp;rsquo;s welcome message. If so, you&amp;rsquo;ll have to find another nickname&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Otherwise, it&amp;rsquo;s time to register your nickname. That isn&amp;rsquo;t mandatory, but if you don&amp;rsquo;t, anyone can log on under that name and sully your reputation. :)&lt;br>
&amp;ldquo;Nickserv&amp;rdquo; is the IRC bot you have to address with all account related things.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;code>/msg Nickserv register&lt;/code> &lt;em>SuperSecretPassword YourEmailAddress&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>From now on it&amp;rsquo;s simply following the instructions in the Nickserv output:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Go to &lt;a href="https://services.oftc.net/">https://services.oftc.net/&lt;/a> and log in with your nickname and password.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Go to your &lt;em>Account&lt;/em> page and &lt;em>Verify&lt;/em> your account by doing the captcha there.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Back in Vision, do a &lt;code>/msg Nickserv indentify SuperSecretPassword&lt;/code> to authenticate yourself and follow it with &lt;code>/msg Nickserv checkverify&lt;/code> to make sure all went OK.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="identify-yourself-on-every-connect">Identify yourself on every connect&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To automatically identify yourself every time you connect to the OFTC network, put a &lt;code>/msg Nickserv indentify SuperSecretPassword&lt;/code> into the &lt;em>Automatically execute&lt;/em> text box under &lt;em>Network setup&lt;/em>. Best before joining your regular IRC channels (see first screenshot in this post).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>GSoC 2021: Coding style checker bot for Gerrit</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/blog/ritz/2021-05-22_gsoc_2021_coding_style_checker_bot_for_gerrit/</link><author>ritz</author><pubDate>Sat, 22 May 2021 20:31:22 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/blog/ritz/2021-05-22_gsoc_2021_coding_style_checker_bot_for_gerrit/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Hey everyone! I am Hrithik Kumar, a sophomore at National Institute of Technology Agartala, India majoring in Computer Science and Engineering (CSE). I am happy to say that I will be working on creating a &lt;strong>Coding style checker bot for Gerrit&lt;/strong> as part of the GSoC 2021 project. My mentors are Alexander von Gluck and Suhel Mehta.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>IRC nick: ritz&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Matrix: ritz (@ritzkr:matrix.org)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h1 id="project">Project&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Haiku has its own coding guidelines which describe how the code should be formatted. There is a tool (&lt;a href="https://github.com/owenca/haiku-format">haiku-format tool&lt;/a>) for reformatting or checking if code follows these guidelines, but it has to be compiled on the developer machine and then run manually. Now this is extra work but what if it could be automated! That&amp;rsquo;s what I&amp;rsquo;ll be working on this summer i.e. creating a Gerrit bot that would use haiku-format tool for checking whether the patch submitted follows the community guidelines of Haiku and post the report in the comments.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A high level architecture of this project will include the following steps:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>For every event (change, patch etc.), trigger the &lt;a href="https://ci.haiku-os.org/">Concourse CI&lt;/a> pipeline.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Implement pipeline in concourse CI for fetching the Git repo and running the haiku-format tool on the relevant files and create appropriate report out of the tool.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Implement REST API call to post the result back to Gerrit reviews as a robot comment.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>The problem with haiku-format tool is that it is a work under progress and cannot be trusted completely so it requires human intervention to make sure that the code follows the coding guidelines. Luckily another GSoCer this year is working on improving the haiku-format tool itself so if all goes well then hopefully the entire thing will get automated. Although I was already planning on working on improving the haiku-review tool after GSoC itself.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At last a big thank you to everyone and I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to working with this amazing community. :)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>GSoC 2021 Project: Modernizing Caya</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/blog/jadedctrl/2021-05-18_gsoc_2021_project_modernizing_caya/</link><author>jadedctrl</author><pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 09:46:10 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/blog/jadedctrl/2021-05-18_gsoc_2021_project_modernizing_caya/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Hi! I&amp;rsquo;m Jaidyn Levesque (jadedctrl on IRC and elsewhere), a 2nd year Computer
Science student. I&amp;rsquo;ve been using *nixes for several years now, and just
moved over to Haiku as my main OS a little over a year ago. I&amp;rsquo;m lucky enough to
be a mentee this summer, and I&amp;rsquo;m excited to get started!&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;h1 id="project">Project&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>My GSoC project is to modernize &lt;a href="https://github.com/Barrett17/Caya">Caya&lt;/a>, a
multi-protocol chat program. &amp;ldquo;Modernize&amp;rdquo; here means a couple different things:
General updates, multi-user chats, and libpurple support. Caya is oriented
around two-member chats, whose protocol is arbitrary, with protocol support
being done through add-ons. It hasn&amp;rsquo;t seen much activity in the past few years,
so my first goal is to get it running on modern Haiku. Afterwards, chats will be
abstracted to allow for multiple users, enabling protocols like IRC to be
implemented. The last goal, libpurple support, will involve writing a generic
libpurple protocol for Caya.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>libpurple is a multi-protocol chat library used by programs like
&lt;a href="https://pidgin.im/">Pidgin&lt;/a> and Finch (&lt;code>libpurple-finch&lt;/code> in ports). It has
varying degrees of support for several protocols that right now lack native
Haiku clients:
&lt;a href="https://github.com/matrix-org/purple-matrix/#readme">Matrix&lt;/a>,
&lt;a href="https://github.com/EionRobb/purple-discord/#readme">Discord&lt;/a>,
&lt;a href="https://github.com/dylex/slack-libpurple/">Slack&lt;/a>,
and &lt;a href="https://pidgin.im/plugins/?type=Protocol">others&lt;/a>. With a libpurple
addon, Caya should work as a native client for just about any of these
protocols in one fell swoop.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As a part of this effort, I&amp;rsquo;ll also be writing ports for some of these libpurple
add-ons. Right now Matrix and OMEMO (&lt;a href="https://github.com/gkdr/lurch">lurch&lt;/a>)
look like safe bets, being popularly used in libre communities, but I&amp;rsquo;d like to
work on what people would find most useful.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If all goes well, Caya should be a usable chat program by summer&amp;rsquo;s end. I&amp;rsquo;ll
make sure to add any updates to this article&amp;rsquo;s forum thread. Right now, you can
find the git repository &lt;a href="https://github.com/JadedCtrl/Caya">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cheers! :)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>GSOC 2021 : Improvements to clang-format and clang-tidy to format code according to haiku coding guidelines</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/blog/saloni/2021-05-20_gsoc_2021__improvements_to_clang-format_and_clang-tidy_to_format_code_according_to_haiku_coding_guidelines/</link><author>saloni</author><pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 18:54:26 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/blog/saloni/2021-05-20_gsoc_2021__improvements_to_clang-format_and_clang-tidy_to_format_code_according_to_haiku_coding_guidelines/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="introduction">Introduction:&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>I am Saloni B.Tech.(3rd year), Computer Science and Engineering(CSE) student of Guru Nanak Dev Engineering College, India. I have been selected for Google Summer of Code 2021 to work with Haiku on the project &lt;strong>Improvements to clang-format and clang-tidy to format code according to haiku coding guidelines&lt;/strong>. My mentors are Preetpal Kaur and Adrien Destugues.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="about-my-project">About my project:&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Haiku has its own coding standards which describe how the code should be formatted. &lt;a href="https://github.com/owenca/haiku-format">Haiku-format&lt;/a> is a tool that reformats code according to Haiku coding style but it is not giving desired results. So, we need to format the code such that when this code is run on &lt;a href="https://review.haiku-os.org/plugins/gitiles/haiku/+/refs/heads/master">Haiku&lt;/a> the coding style of code gets updated according to haiku guidelines, but it has to be compiled on the developer machine and then run manually.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The tool ' haiku-format ' is work in progress which can be used to check the format according to guidelines which will be integrated with concourse to automate the process of checking coding style.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="existing-problem-in-code-review">Existing problem in Code review:&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Haiku code review is done manually due to which there was some delay between the patch submission and the initial feedback. A lot of time is spent just on checking the code format due to which most review comments are only about code formatting and it becomes difficult for reviewers to focus on functionality of the patch.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="work-done-so-far">Work done so far&lt;/h1>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Solved an issue to remove extra spacing for &lt;a href="https://github.com/owenca/haiku-format/issues/17">std::nothrow&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://review.haiku-os.org/q/owner:saloniggoyal%2540gmail.com+is:merged">Gerrit merged changes&lt;/a> according to haiku guidelines.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://github.com/haiku/website/pull/489">Updates coding guidelines&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h1 id="ongoing-reviewdiscussion">Ongoing review/Discussion&lt;/h1>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://review.haiku-os.org/c/haiku/+/3827">Updates code according to haiku guidelines&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://review.haiku-os.org/c/haiku/+/3826">Improving haiku format&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://github.com/owenca/haiku-format/issues/23">Empty functions to inline&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://github.com/owenca/haiku-format/issues/18">&amp;rsquo; : ' should come on its own line and initializers in following lines&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://review.haiku-os.org/c/haiku/+/3826/1/src/preferences/input/InputMouse.cpp#145">Discussion about clang-tidy&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>According to Haiku’s requirement for if-else statement clang-tidy google-readability-braces-around-statements.ShortStatementLines with value &amp;lsquo;2&amp;rsquo; can be used i.e. adding braces to if statement will only trigger when there will be 2 or more lines. So, the idea is to extract the code from clang-tidy and integrate it in the clang-format for better results.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h1 id="conclusion">Conclusion:&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>First of all I say a big thank you to the haiku community for selecting me this year. I will try to give my best to make this project more successful. :)&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="important-links">Important Links:&lt;/h1>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://hackace2.wordpress.com/">Development logs&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://summerofcode.withgoogle.com/organizations/5689314786148352/">GSoC Link&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/19jQsWTde5_ca514YbIOxFb882BRB_B4dbkRZ5polIIU/edit?usp=sharing">Proposal&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Thankyou to all :)&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>