<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Community on Haiku Project</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/community/</link><description>Recent content in Community on Haiku Project</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>2001-2021 Haiku Inc.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2012 15:31:57 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.haiku-os.org/community/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Software Sites</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/community/software/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2017 09:28:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/community/software/</guid><description>Here's a list of sites providing 3rd party software for Haiku. Some offer a direct download of HPKG packages or zip archives, others have a repository which you can add to Haiku with the "Repositories" preference panel.
BeBytes - The BeOS Software Archive: A software archive like the old BeBits in BeOS times. BeSly Software Repo: A repository for Haiku software. Fat Elk Software: A repository Fat Elk's own and other 3rd party software.</description></item><item><title>Social Media</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/community/social-media/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2015 08:34:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/community/social-media/</guid><description>There are a number of ways you can keep up with news about Haiku and social media is one such way. Some social media accounts are official accounts as listed on this page, while others are recognized community groups which are run by the community - for the community. Official Accounts Official Twitter Account
Official Mastodon/GNU Social Account
Official YouTube Account
Official LinkedIn Account
Official OpenHub Account
Official Keybase Team</description></item><item><title>List of inactive mailing lists</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/community/ml-inactive/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2014 21:07:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/community/ml-inactive/</guid><description>App Server This list is to facilitate communication amongst developers working on the Haiku App Server.
Subscribe | Message archive Applications This is for the discussion of general purpose applications and preferences included in Haiku.
Subscribe | Message archive | RSS feed Bluetooth development This is a mailing list for handling all bluetooth related development under Haiku.
Subscribe | Message archive | RSS feed Data Translation This mailing list is for the discussion of topics related to the translation kit, such as the Translation API and data translators for images and text.</description></item><item><title>Haiku Distro Guidelines</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/community/guidelines_creating_haiku_distribution/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2009 21:58:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/community/guidelines_creating_haiku_distribution/</guid><description>The Haiku project believes that having one distribution (the one officially released by the project) is the best long term strategy to ensure success of the platform. Therefore anyone considering creating a new distribution should think long and hard before doing so. The project is very interested in working with anyone who feels they need a new distribution to add what they need to Haiku itself. Haiku distributions must comply to the following set of guidelines.</description></item><item><title>Community Links</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/community/links/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2009 21:45:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/community/links/</guid><description>Social Networking
Google Plus Community Group Facebook Community Group Linkedin Community Group Haiku Twitter Feed Here is a list of links to Haiku User Group (HUG) and third-party Haiku-related sites that make up the wider Haiku community ecosystem. See at the bottom of the page if you would like to have your Haiku-related site added to this page. BeSly: German BeOS, Haiku and ZETA knowledge base.</description></item><item><title>Mailing List Etiquette</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/community/ml-etiq/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2009 15:46:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/community/ml-etiq/</guid><description>As with many other FOSS mailing lists, we at Haiku hold ourselves to a few rules when posting to mailing lists. For now most of these are to ensure that all information is properly archived or to improve a message's readability. In the future this list may be expanded with additional detail. No Attachments Not only are attachments inconsiderate to low-bandwidth users, they fail to be preserved in the archives.</description></item></channel></rss>