<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>promotion on Haiku Project</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/tags/promotion/</link><description>Recent content in promotion on Haiku Project</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>2001-2021 Haiku Inc.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 12:28:21 +1000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.haiku-os.org/tags/promotion/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Update #3 from the Promotion Team</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/blog/jt15s/2021-07-29_update_3_from_the_promotion_team/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 12:28:21 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/blog/jt15s/2021-07-29_update_3_from_the_promotion_team/</guid><description>Hello all! This is the third update from the Haiku Promotion Team.
Beta3 Released As you have noticed, Beta3 has been released! Huge shout out to kallisti5, who was the release coordinator for Beta3. Making a major release of Haiku is a daunting task to all involved!
New Team Members Since I last wrote in March this year, we welcomed the following members to the Team:
animortis AlwaysLivid jeremyf Switching to IRC/Matrix It was brought to our attention that the way the Promotion Team communicated was not a very transparent one – we communicated through a group private message on the Haiku forums.</description></item><item><title>My First Week with Haiku</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/blog/animortis/2021-04-27_my_first_week_with_haiku/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2021 09:15:03 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/blog/animortis/2021-04-27_my_first_week_with_haiku/</guid><description>As you boot your first non-Windows, non-Unix system, you may have a moment when you wonder if this thing is going to work. It’s not from the same family of systems you’re used to: It’s Haiku, and it’s totally different and unique. The great part, though, is when it works better than you could’ve possibly imagined.
And when I sat down with Haiku last week, I knew I had something special.</description></item><item><title>Promotion</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/community/getting-involved/promotion/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 15:16:45 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/community/getting-involved/promotion/</guid><description>Promotion is a crucial part of ensuring Haiku continues to grow. Without spreading the word, we cannot gain new users and volunteers.
Whilst Haiku does have a Promotion Team, which you are more than welcome to join and can read more about here, here are some things you can do on your own as well.
What can I do to promote Haiku? Letting people know that you use Haiku can help more people discover the Project and decide whether they want to try the OS out.</description></item><item><title>Promotion Team</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/community/getting-involved/promotion/promotion-team/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 15:16:45 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/community/getting-involved/promotion/promotion-team/</guid><description>The Haiku Promotion team The Haiku Promotion Team, in its second iteration (there used to be a Promotion Team but the team slowly languished due to its members becoming inactive in the Haiku community), aims to restart promotion efforts and revitalise Haiku in the process. The promotion team currently consists of:
jt15s scott_puopolo18 stoltenberg shaka444 mrumbelow tthoms fox14 animortis AlwaysLivid jeremyf Quick Links Kanban Forums Marketing Category - contact the Promotion Team by posting in this forum category.</description></item><item><title>An Update from the Promotion Team</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/blog/jt15s/2021-03-22_an_update_from_the_promotion_team/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 16:08:47 +1100</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/blog/jt15s/2021-03-22_an_update_from_the_promotion_team/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s been almost three months since I posted about the Haiku Promotion Team, and the response to my initial post has been amazing and exceeded my expectations!
There are now six of us (excluding myself) on the Haiku Promotion Team:
scott_pupolo18 stoltenberg tthoms mbrumbelow shaka444 fox14 The Team communicates regularly through a private group chat on the Haiku forums, and stoltenberg has started up a kanban board, which you can view publicly here (Just ignore the login prompt that pops up once you open the kanban).</description></item><item><title>Hello from the Haiku Promotion 'Team'!</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/blog/jt15s/2020-12-31_hello_from_the_haiku_promotion_team/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 21:33:25 +1100</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/blog/jt15s/2020-12-31_hello_from_the_haiku_promotion_team/</guid><description>Hi there, I&amp;rsquo;m jt15s, a new Haiku community member! I&amp;rsquo;ve been following the project for a few years now since I stumbled upon an article about Haiku.
If you read the title (which I&amp;rsquo;m assuming you did), you’re probably going, &amp;ldquo;wait, we have a promotion team?&amp;rdquo; Well, yes, now we do. As an informal “team” of two (currently), we are super excited to share our plans to help promote Haiku and make more people aware of it.</description></item></channel></rss>