<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>contest on Haiku Project</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/tags/contest/</link><description>Recent content in contest on Haiku Project</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>2001-2021 Haiku Inc.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2020 12:00:00 +0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.haiku-os.org/tags/contest/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>System Sounds Contest Wrap-up</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2020-12-07-contest-results/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2020 12:00:00 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2020-12-07-contest-results/</guid><description>Contest for Haiku System Sounds is finally over; and ladies and gentlemen, we have a winner!
Before going into details, lots of thanks to all participants and voters are in order. Thanks to you, Haiku now has a cohesive high-quality sound set, that will hopefully make using Haiku even more pleasant and accessible.
Without further ado, the winner is Garrett Kabler, with the sound theme &amp;ldquo;grubs-sparkly-tones&amp;rdquo; (previously named as &amp;ldquo;burgs-sparkly-tones&amp;rdquo;, name changed by the author due to a possible identity mixup)!</description></item><item><title>Call for Wallpapers</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2020-10-04-wallpaper-contest/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2020 13:00:00 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2020-10-04-wallpaper-contest/</guid><description>One of the most common feedback that we receive is that Haiku needs some nice colourful wallpapers shipping with its releases. We definitely want to improve the current situation. And we need your help.
Haiku currently ships with only one (1) wallpaper, and it&amp;rsquo;s not a complete wallpaper per se, it&amp;rsquo;s just the Haiku logo positioned at fixed coordinates on the screen. To be fair, there is a reason we only use the Haiku logo as the default wallpaper; we want Haiku to be usable on systems that have memory as low as 256 MB, therefore each byte that we can spare counts.</description></item><item><title>Contest for System Sounds</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2020-09-11-system-sound-contest/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2020 13:00:00 +0300</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2020-09-11-system-sound-contest/</guid><description>UPDATE (2020/12/08): The contest has concluded. See this blog post for the results.
It wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be wrong to say that, Haiku is a unique operating system. It takes its roots from BeOS, the OS everyone envied back in the day. Haiku continues to follow its footsteps, trying to deliver that same experience. What could be better than complementing this unique operating system with a set of unique system sounds?
As R1 steadily approaches, we are looking for contestants (amateur, professional, enthusiast) to produce system sound effects for Haiku.</description></item><item><title>Icon Contest: And the Best Rated Icon Set Award goes to...</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2006-11-03_icon_contest_and_best_rated_icon_set_award_goes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2006 07:33:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2006-11-03_icon_contest_and_best_rated_icon_set_award_goes/</guid><description>Stippi's Icon Set The community has spoken, and as project leader Michael Phipps recently announced at WalterCon 2006, we have a winner for the Best Rated Icon Set Award: the honor goes to Stephan Assmus, for his Stippi icon set. Stippi came in first place with the highest average rating, closely followed in second place by the Honey, Zumi and Mc Clintock icon sets.
With the results of the open rating in hand, there is now work left towards creating the final icon guidelines.</description></item><item><title>Haiku Icon Contest: Time's up! Go Rate Them!</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2006-09-02_haiku_icon_contest_times_up_go_rate_them/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2006 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2006-09-02_haiku_icon_contest_times_up_go_rate_them/</guid><description>Time is up for the Haiku Icon Contest submissions, and it is now everybody&amp;#39;s chance to make their voice heard. Head over to the rating page, and tell us what you think about the fourteen gorgeous icon sets that were submitted to the contest. In the rating page you can view the icon sets side by side for comparison purposes, as well as preview each icon set on a virtual desktop.</description></item><item><title>Clarifying the Haiku Icon Contest</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2006-08-16_clarifying_the_haiku_icon_contest/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2006 22:18:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2006-08-16_clarifying_the_haiku_icon_contest/</guid><description>Since it appears that there may have been some confusion about the recently announced Haiku Icon Contest , we want to make a few clarifications in order to clear up any doubts about the contest.
The objective of the Haiku Icon Contest is to help develop design guidelines for the eventual creation of a full Haiku Icon Set. Just to give you an idea, the guidelines would look something like the Tango guidelines, but would be specific to Haiku.</description></item></channel></rss>