<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Daily Tasks on Haiku Project</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/guides/daily-tasks/</link><description>Recent content in Daily Tasks on Haiku Project</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>2001-2021 Haiku Inc.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2010 18:52:35 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.haiku-os.org/guides/daily-tasks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Updating and downgrading your system</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/guides/daily-tasks/updating-system/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2014 13:11:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/guides/daily-tasks/updating-system/</guid><description>With the introduction of package management you can now upgrade your system in place using the pkgman command. The update process is straightforward, requires an internet connection, and requires a single reboot. pkgman will handle obtaining the latest updates and applying them to your system.
Bleeding edge Warning: Bleeding edge updates may occasionally fail if major ABI updates have taken place since the last update was performed. While problems are rare, having backups is recommended before updating.</description></item><item><title>Disabling components of packages</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/guides/daily-tasks/blacklist-packages/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2014 20:47:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/guides/daily-tasks/blacklist-packages/</guid><description>With the advent of package management and hrev46391, it has become possible to prevent a packaged file from being extracted at boot time.
In Haiku's Boot Options menu, there is a 'Disable components' option available. However, this method will only let you disable components of system packages, and only until the next time you reboot.
As you may know, package management has made some Haiku folders practically read-only, so unlike in the past, it is no longer possible to just delete or rename a problematic driver or library.</description></item><item><title>Installing applications</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/guides/daily-tasks/install-applications/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2013 07:33:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/guides/daily-tasks/install-applications/</guid><description>With the advent of package management, there are now different ways to install an application.
1. A proper .hpkg package Either installed automatically via HaikuDepot or with pkgman in Terminal, e.g. WonderBrush, or downloaded off some site. When using HaikuDepot or pkgman, you're all set. If downloaded somewhere else, just move the .hpkg file into /system/packages/ and (in case of an application) it'll appear in /system/apps/.
2. An "old", self-contained archive Those come traditionally in form of a zipped up folder.</description></item><item><title>Network services</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/guides/daily-tasks/netservices/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 May 2010 15:29:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/guides/daily-tasks/netservices/</guid><description>The basic installation of Haiku contains several standard system network services including an FTP, Telnet, and SSH server.
Setting your user password A good first step is to set the password for your user account (default name is 'user'), in order to secure your system before opening it to the world. ~ passwd new password: repeat new password:
To access your Haiku system remotely, you will need to know its network address.</description></item><item><title>Accessing BFS outside of Haiku</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/guides/daily-tasks/access_bfs_with_fuse/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2010 23:56:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/guides/daily-tasks/access_bfs_with_fuse/</guid><description>Accessing BFS outside of Haiku What is FUSE? FUSE is an acronym for "Filesystem in USErspace" and in essence allows an operating system to communicate with a file system through a userland progam. By providing this functionality outside of kernel space, adding support for a new filesystem is a simple matter of installing the respective FUSE module. As a comparison, the typical paradigm involves altering the operating system's kernel to support the filesystem.</description></item></channel></rss>