<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>GSoC 2014 on Haiku Project</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/community/gsoc/2014/</link><description>Recent content in GSoC 2014 on Haiku Project</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>2001-2021 Haiku Inc.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.haiku-os.org/community/gsoc/2014/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Accepted Students</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/community/gsoc/2014/accepted-students/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2014 16:13:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/community/gsoc/2014/accepted-students/</guid><description>
&lt;h2>Four students to be mentored by Haiku in Google Summer of Code 2014!&lt;/h2>
&lt;img src="../../../files/accepted-students.png" border="8" align="right" />
&lt;p>
For this year's &lt;a href="http://google-melange.com/">Google Summer of Code&amp;trade;&lt;/a> program, we at Haiku have been allocated four students!
In 2014, 371 mentoring organizations applied and 4420 students submitted 6313 proposals.
&lt;strong>Haiku is proud to be one of the &lt;a href="http://www.google-melange.com/gsoc/org/list/public/google/gsoc2014">190 accepted mentoring organizations&lt;/a>,
with four accepted students.&lt;/strong>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
Over the years, Haiku's goals for &lt;em>Google Summer of Code&lt;/em> have evolved.
Originally the ability to evaluate the students' capabilities was lacking and the attention was simply on choosing projects that filled a need.
Now, the emphasis is placed on choosing the best students, as they are more important than their short term code contributions.
During the application process, those students instilled a sense of hope and confidence in Haiku's mentors that they will mature into full project contributors.
In other words,&lt;strong> this is our opportunity to grow and refine young, intelligent, and highly motivated
students into people who will continue to develop Haiku in the years to come.&lt;/strong>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
In recent years, students applying to Haiku were (at first encouraged and later) required to submit a code contribution.
By requiring potential students to submit a code contribution during the application period, Haiku's mentors achieve several things.
First and foremost, it shows that each student possesses basic skills that many of us take for granted -- using a bug tracker and compiling Haiku's sources.
More importantly, it provides our mentors with some insight into each individual student's motivation and abilities.
This year a total of &lt;a href="https://dev.haiku-os.org/query?keywords=~gsoc2014&amp;patch=1">9 patches&lt;/a>
were submitted during the application period (Two were sent to the [haiku] mailing list due to user registration issues and will be migrated to Trac [&lt;a href="http://www.freelists.org/post/haiku/PATCH-12-Optimize-the-serial-puts-function-to-use-directly-EFI-API">1&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="http://www.freelists.org/post/haiku/PATCH-22-Factorize-the-keyboard-driver-wait-for-key-in-console-wait-for-key">2&lt;/a>]).
&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Students</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/community/gsoc/2014/students/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2014 16:31:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/community/gsoc/2014/students/</guid><description> This year, 2 of 4 students completed their GSoC project
Louis Feuvrier - UEFI bootloader (failed - student disappeared right after being selected) Akshay Jaggi - libUSB port Arvind S Raj - ARM / BeagleBone XM port Zhuowei Zhang - Go language port (failed - port was working eventually but many communication problems with mentors)</description></item><item><title>Ideas</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/community/gsoc/2014/ideas/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2014 16:07:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/community/gsoc/2014/ideas/</guid><description>For information about Haiku's participation in GSoC this year, please see this page.
Qualifying students can apply for a Haiku project (see the list of suggested projects below) between March 10th and March 21st, 2014. For details about how to apply, please check out Students: How to Apply for a Haiku Idea.
According to other mentor organizations, the most successful Google Summer of Code projects are the ones proposed by the students themselves.</description></item></channel></rss>