<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Haiku Guides on Haiku Project</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/guides/</link><description>Recent content in Haiku Guides on Haiku Project</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>2001-2021 Haiku Inc.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2010 22:50:50 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.haiku-os.org/guides/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>UEFI Booting Haiku</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/guides/uefi_booting/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/guides/uefi_booting/</guid><description>UEFI Booting the anyboot image 64-bit release images (such as Haiku R1/beta3) can be directly booted from UEFI when the system&amp;rsquo;s hardware supports it. While Haiku&amp;rsquo;s UEFI bootloader is at an early stage, it can be leveraged to boot a stable system.
Installing UEFI to disk Haiku can be installed to a system with an UEFI bootloader, however it is a manual process as of R1/beta3. If you boot the anyboot media from UEFI (and install as usual) your system will boot via the legacy BIOS loader.</description></item><item><title>Network Booting Haiku</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/guides/network_booting/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 22:50:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/guides/network_booting/</guid><description>The root Haiku disk image (raw variant) can be booted remotely over the local network as of recent versions. This is especially useful when an architectures boot and kernel issues need to be troubleshot.
In the example below we will cover remote booting Haiku on various architectures. At the moment this is mostly geared toward developers.
Requirements:
Haiku source code and build environment Linux build tools Enough memory on the test system.</description></item><item><title>Installing a Haiku Image to a Disk Partition</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/guides/installing_haiku_image_disk_partition/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2012 19:28:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/guides/installing_haiku_image_disk_partition/</guid><description>This guide describes how to install Haiku from Linux on a spare hard disk partition directly without using a CD-ROM or USB memory key. It is assumed that you are already running Linux and have prepared an empty partition for Haiku.
Download Haiku You need to download an Anyboot image from the Haiku website.
Convert Anyboot to a raw image Anyboot images are a combination of ISO and raw images.</description></item><item><title>Booting Haiku</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/guides/booting/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2010 22:50:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/guides/booting/</guid><description>There are a wide range of options and configurations available to boot Haiku, from from modifying the boot sector, to configuring (and possibly installing) a boot manager. For an overview of the various booting options available to Haiku, please check out this page of the Haiku User Guide
Using Makebootable makebootable is a low-level Haiku tool to enable x86 MBR (legacy bios) systems to boot from the active Haiku partition.</description></item></channel></rss>