<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Developing on Haiku Project</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/community/getting-involved/developing/</link><description>Recent content in Developing on Haiku Project</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>2001-2021 Haiku Inc.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2015 17:29:55 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.haiku-os.org/community/getting-involved/developing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Infrastructure Development</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/community/getting-involved/developing/infrastructure/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2015 17:18:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/community/getting-involved/developing/infrastructure/</guid><description>Project Areas HaikuProject websites Web Applications HaikuProject websites Trac Plugin: "Test and Commit Patch" functionality Several developers have requested the ability to simply press a button that would trigger an automatic system to test and (conditionally commit) a supplied patch.
Trac Plugin: update tracbuildbot plugin The tracbuildbot plugin is a plugin that provides intergration between Trac and the BuildBot build system.
BuildBot Plugin: Update BuildBot Bootstrap BuildBot Bootstrap is a set of templates to be used with BuildBot 0.</description></item><item><title>Application Development</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/community/getting-involved/developing/applications/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2015 11:07:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/community/getting-involved/developing/applications/</guid><description>Project Areas 1st Party Development 3rd Party Development Porting Applications 1st Party Updating Mail Haiku provides an innovative Mail management system using the file system database-like features (queries) to efficiently manage the e-mails. While the technology for this is working well, the user interface is rather limited, making it difficult to use the feature up to its full potential.
The first part of this task is reworking the code base to adhere to our coding style guidelines and convert the user interface to the Layout Kit, making it work with all font sizes and languages.</description></item><item><title>System Development</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/community/getting-involved/developing/system/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2015 13:36:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/community/getting-involved/developing/system/</guid><description>Project Areas Drivers Kernel/File systems Media Network User interface Drivers USB Support for FreeBSD network compatibility layer Haiku uses a FreeBSD network compatibility layer to support many network devices (ethernet and wireless) using drivers written for the FreeBSD project. This allows reusing network drivers with very little changes, considerably decreasing the effort needed to get good hardware support in Haiku. However, this layer only supports PCI devices, and doesn't work with USB ones.</description></item></channel></rss>