<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Organization on Haiku Project</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/community/organization/</link><description>Recent content in Organization on Haiku Project</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>2001-2021 Haiku Inc.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 May 2015 17:41:14 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.haiku-os.org/community/organization/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Funding and donations</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/community/organization/funding/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2018 13:26:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/community/organization/funding/</guid><description>The Haiku project itself is not a formal entity, and as a result it cannot accept donations directly. There are however various way to donate, either to an organization or directly to some developers.
Haiku, Inc. Haiku, Inc. is an US-based non-profit organization which handles donations to the Haiku project. They fund the infrastructure (servers, hosting), communication (stickers, flyers) as well as travel and hosting costs for people representing Haiku at open source conferences (FOSDEM, RMLL, .</description></item><item><title>Governance</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/community/organization/governance/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2015 17:03:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/community/organization/governance/</guid><description>The following organisations are the driving force behind the open source development of Haiku: The Haiku development team A group of people known as the development team runs and manages the project. They have the permissions to edit and triage tickets on the bug tracker, push and merge code to the repositories, and also get voting rights in important project decisions.
The development team is not a legal entity, but a group of people managing the technical aspects of the project: coding guidelines, tools to use for collaboration, and general direction of the development of Haiku.</description></item><item><title>Community Initiatives &amp; Mentorship Opportunities</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/community/organization/initiatives/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2015 16:19:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/community/organization/initiatives/</guid><description>The Haiku Project is proud to work with other organisations on social initiatives to get more young and marginalized people involved in the open source community. They are a great opportunity for people to get started with working on top of the Haiku platform, as well as open source development in general.
Google Summer of Code | Google, Inc. The Google Summer of Code&amp;trade; is a program that offers student developers stipends to write code for various open source projects.</description></item><item><title>Policies</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/community/organization/policies/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2015 13:26:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/community/organization/policies/</guid><description>The standards that govern the Haiku community are similar to the Unwritten Constitutions that govern some countries, where their constitution simply acts as an aggregation of other laws, rather than a standalone constitution.
These rules are not final, and subject to change over time as problems, potential improvements or issues arise.
Our policies are listed below in a summarized manner:
Communication General rules Users are to refrain from delving into discussions about religion, politics, and other similar subjects.</description></item></channel></rss>