<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Code-In on Haiku Project</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/tags/code-in/</link><description>Recent content in Code-In on Haiku Project</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>2001-2021 Haiku Inc.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2020 08:14:36 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.haiku-os.org/tags/code-in/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Google Code-in 2019 finished</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2020-02-13_google_code-in_2019_finished/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2020 08:14:36 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2020-02-13_google_code-in_2019_finished/</guid><description>This 2019/2020 Google Code-in (GCI) was the 10th iteration in as many years and according to Google&amp;rsquo;s stats it was the most successful yet: In 7 weeks 3,566 students from 76 countries finished 20,840 tasks for 29 open source organizations!
Haiku was one of those organizations - the only open source project, by the way, that participated in all 10 editions of GCI - and we had our share of dedicated students that completed numerous tasks, big and small.</description></item><item><title>It's almost time for the 2019 Google Code-In and Haiku is ready!</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2019-11-7_its_almost_time_for_the_2019_google_code-in_and_haiku_is_ready/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2019 12:40:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2019-11-7_its_almost_time_for_the_2019_google_code-in_and_haiku_is_ready/</guid><description>Another year, another Google Code-In! The Haiku project is proud to announce that it will be participating in the 2019 Google Code-In!
Together with 28 other open source projects, we&amp;rsquo;ll mentor students between 13 and 17 years of age through a variety of large and small tasks. The aim is to introduce them to the work and community of open source projects, while benefitting ourselves from their work and energy, and maybe even by gaining future contributors.</description></item><item><title>GCI 2017 Wrap Up Report</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2018-02-02_gci_2017_wrap_up_report/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2018 00:13:41 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2018-02-02_gci_2017_wrap_up_report/</guid><description>Like all good things Google Code-In 2017 comes to an end, this year the program attracted over 3555 students in total for Google Code-In and out of those about ⅓ of the students claimed at least one task for Haiku, with 255 students completing at least one Haiku task. Haiku is also proud of its history of getting selected each year in Google’s Code-In. Just like the other 24 organizations, Haiku picked winners out of the 10 students who completed the most tasks for Haiku, finalists and grand prize winners were picked collectively by the diligent team of Haiku’s 20+ mentors.</description></item><item><title>GCI 2016 Wrap Up Report</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2017-02-05_gci_2016_wrap_up_report/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 12:44:02 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2017-02-05_gci_2016_wrap_up_report/</guid><description>What happens when you combine 337 students, 20+ mentors, and an endless volley of tasks? During the time from November 2016 to January 2017, 368 Haiku tasks were successfully completed. The seventh year of Google’s Code-In, and the seventh for Haiku as a mentoring organization was a grand success.
Students from all around the world aged 13-17 worked with the project mentors on improving Haiku during the 7 weeks of the contest.</description></item><item><title>GCI 2015 meeting; D+3</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/blog/mmu_man/2016-06-21_gci_2015_meeting_d3/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2016 03:02:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/blog/mmu_man/2016-06-21_gci_2015_meeting_d3/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img width="25%" height="25%" align="right" src="../../files/IMG_20160615_135756.jpg" title="Stephanie cutting the map cake" alt="Stephanie cutting the map cake" />The last day was spent at the San Francisco office, which although smaller (they have &amp;ldquo;only&amp;rdquo; a few floors in a building), is quite nice, with a rooftop and other funny things.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We had a nice breakfast at the cafeteria (I sampled their croissants… not too bad for US ones).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>GCI 2015 meeting; D+2</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/blog/mmu_man/2016-06-21_gci_2015_meeting_d2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2016 03:00:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/blog/mmu_man/2016-06-21_gci_2015_meeting_d2/</guid><description>&lt;p>Tuesday is going to be adventure-packed. Let&amp;rsquo;s hope everyone slept well. I made a quick survey but I&amp;rsquo;m not sure everyone answered honestly. Although someone admitted lying on the bed and waking up with the clothes still on. No, I won&amp;rsquo;t give names :D&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We had to choose between a Segway tour or a visit to the &lt;a href="http://www.exploratorium.edu/">Exploratorium&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>GCI 2015 meeting; D+1</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/blog/mmu_man/2016-06-14_gci_2015_meeting_d1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2016 06:56:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/blog/mmu_man/2016-06-14_gci_2015_meeting_d1/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="../../files/IMG_20160613_084622.jpg" width="25%" height="25%" align="right" alt="Morning light in the bus" title="Morning light in the bus" />[Looks like I&amp;rsquo;m still jet-lagged a week later&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;ll try to publish my notes anyway, and put photos later on]&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Today is the big day: we&amp;rsquo;re going to the Googleplex in Mountain View!
It took a while to get there due to traffic jam, and we were on the lucky bus, the other ones took even more time. Before getting out we had a tour of the vast campus with the bus, showing the various buildings and places, and the famous gbikes everywhere.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>GCI 2015 meeting; D day</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/blog/mmu_man/2016-06-13_gci_2015_meeting_d_day/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2016 03:37:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/blog/mmu_man/2016-06-13_gci_2015_meeting_d_day/</guid><description>&lt;p>So this is the day.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I slept not too bad. The only trouble with rooms this big is you have to walk a lot :D&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After two days hacking I wanted to do some sightseeing. I started by the cable-car, it&amp;rsquo;s really funny the way it goes up and down. Then I went north on Van Ness, west on Lombard street, and I walked a little in the Presidio Park. Was nice to see some nature! And I finally saw the Golden-Gate Bridge in the distance. Then I walked back to town via the Palace of Fine Arts, Marina Boulevard (btw, &lt;a href="https://en.wiktionary.org/wiki/boulevard">boulevard&lt;/a> is a French word, although there are several explanations for its origin), Fort Mason, and they I took the bus back to the hotel to get a shower and a little nap before the GCI Opening Party.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>GCI 2015 meeting; D -1</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/blog/mmu_man/2016-06-12_gci_2015_meeting_d_1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2016 07:47:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/blog/mmu_man/2016-06-12_gci_2015_meeting_d_1/</guid><description>Saturday, also slept very well, I&amp;rsquo;m thinking about taking the mattress with me but it won&amp;rsquo;t fit into the plane. and yet I woke up early to participate in a French radio show remotely, that is broadcasted live from the Very Important Party (a little DemoParty I usually attend), for them it&amp;rsquo;s 5pm, but for me it&amp;rsquo;s 8am…
At 10 I&amp;rsquo;m packing up as I&amp;rsquo;ll have to change the hotel, I just hope I&amp;rsquo;ll sleep as well in the next one.</description></item><item><title>GCI 2015 meeting; D -2</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/blog/mmu_man/2016-06-12_gci_2015_meeting_d_2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2016 00:18:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/blog/mmu_man/2016-06-12_gci_2015_meeting_d_2/</guid><description>Friday, I sleep surprisingly well for a first night abroad. I chose to wear a red FSFE t-shirt &amp;ldquo;There is NO CLOUD, just some other people&amp;rsquo;s computers&amp;rdquo;.
At 10am I&amp;rsquo;m going out to get a donut and coffee, and try to get inside NoiseBridge. Ringing the bell didn&amp;rsquo;t really work the first time, so I had to work a bit and retry once or twice. But then I was greeted by a French guy, who gave me a tour of the space : library, soldering stations, lots of parts, two classroom, a sewing space, and soon a large cutting machine… they have the whole 3rd floor of the building!</description></item><item><title>GCI 2015 meeting; D -3</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/blog/mmu_man/2016-06-12_gci_2015_meeting_d_3/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2016 23:51:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/blog/mmu_man/2016-06-12_gci_2015_meeting_d_3/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img align="right" width="25%" height="25%" src="../../files/DSCN4554.JPG" />So, it&amp;rsquo;s Thursday and I&amp;rsquo;m getting a plane to San Francisco for the GCI meeting. Well, hopefully, as the French railway is on strike… Ok, my train was canceled, but another was 1.5 hours late so I managed to jump on it and arrive… at the Paris Lyon station, which meant taking the RER (oh no, it&amp;rsquo;s on strike as well), ok, the Metro to another station and then the RER to the airport.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Haiku's GCI 2015 winners</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2016-02-13_haikus_gci_2015_winners/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2016 08:13:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2016-02-13_haikus_gci_2015_winners/</guid><description>&lt;p>In February the roughly two months long Google Code-In (GCI) period came to an end. See the results of all participating organizations at the &lt;a href="https://codein.withgoogle.com/winners/">GCI site&lt;/a>. As always, it&amp;rsquo;s been a strenuous time for students and mentors alike. Of course, it was a very productive one, too.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Google Code-In 2014 Wrap Up Report</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2015-02-13_google_codein_2014_wrap_report/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2015 08:53:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2015-02-13_google_codein_2014_wrap_report/</guid><description>&lt;p>Google has now announced the 24 winners for Google Code-In 2014, with Josef Gajdusek and Puck Meerburg being the two winners from Haiku. This is Puck&amp;rsquo;s second time winning for Haiku. This year we got to pick our top 5 out of the top 10 students who completed that most tasks for Haiku. Augustin Cavalier was selected as our backup winner, and Markus Himmel and Chirayu Desai were selected as finalist. Chirayu was a GCI 2013 winner with RTEMS, and made the jump to Haiku when RTEMS took this year off from GCI.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This was the fifth year of Google&amp;rsquo;s Code-In, and the fifth for Haiku. This year we had 6 students who completed 20 or more tasks, one more than in 2013. We had 36 students who completed three or more tasks and qualified for a Google Code-In T-Shirt, and 53 students who completed two or more tasks. This was the first year of having beginner tasks, aimed at lowering the bar to get more new students introduced into open source. Haiku had 149 total students complete at least one task, many of those were for the beginner tasks. We had 164 beginner tasks completed, which was mostly just to introduce students to booting and using Haiku. Other beginner tasks were to compile Haiku or to install and use Haikuporter to build a package from a recipe file. In total students completed a staggering 435 tasks this time for Haiku.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Google Code-In 2012 Haiku Wrap Up Report</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/node/5087/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2013 06:03:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/node/5087/</guid><description>&lt;p>Haiku participated in Google&amp;rsquo;s Code-In for the third year in a row. This year&amp;rsquo;s event was a bit different than in 2010 and 2011. Google changed the rules a bit to make the contest better than in previous years. One of the changes was to remove the translation tasks as it seems for many of these tasks students were using Google Translator and other such tools. This meant that the biggest category for Haiku in GCI2010 and 2011 was gone, so we would have to adjust things a bit. For 2012 we had students complete 168 tasks, with ten students completing six or more tasks each. We focused more on coding and coding related tasks than in the past.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Haiku Amongst 10 Open-source Organizations To Participate in Google Code-In 2012</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2012-11-25_haiku_amongst_10_opensource_organizations_participate_google_codein_2012/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Nov 2012 21:16:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2012-11-25_haiku_amongst_10_opensource_organizations_participate_google_codein_2012/</guid><description>What is Google Code-in ? GCI is a contest for pre-university students (from 13 to 17 years old) with the goal to encourage young students to participate into open-source development. To achieve that goal, open-source organizations sets up various tasks and students are invited to claim them. Various prizes are awarded and, this year, each organizations are going to award two (2) grand prize winners amongst participating students.
When does the contest start ?</description></item><item><title>2011 Google Code-In Contest, Haiku Selected as One of Eighteen Participating Organzations</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2011-11-10_2011_google_codein_contest_haiku_selected_one_eighteen_participating_organzations/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2011 04:18:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2011-11-10_2011_google_codein_contest_haiku_selected_one_eighteen_participating_organzations/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Haiku has been selected as one of eighteen organizations to participate in the Google Code-In 2011!&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Once again Haiku has been selected to participate in Google Code-In. To read the announcement and to see what other organizations were selected see [1] below. Here&amp;rsquo;s some basic information on the contest:&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="alert alert-info">
&lt;span class="inline inline-right">
&lt;img src="http://code.google.com/opensource/gci/2011-12/gci_logo.jpg" alt="Google Code-In 2011 logo" />&lt;/span>
Google's contest to introduce pre-university students to the many kinds of contributions that make open source software development possible, is starting on November 21, 2011. We are inviting students worldwide to produce a variety of open source code, documentation, training materials and user experience research for the organizations participating this year. These tasks include:
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Code: Tasks related to writing or refactoring code&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Documentation: Tasks related to creating/editing documents&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Outreach: Tasks related to community management and outreach/marketing&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Quality Assurance: Tasks related to testing and ensuring code is of high quality&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Research: Tasks related to studying a problem and recommending solutions&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Training: Tasks related to helping others learn more&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Translation: Tasks related to localization&lt;/li>
&lt;li>User Interface: Tasks related to user experience research or user interface design and interaction&lt;/div>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Official Google Code-In website and to review the updated rules for 2011. [2]&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Over the next couple of weeks we will be busy getting our task list in order and putting together a good group of Haiku mentors for this. Many of the tasks will be for translations, so we may still need a few more mentors to cover some of those tasks. If you are interested in mentoring please let us know on the mailing list. For a preview of some of the possible Haiku tasks, you can check the wiki page we used for gathering ideas. [3]&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Google Code In Wrap Up Report</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/blog/scottmc/2011-01-12_google_code_wrap_report/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2011 00:30:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/blog/scottmc/2011-01-12_google_code_wrap_report/</guid><description>
&lt;p>
The Google Code In is now over. I’d like to thank all of the students, and the Haiku mentors, 30 in all, for all their hard work. I’d also like to thank Google, the Melange team and Carol Smith for running GCI. Haiku had over 150 tasks completed by students!
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
Many of the tasks completed for Haiku were for translations. In all, there were about 65 translation tasks completed, nearly completing 12 different languages, and partial coverage on 7 more. One student, when we couldn’t find a mentor to cover the Romanian translations, went out and found a mentor, and then she proceeded to translate all of the apps and preflets that are in HTA, all while she was also doing tasks for several other orgs. In case anyone is interested in working on the translations there is still a lot of work left to do on some of the less common languages. If you are interested in helping out, join the Haiku-i18n mailing list. To work on the localization of the system, go to &lt;a href="http://hta.polytect.org/">HTA&lt;/a>, register and get started. To start a new translation team for the user guide, read &lt;a href="https://dev.haiku-os.org/wiki/i18n/UserGuide">Starting a new translation&lt;/a>.
&lt;/p>&lt;p>
&lt;div class="alert alert-info">
&lt;a href="../../files/images/gci-screenshot.png">&lt;img src="../../files/images/gci-screenshot.png" width="480">&lt;/a>
&lt;p>
Haiku get's a couple of new screensavers, several new translators for many languages, and some more i18n'd applications and preferences thanks to GCI students.
&lt;/p>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>2010 Google Code-In Contest, Haiku Selected as a Participating Organization</title><link>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2010-11-18_2010_google_codein_contest_haiku_selected_participating_organization/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Nov 2010 20:17:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.haiku-os.org/news/2010-11-18_2010_google_codein_contest_haiku_selected_participating_organization/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Haiku has been selected as one of twenty organizations to participate in the 2010 Google Code-In!&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>From the Google announcement[1]:&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="alert alert-info">
&lt;span class="inline inline-right">
&lt;img src="http://code.google.com/opensource/gci/2010-11/images/gcilogo.jpg" alt="Google Code-In logo" />&lt;/span>
Google's contest to introduce pre-university students to the many kinds of contributions that make open source software development possible, is starting on November 22, 2010. We are inviting students worldwide to produce a variety of open source code, documentation, training materials and user experience research for the organizations participating this year. These tasks include:
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Code: Tasks related to writing or refactoring code&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Documentation: Tasks related to creating/editing documents&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Outreach: Tasks related to community management and outreach/marketing&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Quality Assurance: Tasks related to testing and ensuring code is of high quality&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Research: Tasks related to studying a problem and recommending solutions&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Training: Tasks related to helping others learn more&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Translation: Tasks related to localization&lt;/li>
&lt;li>User Interface: Tasks related to user experience research or user interface design and interaction&lt;/div>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Since we were picked on November 5th, we have been busy getting our task list in order and putting together a good group of Haiku mentors for this. Many of the tasks are for translations, so we may still need a few more mentors to cover some of those tasks. If you are interested in mentoring please let us know on the mailing list. For a preview of some of the possible Haiku tasks, you can check the wiki page we used for gathering ideas[2].&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>